<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environment on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/environment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environment on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 10:33:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambodia</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/03/cambodia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 10:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/03/cambodia/</guid>
      <description>Sunday, March 12, we arrived in Sihanoukville (Cambodia). We were greeted by our driver, “Mr. Temple” and our guide, “Mr. Lucky”.
Mr. Lucky was a sweet guy who told us a great deal about Cambodia’s history, present, and his life. The kind of guide you always hope to get, but seldom do.
Mr. Lucky was the youngest of 4 brothers. His other 3 brothers died during the Khmer Rouge regime. Fortunately he survived (hence his nickname).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horse riding surrounded by parks</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/horse-riding-surrounded-by-parks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 15:23:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/horse-riding-surrounded-by-parks/</guid>
      <description>As we imagined, the highlight of moving to Wimbledon is being surrounded by nature.
On one side, 0.3 miles to the East, we have the family-friendly and very civilized Wimbledon Park, with its swans and ducks, water sports, minigolf, tennis courts… even beach volleyball!
On the other side, 0.3 miles to the West, we have the wild and lush dense forest of Wimbledon Common:
Adjacent to Wimbledon Common we have Richmond Park, with its live and free roaming deer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hampstead Heath</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/hampstead-heath/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 17:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/hampstead-heath/</guid>
      <description>Today, on our way to the AFF show we strolled around Hampstead Heath, one of the many lovely areas with a park, pond (with baby swans!), and flowers around London. It was truly beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family road trip to Ithaca, Niagara and Thanksgiving in Buffalo</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/family-road-trip-to-ithaca-niagara-and-thanksgiving-in-buffalo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 13:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/family-road-trip-to-ithaca-niagara-and-thanksgiving-in-buffalo/</guid>
      <description>Since my parents were visiting from Spain, we decided to drive with them to Buffalo to spend Thanksgiving all together with my in-law family.
Wednesday, November 26 we drove over 400 miles (650 Km) through the snow stormfrom New York City to Niagara Falls. Well, my wife drove. I don’t think anyone else in the car could have managed all that snow and ice on the road, but fortunately she has a lot of experience with it, so while it took us four more hours than expected (and forced us to stop at a diner in the middle of the road for lunch, instead of making it to Ithaca as it was our plan), we made it across the Canadian border at Niagara Falls safe and sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to the beach... Canadian style</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/02/going-to-the-beach...-canadian-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 17:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/02/going-to-the-beach...-canadian-style/</guid>
      <description>This has been a hard winter in North America. Snow, ice, flurries, sleet&amp;hellip; But today I got to enjoy the beach (Waverly beach – Lake Erie, Canada) in a way I had never experienced before: walking over water&amp;hellip;. frozen water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It was so cold, it was funny</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/it-was-so-cold-it-was-funny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 19:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/it-was-so-cold-it-was-funny/</guid>
      <description>The other day my wife and I had to put on several layers of warm clothes to leave our apartment.
Then, when we got back home, we saw this online and we could not stop laughing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This IS cold -23ºF in New York right now with ice inside the window</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/this-is-cold-23%C2%BAf-in-new-york-right-now-with-ice-inside-the-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 16:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/this-is-cold-23%C2%BAf-in-new-york-right-now-with-ice-inside-the-window/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Severe weather warning</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/severe-weather-warning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 14:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/severe-weather-warning/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alaska Cruise Day 8: Seward to Anchorage</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/alaska-cruise-day-8-seward-to-anchorage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 18:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/alaska-cruise-day-8-seward-to-anchorage/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5891423416835987953]
All things must come to an end, and this amazing trip did too. We disembarked in Seward early, following an easy and relaxed procedure, finding our luggage right away, and boarding the transfer service that would drive us to Anchorage for the next three hours. But on the way we made a few “last stops” where we saw black and brown bears, moose, lynxes, oxen, elks, rain deers, bisons, eagles, owls…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alaska Cruise Day 7: Hubbard Glacier</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/alaska-cruise-day-7-hubbard-glacier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 18:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/alaska-cruise-day-7-hubbard-glacier/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5890927123261020129]
Before breakfast, we woke up to the sound of the ship’s hull breaking ice plaques in the water. The captain warned us that we were sailing next to Hubbard Glacier, so we got dressed in a hurry and ran to the observation deck (level 12). The glaciers were spectacular. Amazing. Breathtaking. And any other similar adjectives you can think of.
Their intense blue is due to the way they are formed: layers upon layers of heavy snow compresses the bottom, squeezing any tiny bubble of air out, until only pure ice crystals remain, glacier crystals, which are intense and beautiful blue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alaska Cruise Day 6: Sitka</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/alaska-cruise-day-6-sitka/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 18:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/alaska-cruise-day-6-sitka/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5890669129913176289]
As if we had not experienced enough adventure and beauty, Sitka was awaiting us with even more. Early in the morning, after an in-room breakfast, we boarded the St. Michael catamaran to go on a wild life quest between the narrow island passages and open bays of the Sitka Sound, with the dormant volcano Mount Edgecumbe providing an unsurpassable background to one of the world`s most beautiful coastal environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alaska Cruise Day 5: Skagway</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/alaska-cruise-day-5-skagway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 17:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/alaska-cruise-day-5-skagway/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5890279804678844545]
Caviar on warm blinis and Montaudon champagne for breakfast, while docking in Skagway. That is the right way to start an amazing day. As soon as we finished our breakfast, we disembarked right in front of the “graffiti” that cruise lines have been painting on the mountain (with their logos, captain and vessel names) since 1928, and went to the heliport to board a Eurocopter that took us, through narrow canyons and spectacular valleys, flying over very high peaks and several glaciers, to the dog camp on the Denver Glacier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alaska Cruise Day 4: Juneau</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/alaska-cruise-day-4-juneau/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 17:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/alaska-cruise-day-4-juneau/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5890277524527986321]
June 15 we woke up in Juneau, Alaska’s capital (the largest and best known city is Anchorage, but Juneau is the official capital).
After breakfast, we attended a very rare screening of a 7 minute animation film called “Destino”, a little known collaboration between Salvador Dali and Walt Disney started in 1949, but unfinished until 2007 when Roy Disney decided to hire a team of French animators to complete it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vancouver Day 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/vancouver-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 01:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/vancouver-day-3/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5888480420051909169]
On Tuesday, June 11, and not believing that it had not rained on our trip yet, we asked the hotel for a couple of complimentary bicycles and were told that only one was available but the other one should be available soon. So in the meantime we took the aquabus from the foot of Davie Street in Yaletown to the Public Market on Granville Island, False Creek, where a former industrial site was long ago converted into an indoor public market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NY Shorewalkers The Great Saunter 2013</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/ny-shorewalkers-the-great-saunter-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 14:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/ny-shorewalkers-the-great-saunter-2013/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5874557463298386241]
Yesterday we joined a few friends in part of the NY Shorewalkers The Great Saunter 2013walk. While the Shorewalkers started early in the morning and walked all along the West side of Manhattan, we started much later, and to the subway to Carl Schurz Park, where we had fun watching the dogs at the dog park, visiting Major Bloomberg`s official residence (although he does not really live there, he only uses it as a nice reception place), enjoying the trees blooming and flowers, and strolling up the East side to meet them half way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freak snow storm</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/freak-snow-storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 22:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/freak-snow-storm/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5853068702144573873]
On Thursday I woke up to a message from a friend, professor at MIT, who was flying to SXSW and was stuck onboard the plane with the Boston airport closed. We had a freak snow storm: it started snowing in the morning. The snow accumulated throughout the day. By night it stopped and temperatures went up. In two days we have gone from 20ºF to 54ºF. New York weather: unpredictable and not for the faint of heart 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After hurricane Sandy in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 20:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>From tilted posts to trees completely gone, after hurricane Sandy there were many signs of destruction around New York.
I had to stay at Stepahnie`s apartment (thank you again!) until Monday, because my building remained without power. And even after the power returned, the telephone and internet took two more days.
Some people were not so lucky, with all hotels fully booked, and had to stay at home for days without power or water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Sandy in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 20:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>To go from Baltimore to NY has been a real nightmare. I had a return train ticket for the 29th at night, but that was obviously cancelled. Amtrak then rebooked me on the first train out of Baltimore (at 03:45am on November 1st), and since flights or buses were not operating, I took it.
The nice lady at the travel agency got me a reservation on a flight to La Guardia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Sandy in Baltimore</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/hurricane-sandy-in-baltimore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 23:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/hurricane-sandy-in-baltimore/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Norse vs Inuit approach</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-norse-vs-inuit-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-norse-vs-inuit-approach/</guid>
      <description>The Norse vs Inuit approach
There are many seemingly &amp;ldquo;small events&amp;rdquo; in history to which we do not pay much attention, when actually they provide very important lessons. I always talk about historical examples of perfectly successful cooperatives and anarchist self government. But this time I want to comment on a very different historical event: the Norse attempt to colonize Greenland.
When the Norse tried to colonize Greenland, the Inuit already lived there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incredible photo of last night`s &amp;quot;derecho&amp;quot; storm in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/incredible-photo-of-last-nights-quotderechoquot-storm-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 10:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/incredible-photo-of-last-nights-quotderechoquot-storm-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>Last night`s storm was, again, AMAZING. I was not exactly in a position to take a picture, &amp;ldquo;too concentrated on something else&amp;rdquo; (although I would have loved it), but this is a great shot by Ryan Brenizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazing storm in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/amazing-storm-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 18:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/amazing-storm-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>I have been under tropical storms several times in the jungle. But I have never seen anything like today`s storm over Manhattan. Absolutely incredible.The Guardian. Photo: Inga Sarda-Sorensen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is poisoning the world?</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/who-is-poisoning-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 18:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/who-is-poisoning-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Play with data, discover, learn the hard truth&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The parks of the future</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-parks-of-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 22:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-parks-of-the-future/</guid>
      <description>Is this what the parks of the future will look like?“Bird,” by Jacco Olivier, one of six animation installations on display in Madison Square Park, New YorkIt will be, if we do not do something about it now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It`s finally snowing... upwards!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/its-finally-snowing...-upwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 19:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/its-finally-snowing...-upwards/</guid>
      <description>When the wind and cold/warm air currents collide while snowing, you get the funny &amp;ldquo;snowing upwards&amp;rdquo; effect (and sideways also, of course). The 5ºF &amp;ldquo;real feel&amp;rdquo; is not so funny though 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEDxManhattan: Changing the way we eat</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/tedxmanhattan-changing-the-way-we-eat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 16:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/tedxmanhattan-changing-the-way-we-eat/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow, January 21st, 2012, NY</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bella Gaia concert</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/bella-gaia-concert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 22:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/bella-gaia-concert/</guid>
      <description>Mickey Hart, Dar Williams, Bella Gaia(AWESOME), &amp;amp; The Abrams Brothers(country/folk/rock energetic brothers&amp;hellip; that violin was smoking! loved it) concert at Highline Ballroom.
Cool mix of music, dance and infographic visuals with eco message. Highly recommended (even the veggie burger was good!).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignorants eat shit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/ignorants-eat-shit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 12:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/ignorants-eat-shit/</guid>
      <description>According to this articlethe food people usually eat (thanks to my wife and my conscience, I have slightly healthier eating habits than most people) is pure shit: wood celulose in many foods, fruit juices over a year old, ammonia in meat, artificial blueberries, &amp;ldquo;free-range chicken&amp;rdquo; that is not free at all, and other lies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>