<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 17:16:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>This Revolution needs a Revolution</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 17:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went with my wife and son to visit the Victoria &amp;amp; Albert`s Museum exhibition You Say You Want a Revolution? Records and Rebels 1966-1970. The aim of the exhibition was quite clear:
 How have the finished and unfinished revolutions of the late 1960s changed the way we live today and think about the future?
 I was very much looking forward to visiting the exhibition. It is SO timely, and SO needed, I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My artwork “God bless Amurika”, on display at the Ludwig Museum (Cologne), explained</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-artwork-god-bless-amurika-on-display-at-the-ludwig-museum-cologne-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 09:26:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-artwork-god-bless-amurika-on-display-at-the-ludwig-museum-cologne-explained/</guid>
      <description>I have often criticized artists who hide behind “my work speaks for itself” or “it’s up to the viewer to interpret my work”. Nice try, but that’s bullshit.
Of course, anyone can interpret anything when exposed to an artwork! But the artist should at least make an attempt to explain the meaning behind a piece. No matter how self-explanatory (or obscure) it might be. It’s not “restricting the viewer”, it’s guiding; suggesting is not imposing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview for the art exhibition that I have curated and is currently being shown in Kaunas, Lithuania</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/interview-for-the-art-exhibition-that-i-have-curated-and-is-currently-being-shown-in-kaunas-lithuania/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/interview-for-the-art-exhibition-that-i-have-curated-and-is-currently-being-shown-in-kaunas-lithuania/</guid>
      <description>INTERVIEW with JORGE CORTELL, curator
By Airida Rekštytė – November 4, 2016
According to your profound theoretical education (sic) it will not be difficult to present us in short your intentions for organizing this event.
When did the idea of making this exhibition occur and what inspired it?
I have spent years as activist defending free software and online privacy, and opposing censorship.
During a dinner with the director of an event that focuses on those themes (the Internet Freedom Festival, also known as Circumvention Festival), I told him how it would be a nice challenge to try to convey the main messages of the Festivals themes into an art exhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s pretend none of this ever happened</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 10:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</guid>
      <description>Walking towards my London Shoreditch office
to meet the Swiss investor and his impeccable suit,
leaving the City bankers’s coffee-holding fast pace behind,
I notice the absence nobody seems to
Where did he go?
His sleeping sack and pillow still on the sidewalk
as annoyingly positioned in the corner as always
But he’s gone
.
I wonder and I worry
his failing body, almost as absent as his lost gaze</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Big Bang Data” and “Tintin” exhibitions at Somerset House, London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/01/big-bang-data-and-tintin-exhibitions-at-somerset-house-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 18:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/01/big-bang-data-and-tintin-exhibitions-at-somerset-house-london/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we went to see a couple exhibitions at Somerset House, in London.
The first exhibition we saw was “TINTIN: Hergé`s Masterpiece”. Basic but obviously appealing, it was too crowded to be enjoyable.
The second one was “Big Bang Data”.
While undoubtedly interesting, especially for someone who works in, teaches, and loves bid data and technology like myself, to me the most interesting aspect of this exhibition is that everyone who was there had already experienced the subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tate Modern curating methodology</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/tate-modern-curating-methodology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 13:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/tate-modern-curating-methodology/</guid>
      <description>December 2 I went to the Tate Modernwith the whole family, since my mother-in-law was visiting from overseas.
I really like how it is set up according to concepts, rather than chronologically, by artists, or by styles. It feels more like an art gallery (which it is) than a museum. It puts things into the subjective focus of the curator. I wonder how much the artists themselves would agree with the collection parameters, but it definitely is a welcome departure from the more traditional museum logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I stood up against a terrorist in a German train</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/i-stood-up-against-a-terrorist-in-a-german-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 12:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/i-stood-up-against-a-terrorist-in-a-german-train/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, after spending the day at a tradeshow in Düsseldorf, on my way by train to the hotel in Mülheim, I stopped in the town of Duisburg, which was on my way, because I heard they were setting up a Christmas market. The market was indeed being set up, but it was still closed, so I decided to go back to the station. To avoid the sprinkling rain I took the 901 tram at König-Heinrich Platz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sankeien Garden Yokohama</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/sankeien-garden-yokohama/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 15:21:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/sankeien-garden-yokohama/</guid>
      <description>Friday I only had one meeting scheduled late, so I decided to brave the very foggy and rainy day and venture forth to the Sankeien Garden. It was out of the way, but I read great things about it, so not caring about pictures not turning out OK or getting lost, or getting wet, I went anyway.
I can only assume that the place was mostly empty because of the suboptimal weather, but I was very very happy to walk around there almost by myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Oxford Alumni Weekend lectures</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/four-oxford-alumni-weekend-lectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 10:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/four-oxford-alumni-weekend-lectures/</guid>
      <description>[More pictures here]
Last Saturday I had the pleasure to attend Oxford’s Alumni Weekend with my son.
I knew he would not be the only teenager there, but I was surprised to see kids even younger than him accompanying their parents. The truth is that I wish I had brought him earlier. I’ll try to bring my daughter to the next one.
Besides the obvious networking opportunity, the true pleasure was to attend interesting lectures delivered by top academics, and to see my son actually interested in those lectures!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking at the CUNY President`s office</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/networking-at-the-cuny-presidents-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 19:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/networking-at-the-cuny-presidents-office/</guid>
      <description>On May 6th, having just returned from quick trips to Cleveland and Atlanta, I attended with my wife the round table debate &amp;ldquo;Curiosity, Understanding, and Utility: Science and the Creative Economy&amp;rdquo; held at the City University of New York Graduate Center`s Proshansky Auditorium.
William Bialek, director of the Graduate Center`s Initiative for the Theoretical Sciences, moderated a discussion with Jennifer Tour Chayes, distinguished scientist and managing director of Microsoft Research New England and Microsoft Research New York City; Fernando Pereira, research at Google; and Chris Wiggins, chief data scientist at the New York Times and faculty member in the Department of Applied Mathematics and Applied Physics at Columbia University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am requested to take a link down and... Streisand effect!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 01:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</guid>
      <description>Today I received this email (it was in Spanish, I have translated it into English because that is the main language of this blog, and in order to give this issue the international coverage that it deserves – sorry for any translation mistake since I am not a lawyer and he writes like an old-fashioned one trying to sound intimidating; here is the original):
 Mr. Cortell:
Currently I am suing Greg Prévôt in the Courts of Barcelona, author of a defamatory site which infringes upon my honor, whose link appears in which you administer, at the following address:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look at the data, just look at it!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/look-at-the-data-just-look-at-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 14:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/look-at-the-data-just-look-at-it/</guid>
      <description>Carna botnet offers us this amazing 24 hour visualization of relative IPv4 utilization observed using ICMP Ping requests.
Look at the data, just look at it! Dont you see peoples sleeping patterns, internet usage patterns, eating schedule habit, cultural differences, urban influence, regional inequalities&amp;hellip;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology in Phoenix, autopsy in Albuquerque</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/technology-in-phoenix-autopsy-in-albuquerque/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 16:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/technology-in-phoenix-autopsy-in-albuquerque/</guid>
      <description>4 flights and 40 hours later (after having missed Japan Week), I am back in New York in the modern and technological Delta terminal (C, not D) at Laguardia Airport, with its tablets and card readers on all tables and bars at all bars and restaurants.What a difference from the Delta Terminal 4 at JFK! Luckily the new one will be finished in May, because the old one is falling apart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Montevideo in December</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/montevideo-in-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 20:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/montevideo-in-december/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5821499441712215169]
December 2nd I flew to Montevideo. I stayed at the Radisson Hotel, Plaza de la Independencia. Very conveniently located with some impressive views from the top floor. Good thing it had a pool, because it is not easy to keep my exercise regime when traveling so much.
Besides very productive meetings with IBM (very nice, professional, and friendly executives, by the way) and presentation to several hospital groups (one of the meetings at the Presidential Building, another one at the country`s largest hospital, and a presentation at the Solis Theater), I enjoyed the promenade by the river which seems like a sea, the old town, and a weird Ice Bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slavoj Žižek lecture &amp;quot;Conditions of Possibility&amp;quot; with M. Hägglund and A. Johnston</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/slavoj-%C5%BEi%C5%BEek-lecture-quotconditions-of-possibilityquot-with-m.-h%C3%A4gglund-and-a.-johnston/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 13:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/slavoj-%C5%BEi%C5%BEek-lecture-quotconditions-of-possibilityquot-with-m.-h%C3%A4gglund-and-a.-johnston/</guid>
      <description>Note: Start video on 33:33 (absolutely nothing happening before that, but just people waiting for the panelist to go on stage).On Friday I was invited to attend Slavoj Žižeks lecture &amp;quot;Conditions of Possibility&amp;quot; with M. Hägglund &amp;amp; A. Johnston at City University of New Yorks Graduate Center.
Martin Hägglund (associate professor of comparative literature and humanities at Yale University) and Adrian Johnston (professor in the department of philosophy at the University of New Mexico at Albuquerque and a faculty member at the Emory Psychoanalytic Institute in Atlanta) both read legthy and endogamic discourses about Heidegger, classic philosophical concepts, and stubbornly narrow minded &amp;ldquo;canons&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>319 Scholes art opening of &amp;quot;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 12:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I went to 319 Scholes to attend the art opening of &amp;ldquo;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;rdquo;.
Beyond the anecdotal post/pre hispter crowd, the exhibition itself is a sad celebration of noise. Which, in itself is as valid, or invalid, as any other starting point in the endless debate about art (more so in regards with contemporary, electronic, net, etc).
But it is its legitimization attempt, with research project, curator, catalogue, and international tour, which brings the debate to a whole different level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections from NY Comic Con</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 09:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I went to NY Comic Con, like everyone else, I guess, with the idea of having fun, of experiencing first hand one of the &amp;ldquo;major events&amp;rdquo; that a true nerdy geek can attend. I also wanted to meet Cory Doctorow (although we actually ended up not meeting). It has been years since I last met him, and it was the perfect &amp;ldquo;excuse&amp;rdquo; to attend the conference.
When I arrived, I was really surprised to see the size of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Norse vs Inuit approach</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-norse-vs-inuit-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-norse-vs-inuit-approach/</guid>
      <description>The Norse vs Inuit approach
There are many seemingly &amp;ldquo;small events&amp;rdquo; in history to which we do not pay much attention, when actually they provide very important lessons. I always talk about historical examples of perfectly successful cooperatives and anarchist self government. But this time I want to comment on a very different historical event: the Norse attempt to colonize Greenland.
When the Norse tried to colonize Greenland, the Inuit already lived there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High culture might will numb you, how stay true? On &amp;quot;Graffiti&amp;quot; screening and panel at New Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 15:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I was invited to the New Musuem for the screening of &amp;ldquo;Graffiti – PostGraffiti&amp;rdquo; documentary and panel discussion.Your usual suspects were there. Besides the panelist (Pattie Astor, Fab Five Freddy, Lady Pink, and Lee Quinones), there were many old glories and a couple of aspiring bomber kids in the audience that I am sure were tagging walls late that night.
What started as a celebration, a remembrance, and a comunion, as the liturgy advanced ended up becoming a hurtful vindication and even a flat out purist attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round table at NYCBA about Campaign Reform</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/round-table-at-nycba-about-campaign-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 13:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/round-table-at-nycba-about-campaign-reform/</guid>
      <description>September 5th (I know, I have really fallen behind my posts; bear with me, there is just too much going on to keep up) I attended a very interesting and enlightening round table at the New York City Bar Associationtitled &amp;ldquo;How Will Recent Developments in the Law Influence the 2012 Elections&amp;rdquo;?
Moderated by Nan Aron (lecturer, author, and President of Alliance for Justice), the panel consisted of:
 Angelo Falcón: President and Founder of the National Institute for Latino Policy Keesha Gaskins: Senior Counsel in the Brennan Center`s Democracy Program Lawrence Lessig: Professor of Law at Harvard University (and much more) John Samples: Director of the Cato Institute Center for Representative Government  The discussion was quite interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multidimensional matrix of epistemology</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/a-multidimensional-matrix-of-epistemology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 09:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/a-multidimensional-matrix-of-epistemology/</guid>
      <description>I have no clue about physics or philosophy. But just like, when thinking theoretical physics, I cant help but reach the conclusion that time is a form of energy, when I think of epistemology, I cant help but to think of it in a multidimensional matrix, of which we can usually only grasp part, because the interconnexions we trace are linear an unidirectional.
It`s a well known fact that our brain is not built to comprehend reality, but &amp;ldquo;to make sense&amp;rdquo; of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting videos</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/interesting-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 22:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/interesting-videos/</guid>
      <description>Let me share some odd videos I have watched recently, thanks to Leaitrice and Patricia:
The famous &amp;quot;Sunscreen&amp;rdquo; music video(the text comes from an essaywritten in 1997 by Mary Schmich, a columnist at the Chicago Tribune, as a graduation speech for the class of `97) which gives some amazing advice for life. There is even a StarWars Version.
Drunk History: get some history students drunk, have them narrate historical events, while reenacting them&amp;hellip; more fun than it seems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comment on &amp;quot;Debunking Putin`s Newest Myth&amp;quot; by Alexander Yanov</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/comment-on-quotdebunking-putins-newest-mythquot-by-alexander-yanov/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 22:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/comment-on-quotdebunking-putins-newest-mythquot-by-alexander-yanov/</guid>
      <description>After reading &amp;ldquo;Debunking Putin`s Newest Myth&amp;rdquo; by Alexander Yanov, PhD, and with all my respect and admiration for this very well known historian of Russian nationalisms:
Although quite brilliant and eloquent, I believe it is not incisive and daring enough in debunking Putin`s newest myth. It takes a very conservative approach, perhaps letting a Western traditional philosophy baggage and inclination take the part of pure reason and belief, which is usually needed, in equal parts, to fight a political/philosophical quarrel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay for Nebula`s new photobook</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/essay-for-nebulas-new-photobook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 13:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/essay-for-nebulas-new-photobook/</guid>
      <description>I have contributed an essay to the book (PDF soon available for free online, and for purchase in book format -a few sample images shown here-) of an exhibition I am curating. 3 years in the making, &amp;ldquo;Gaze, Reflexion, Fusion&amp;rdquo; is the highly poetical but politically charged work of one of the most interesting new photographers in the New York art scene: NEBULA.
From Tokyo to San Francisco, Madrid to Seoul, the Spanish photographer Nebula has traveled to 10 cities in 4 countries in order to find inspiration and the right images (somethimes a fleeting reflexion of it) to bring to life what she feels about art, identity, apropriationism, feminism, and psychoanalysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I beat Watson at Jeopardy (more or less)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 18:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in my previous post, at IBM Innovation Center in Chicago they have a Watson(more info here) interactive kiosk with which to play an interactive game of Jeopardy. In case you have been living in a cave for the past few months, Watson beatJeopardy human champions on live TV, the significanceof which can not be overstated.
Now, remember: this is a &amp;ldquo;small version&amp;rdquo; of Watson, and a &amp;ldquo;self-contained&amp;rdquo; version of Jeopardy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real strength</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/real-strength/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 17:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/real-strength/</guid>
      <description>As I head for the shower at the gym, wondering if I should stay longer on the bike, lift more weights, or try a new boxing class, I find the real meaning of strength lying right there in front of me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom of religion, freedom of expression, and public spaces</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/freedom-of-religion-freedom-of-expression-and-public-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 17:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/freedom-of-religion-freedom-of-expression-and-public-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Picture.
Question: why do I have to cross the street on my way home?
Debate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A definition of art</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/a-definition-of-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 10:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/a-definition-of-art/</guid>
      <description>Seeking the definition of Art for a while, I can not find one that satisfies me, nor I seem to be able to reach one by myself. Here is as far as I have been able to get so far:
 Art is giving the opportunity of being to something that would never be
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A conversation with Spanish Philosopher Fernando Sabater at Instituto Cervantes NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/a-conversation-with-spanish-philosopher-fernando-sabater-at-instituto-cervantes-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 13:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/a-conversation-with-spanish-philosopher-fernando-sabater-at-instituto-cervantes-ny/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday May 2nd, I had the pleasure to meet Fernando Sabaterat Instituto Cervantes, NY.
The conversation was lighthearted and included many anecdotes and trvia, but also a good dose of Philosophy and Psychology wisdom and aphorisms (like those by Andrés Newman). Here are some delicious quotes by him:
  Dont attack, dont comply Childhood is always bad: wether because it was bad and left you a trauma, or because it was good and it frustrates you to leave it behind Happyness is also hard to bear Skepticism grows, and thats why when I am about to make a statement (particularly if it is a grand one) I end up laughing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC anarchist book fair</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/nyc-anarchist-book-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 13:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/nyc-anarchist-book-fair/</guid>
      <description>Since I could not get a hold of tickts for New Museum`s Seven on Seven, I decided to make the most out of my day yesterday (defying my cold), so I even had time to visit the NYC anarchist book fair, at Judson Church (Washington Square).
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5731668030633382577]
I wish I had had more time to devote to exploring all the literature (great and aweful) on display. But at least I had time to notice:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I admire these criminals</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-admire-these-criminals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 15:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-admire-these-criminals/</guid>
      <description>In Spain, the conservative PP government is planning to make &amp;ldquo;passive resistance&amp;rdquo; a crime(as well as organizing demonstrations using internet technologies).
I have these 4 criminals` magnetic puppets on my fridge. 2 were outlawed (and had to flee) by German Nazis. 1 had to flee Spanish dictatorship because he was a Communist. And the other one was thrown in jail by British occupation forces for &amp;ldquo;passive resistance&amp;rdquo;.
 I will not let anyone walk through my mind with their dirty feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curators` thoughts</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/curators-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 00:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/curators-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>On September 28, 2011, Hou Hanru, Director of Exhibitions and Public Programs at the San Francisco Art Institute said on a lecture (Curator`s Perspective) in New York:
 I think the worst exhibition in the world is the exhibition that is organized like a book. We see this a lot, an exhibition that takes the artwork as an illustration of a concept. I think an exhibition is not necessary for this: frankly, it`s too expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am such an ignorant</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-am-such-an-ignorant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 21:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-am-such-an-ignorant/</guid>
      <description>No wise man ever wished to be younger
Live everyday of your life
 Jonathan Swift</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The price of standing up for your rights: Opt-Out at Atlanta`s airport scanner</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-price-of-standing-up-for-your-rights-opt-out-at-atlantas-airport-scanner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 14:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-price-of-standing-up-for-your-rights-opt-out-at-atlantas-airport-scanner/</guid>
      <description>Atlanta`s Hartsfield airport has been having one of those uselessscanners that show passengers naked for a while now. But the last time I was there, they were being tested, and most passengers did not go through them. Today, though, as I approached the security line, I saw that next to every metal detector, there was one of those scanners. &amp;ldquo;Wow, this is getting worse&amp;rdquo;, I thought, while seeing how almost everybody was going through the scanners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At a WhiteBox NY exhibition closing party</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/at-a-whitebox-ny-exhibition-closing-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 15:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/at-a-whitebox-ny-exhibition-closing-party/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I attended WhiteBox`s exhibition closing party. The invitation said:
 Author and curator Raul Zamudioin conversation with Mookie Tenembaum.
Please join us at White Boxfor the closing reception of DISILLUSIONISM, and to engage in a stimulating conversation between Raul Zamudio and Mookie Tenembaum at 8pm sharp. Mookie will be presenting his new artist book, Paranoia. Malbec wines and truffles will be served.
 Although I am grateful for the invitation, and it sure was an interesting event, some things just beg to be commented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards an oversimplification cliff: when green=drunks</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/towards-an-oversimplification-cliff-when-greendrunks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 18:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/towards-an-oversimplification-cliff-when-greendrunks/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday morning, as I was walking towards the gym on Park Avenue, I saw waves of young adults (although acting like teenagers or frat boys) wearing green (some just a t-shirt or sweater, some a full leprechaun costume) on a procession towards their favorite Irish watering hole to &amp;ldquo;celebrate&amp;rdquo; St. Patricks Day in the only way that they seem to believe to be appropriate, besides a 5th Ave. official parade: drink until you pass out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spain – US business = Pride Vs Arrogance</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/spain-us-business-pride-vs-arrogance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 20:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/spain-us-business-pride-vs-arrogance/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, in a meeting at the Setai Hotel in NY, Michael (with over 3 decades of experience working with US and Spanish corporations) perfectly described what is like to do business between the USA and Spain:
 A struggle between American arrogance and Spanish pride
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of context in the interpretation (and enjoyment) of a work of art</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-importance-of-context-in-the-interpretation-and-enjoyment-of-a-work-of-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 01:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-importance-of-context-in-the-interpretation-and-enjoyment-of-a-work-of-art/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went to 3 exhibitions/events that have allowed me to see the importance of context in the interpretation (and enjoyment) of a work of art. Note that I differentiate &amp;ldquo;interpretation&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;enjoyment&amp;rdquo;, although for many of us, those two concepts go hand in hand. But this is just a short post, so the Phenomenological Aesthetics will have to wait (you can read Dewey, Hartmann, Adorno, Ortega y Gasset, Sartre, etc, etc in the meantime 😉 )</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture in today`s world in a state of polarized anomie</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/culture-in-todays-world-in-a-state-of-polarized-anomie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 17:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/culture-in-todays-world-in-a-state-of-polarized-anomie/</guid>
      <description>When Émile Durkheim wrote on the concept of anomie (expanding on Jean-Marie Guyau`s work) in his 1897 book Suicide, he spoke of one end of anomie: a society with too much rigidity and little individual discretion causing a destructive mismatch (moral deregulation and an absence of legitimate aspirations).
This is happening in the XXI century world, in many countries: those totalitarian (military or religious) societies where the social rule, expectations, and repression conform a cage around individuals, deposessing them of their individuality, their aspirations, subtly (or otherwise) imposing a social corset where the individual can not be itself, concentrating only on breathing, surviving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Zen ad making me sick</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/anti-zen-ad-making-me-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 10:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/anti-zen-ad-making-me-sick/</guid>
      <description>As I walk towards my office, I see an ad that makes me sick (as a matter of fact, I see many, but this one points to something other that the consumerism-sexism-excess that we are so dangerously getting used to).
The ad says &amp;ldquo;Turn now into memories&amp;rdquo;. How wrong is that?!!
Now is now. Now has to be now. Now should be now. Now has to remain now.
When you strive to &amp;ldquo;turn now into memories&amp;rdquo;, you are missing out on the real now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate MLK day with RX2008 mix</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/celebrate-mlk-day-with-rx2008-mix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 09:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/celebrate-mlk-day-with-rx2008-mix/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligence and heart quote</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/intelligence-and-heart-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 05:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/intelligence-and-heart-quote/</guid>
      <description>Intelligence could not represent for a long time the part of the heart.
 François de la Rochefoucauld</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga Guru uses copyright to sue competitor</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 19:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</guid>
      <description>Ego, money, power, abuse, restriction&amp;hellip; shame on those who stain the &amp;ldquo;holy&amp;rdquo; teachings.
Source: NYT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are charitable dinners and then charitable dinners</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/there-are-charitable-dinners-and-then-charitable-dinners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 10:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/there-are-charitable-dinners-and-then-charitable-dinners/</guid>
      <description>I hate charitable dinners where most (or almost all) of the money goes to caviar, tuxedos, valet parking and other hoopla.
Fortunately there are other charitable dinners, where you wont see any &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;httpss://www.escolar.net/MT/archives/2011/11/la-nueva-politica-de-igualdad.html&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;httpss://www.escolar.net/MT/archives/2011/11/la-nueva-politica-de-igualdad.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;PP mothers&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, like yesterdays organized by Didi, where people sit on the floor, eat off plastic plates, and enjoy Didis deliciously vegan cooking and sincere love, so just about all money collected goes to Calcuttas orphans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a movement!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-a-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 10:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-a-movement/</guid>
      <description>First things first: thanks to whomever thought I would be interested in joining MCAthrough RiseUp, BUT&amp;hellip;
 Don`t subscribe me to a list without my consent Don`t do so without at least letting me know who you are Don`t assume I might be interested in something because it sounds related to my interest Don`t align me with &amp;ldquo;scientific socialism&amp;rdquo; when I am a declared anarchist Don`t make me waste my time on a list where the first 20 or so messages are split between arguing troskist, marxist, rose of lenburguist, bujarinist, bakuninist, leninist, hotsiminist, guevarist, maoist, castrist&amp;hellip; and people who want to be taken off the list  So, thanks (and I show it by talking about your project here), but show a little respect for other people`s rights, please.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tragedy of probability ignorance</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-tragedy-of-probability-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 13:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-tragedy-of-probability-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>When a M. Phil. from Cambridge, A.B. from Harvard, and M.D. from UCal writes an articleinsisting on a probabilistic fallacy, a trap where, in one way or another, many have fallen (from Eccles to Nagel), and this article is echoed in many sites (such as BoingBoing) and an infographicis made and becomes staff pick at visual.ly&amp;hellip; then you know ignorance is everywhere and very dangerous.
Read the article, then read Roy Weatherford`s &amp;ldquo;Philosophical foundations of probability theory&amp;rdquo; (or maybe something simpler), and once you grasp the concept of &amp;ldquo;a priori theories of probability&amp;rdquo;, laugh at those who think each one of us is a miracle&amp;hellip; we all are, but not because the probability of us being born is extremely small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finishing is not ending</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/finishing-is-not-ending/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 08:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/finishing-is-not-ending/</guid>
      <description>October knew, of course, that the action of turning a page, of ending a chapter or of shutting a book, did not end a tale.
 &amp;ldquo;The man who was October&amp;rdquo;, G. K. Chesterton</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>