<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 02:45:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I won the Anti-Patents Policy Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/i-won-the-anti-patents-policy-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 02:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/i-won-the-anti-patents-policy-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>On September 13, Mind the Bridge hosted a policy hackathon sponsored by Dell at the MTB Innovation Center in San Francisco. The Dell PolicyHack™ brought together entrepreneurs and U.S./EU policy experts to solve policy challenges. The goal is to productively brainstorm and to provide top-line thinking that can inspire and serve as basis to develop and implement full policies.
My team was formed by:
 Sara R. Klucking (Section Chief, Innovation &amp;amp; Programs, Office of Science and Technology Cooperation, US Department of State) Bogdan Ceobanu (Policy Officer, Startups &amp;amp; Innovation, European Commission) David Hodgson (CEO, Hummingbird Labs) me  The five teams had 75 minutes to come up with a policy solution to issue areas that impact entrepreneurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking to Prof. Church about machine learning applied to genomic research</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/talking-to-prof.-church-about-machine-learning-applied-to-genomic-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 12:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/talking-to-prof.-church-about-machine-learning-applied-to-genomic-research/</guid>
      <description>During my flight to Boston I read “Regenesis”, the interesting genomic science book by Professor George Church, which was a gift from my friend Dr. Raminderpal Singh.
On Wednesday evening I had a very interesting conversation in Boston with both of them. Neither of them needs an introduction in the genomics world, but for those of you outside the field:
 Raminder is Vice-president at Eagle Genomics and Advisor at Kanteron Systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up my first art exhibit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/setting-up-my-first-art-exhibit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 14:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/setting-up-my-first-art-exhibit/</guid>
      <description>The weekend of February 27 and 28 I set up my first art exhibition as Independent International Art Curator.
In collaboration with the Internet Freedom Festival, held in Las Naves (Valencia) from 2 to 6 March, Net Freedom Art Showis an international, itinerant, collective and multidisciplinary contemporary art show. After its debut in Valencia, it will be exhibited in galleries around the world (New York, London, Santiago de Chile, and Kaunas).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The White House Chief Data Scientist assures me the White House strongly supports encryption and opposes back doors</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/the-white-house-chief-data-scientist-assures-me-the-white-house-strongly-supports-encryption-and-opposes-back-doors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 13:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/the-white-house-chief-data-scientist-assures-me-the-white-house-strongly-supports-encryption-and-opposes-back-doors/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday March 1 I had a conversation with Dr. DJ Patil, the First White House Chief Data Scientist, at the Venetian Hotel in Las Vegas.
He was interested in discussing ways in which the White House can help healthcare technology companies like mine. The first issue I raised was my concern over the FBI’s request for Apple to decrypt a suspected criminal’s iPhone.
My position in this issue is well known: weak encryption means weak security for ALL of us, so nobody can request weak security for security’s sake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft comes to Valencia to meet with my team, collaborate on medical technology research, and discuss a Term Sheet</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/microsoft-comes-to-valencia-to-meet-with-my-team-collaborate-on-medical-technology-research-and-discuss-a-term-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 08:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/microsoft-comes-to-valencia-to-meet-with-my-team-collaborate-on-medical-technology-research-and-discuss-a-term-sheet/</guid>
      <description>On February 25 a group of medical imaging researchers from Microsoft came to our company’s headquarters in Valencia (Spain) for a day-long workshop on bleeding edge medical image software.
I must admit that just a few years ago I would have laughed at the idea of such an occurrence for many reasons. But things change, and now Microsoft is much more open (and convinced) about Open Source software, their researchers have demonstrated exceptional ability in advanced medical imaging analysis algorithms (unlike their failed business strategy around Amalga), and my company has grown and innovated to the point where it captures the interest and even enthusiasm of some of the largest technology companies in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I stood up against a terrorist in a German train</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/i-stood-up-against-a-terrorist-in-a-german-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 12:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/i-stood-up-against-a-terrorist-in-a-german-train/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, after spending the day at a tradeshow in Düsseldorf, on my way by train to the hotel in Mülheim, I stopped in the town of Duisburg, which was on my way, because I heard they were setting up a Christmas market. The market was indeed being set up, but it was still closed, so I decided to go back to the station. To avoid the sprinkling rain I took the 901 tram at König-Heinrich Platz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited by the London Stock Exchange to participate in the market opening ceremony</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/invited-by-the-london-stock-exchange-to-participate-in-the-market-opening-ceremony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 14:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/invited-by-the-london-stock-exchange-to-participate-in-the-market-opening-ceremony/</guid>
      <description>On Friday, November 6th, I was invited by Marcus Stuttard, head of AIM (the London Stock Exchange’s growth market), to participate in the London Stock Exchange market opening ceremony, which takes place daily at 8:00 am.
The ceremony offers companies joining London Stock Exchange’s markets the opportunity to mark their success on the day of their admission. The event was followed by drinks and breakfast.
The reason why I was invited is because one of my companies (Kanteron Systems) had been selected as a member of the #ScaleUpClub 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Million masks march</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/million-masks-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 14:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/million-masks-march/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday, coming back home from a meeting, I run into the Million Masks March. While I assume I agree with most of their anti-system protests (the truth is I did not bother to read them), I think their choice of Guy Fawkes as an &amp;ldquo;icon&amp;rdquo;, even if a graphical one as proposed by the comic/movie &amp;ldquo;V for Vendetta&amp;rdquo;, is a very stupid one. Just read about what that historical figure had in mind and judge for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pina Bausch dance company at the Howard Gilman Opera House Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/pina-bausch-dance-company-at-the-howard-gilman-opera-house-brooklyn-academy-of-music-bam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 20:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/pina-bausch-dance-company-at-the-howard-gilman-opera-house-brooklyn-academy-of-music-bam/</guid>
      <description>Between my trip to Mexico and the next one to Peru and Colombia, I spent a weekend in New York, and took the opportunity to go with my wife and her ex-husband to see &amp;ldquo;Kontakthof&amp;rdquo; by Pina Bausch dance company at the Howard Gilman Opera House Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM).
Before the show we went to a South African restaurant in Brooklyn called Madiba. Interesting mix of flavors and decor, great seafood imported directly from Mozambique, rustic atmosphere and somewhat &amp;ldquo;hipster&amp;rdquo; but not too much despite being in Brooklyn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wearable review: Withings Pulse Ox, WS-30 WiFi scale, and Blood Pressure Monitor</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/wearable-review-withings-pulse-ox-ws-30-wifi-scale-and-blood-pressure-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 20:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/wearable-review-withings-pulse-ox-ws-30-wifi-scale-and-blood-pressure-monitor/</guid>
      <description>Due to the launch of the biosensors module for my company`s medical imaging and data solution a few days ago, the Withings company sent me a biosensor (wearable) Withings Pulse Ox, manometer BPM and WiFi WS-30 scale for testing and integration tests ahead of some national projects we are about to sign in London and Santiago de Chile.
All three came in luxury packaging, and were relatively easy to connect and set up, at least for a &amp;ldquo;tinkerer&amp;rdquo; (there are people who gets annoyed if I use &amp;ldquo;hacker&amp;rdquo; as a synonym, although it is) like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innomedyx, one of the companies I co-founded, establishes the Clinical Innovation Center at the Polytechnic University of Valencia</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/07/innomedyx-one-of-the-companies-i-co-founded-establishes-the-clinical-innovation-center-at-the-polytechnic-university-of-valencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 09:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/07/innomedyx-one-of-the-companies-i-co-founded-establishes-the-clinical-innovation-center-at-the-polytechnic-university-of-valencia/</guid>
      <description>Innomedyx(Twitter, LinkedIn, FaceBook), a company I`m a co-founder of, has established the Clinical Innovation Center at the Polytechnic University of Valencia(Spain), the best BioTechnology University in Spain according to Spanish newspaper El Mundo.photo © UPVThe Dean of the Polytechnic University of Valencia (UPV), Francisco Mora, and the general director of Innomedyx Knowledge in Action, Rosa Valenzuela, signed a partnership agreement that formalizes the chair of Clinical Innovation company on July 1st.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reset the net</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited by Google to the Google Cloud Platform presentation</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-by-google-to-the-google-cloud-platform-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-by-google-to-the-google-cloud-platform-presentation/</guid>
      <description>March 25 Google NY invited me to their Google Cloud Platformpresentation in their Chelsea offices, 8 blocks away from my apartment.
Besides the interesting new features (here are the videos), and the delicious and healthy lunch buffet, I networked quite a lot, and had a few laughs about the highest concentration of Google Glasses per person I have seen so far. One thing is clear: genomics, which is one of the main things my two companies deal with, and the cloud, are closely related, and they will be even more in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the introduction of IBM Watson at WTC NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/invited-to-the-introduction-of-ibm-watson-at-wtc-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 13:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/invited-to-the-introduction-of-ibm-watson-at-wtc-ny/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday January 8th I was asked to hold a meeting regarding the potential involvement of my company (Kanteron Systems) in IBM’s Watson. It was a late night meeting, on the 54th floor of the still under construction World Trade Center. The reason why the meeting took place there is because the IBM team was finishing the set up of the next day’s Watson presentation.
What is Watson, you may ask?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banksy in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/banksy-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 16:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/banksy-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>Banksy is in New York for a month.
With the title &amp;ldquo;Better Out than In&amp;rdquo;, there is a blog, unofficial twitter account(along with the hashtag #banksyny) since it is not linked in the blog, and Instagram(really? Instagram?&amp;hellip; good grief; Im glad I dont have FaceBook so I can`t check if there is also a FB page)&amp;hellip; even a phone number (1 800 6564271) for each piece for which you can call and listen to a great message about (also accessible through the blog).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate cowardice, political hypocrisy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/corporate-cowardice-political-hypocrisy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 15:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/corporate-cowardice-political-hypocrisy/</guid>
      <description>On July 25 I was asked by someone at IBM to write an article about the use of the cloud in healthcare:
 I’d like to offer you the opportunity to author an article which we would look to promote across all of our social properties, other external communications as well as our paid media sponsorships, i.e. blogs.
 I was given suggestions on article length, topic, and keywords, but freedom to write whatever I wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am named Executive of the Year (Healthcare)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/08/i-am-named-executive-of-the-year-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 06:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/08/i-am-named-executive-of-the-year-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>I was named the winner of a Bronze Awardin the Executive of the Year – Health Products &amp;amp; Services category in the 10th Annual International Business Awards today.
More than 3,300 nominations from organizations of all sizes and in virtually every industry were considered in several categories, including Management Team of the Year, Corporate Social Responsibility Program of the Year, among others. I won (bronze) in the Executive of the Year for Health Products &amp;amp; Services category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police state: TXT with police alert in TX</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/police-state-txt-with-police-alert-in-tx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 14:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/police-state-txt-with-police-alert-in-tx/</guid>
      <description>While in Fort Worth, TX, I received the following TXT:
 They who can give up essential liberty to obtain a little temporary safety, deserve neither liberty nor safety.
 Benjamin Franklin, 1775</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am featured in an IBM ad</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/i-am-featured-in-an-ibm-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 15:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/i-am-featured-in-an-ibm-ad/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video interview (IBM Beacon Award)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/video-interview-ibm-beacon-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 17:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/video-interview-ibm-beacon-award/</guid>
      <description>Right after I accepted the IBM Beacon Award for Healthcare and Life Sciences given to my company (Kanteron Systems), I was video interviewed in the corridor. Here is the result:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Receveing an award in Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/receveing-an-award-in-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 17:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/receveing-an-award-in-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>From Monday 25 to Wednesday 27 I was in Las Vegas receving an award (IBM 2013 Beacon Award for Best Industry Solution, Healthcare and Life Sciences).
I dont like Las Vegas, too flashy, too empty, too superficial... but every time I go, I end up with interesting experiences and observations. Like the devastating effect extreme market capitalism can have on the credibility of institutions (Judge Judys branded slot machine?? WTF!!).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed for Zoom News about the Mega case</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/interviewed-for-zoom-news-about-the-mega-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/interviewed-for-zoom-news-about-the-mega-case/</guid>
      <description>Interviewedby Aurora Muñoz for Zoom News about the Mega case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article in El Mundo &amp;quot;Innovators&amp;quot; special</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/article-in-el-mundo-quotinnovatorsquot-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/article-in-el-mundo-quotinnovatorsquot-special/</guid>
      <description>Here (PDF)is a 3 page article Spanish newspaper El Mundo published on Monday in their &amp;ldquo;Innovators&amp;rdquo; special, featuring my company, Kanteron Systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>007 Skyfall at MoMA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/007-skyfall-at-moma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 21:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/007-skyfall-at-moma/</guid>
      <description>Although it may not be too obvious, I have been going through a few very hard weeks for several reasons. So someone who knows me well told me I should not be stupid, and should have fun. Let`s be it, then!
As part of their James Bond 50 years celebration, MoMA has been showing some of 007 movies in their collection (the largest by any museum in the world). So yesterday I was invited, and I of course invited Stephanie to be my guest, to the screening of the latest James Bond movie: &amp;ldquo;007 Skyfall&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After hurricane Sandy in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 20:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>From tilted posts to trees completely gone, after hurricane Sandy there were many signs of destruction around New York.
I had to stay at Stepahnie`s apartment (thank you again!) until Monday, because my building remained without power. And even after the power returned, the telephone and internet took two more days.
Some people were not so lucky, with all hotels fully booked, and had to stay at home for days without power or water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Sandy in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 20:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>To go from Baltimore to NY has been a real nightmare. I had a return train ticket for the 29th at night, but that was obviously cancelled. Amtrak then rebooked me on the first train out of Baltimore (at 03:45am on November 1st), and since flights or buses were not operating, I took it.
The nice lady at the travel agency got me a reservation on a flight to La Guardia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Sandy in Baltimore</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/hurricane-sandy-in-baltimore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 23:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/hurricane-sandy-in-baltimore/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20,000 homeless kids in NYC</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/20000-homeless-kids-in-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 02:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/20000-homeless-kids-in-nyc/</guid>
      <description>Number of homeless kids in NYC last year: 16,000
Number of homeless kids in NYC this year: 20,000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The longest war in US history</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-longest-war-in-us-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-longest-war-in-us-history/</guid>
      <description>Afghanistan already is the longest (official) war in US history.
In order to begin to understand that mess, as usual in modern history, we may have to go back to the end of World War II, when Pakistan`s colonial nominees, the &amp;ldquo;Taliban&amp;rdquo;, were sent to take over Afghanistan to give them a strategic edge over India in the war over Kashmir.
Today the Taliban and Pakistans ISI (Directorate for Inter-Service Intelligence) alliance are at the heart of why the USA is stuck in an endless war: the USA aligns, or so it would seem, much more with India in terms of values, policy, economy, etc, than with Pakistan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incredible photo of last night`s &amp;quot;derecho&amp;quot; storm in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/incredible-photo-of-last-nights-quotderechoquot-storm-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 10:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/incredible-photo-of-last-nights-quotderechoquot-storm-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>Last night`s storm was, again, AMAZING. I was not exactly in a position to take a picture, &amp;ldquo;too concentrated on something else&amp;rdquo; (although I would have loved it), but this is a great shot by Ryan Brenizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazing storm in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/amazing-storm-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 18:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/amazing-storm-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>I have been under tropical storms several times in the jungle. But I have never seen anything like today`s storm over Manhattan. Absolutely incredible.The Guardian. Photo: Inga Sarda-Sorensen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering snow today at near 100ºF in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/remembering-snow-today-at-near-100%C2%BAf-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 12:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/remembering-snow-today-at-near-100%C2%BAf-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>Today, #HelloSummer, at almost 100ºF in NY, is a good day to remember the snow. I took this picture of a promo stunt May 31st at Times Square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYPL support and citizen budget involvement</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/nypl-support-and-citizen-budget-involvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 12:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/nypl-support-and-citizen-budget-involvement/</guid>
      <description>After supporting the NYPL efforts to fight back budget cuts, I have received a lovely message of thanks from Christine C. Quinn (Speaker, NYC Council), along with a very nice suggestion:
 Dear New Yorker, Many thanks for your email expressing your support for our city`s libraries. [&amp;hellip;]
We cant do it alone, though, and I hope youll consider signing up for Council &amp;ldquo;enews&amp;rdquo;. These issue-based e-mail updates are a great way for us to stay connected and engaged with you and other New Yorkers about the budget, healthcare, and other important issues affecting our city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry Elephants</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/angry-elephants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 21:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/angry-elephants/</guid>
      <description>via APM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal action against Bankia and Rato</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/legal-action-against-bankia-and-rato/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 17:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/legal-action-against-bankia-and-rato/</guid>
      <description>The citizen platform #15MpaRato is preparing legal action to take Rodrigo Rato to court.
Today they started asking small Bankia stockholders to file an anonymous report, so it can be used in a lawsuit.
Here is their news release [ES]:
https://15mparato.wordpress.com/2012/05/29/accionesparato/
Here is their website:
https://15mparato.wordpress.com/2012/05/29/accionesparato/
Here is their twitter:
@15MpaRato
Hashtag:
#accionpaRato
If you know any Bankia stockholder, ask him/her to contact:
15mparato@gmail.com
Good luck!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journalists covering FB IPO</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/journalists-covering-fb-ipo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 13:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/journalists-covering-fb-ipo/</guid>
      <description>May 18th, on my way to the subway, outside my office.
Look at the pictures. The making of the circus. Draw your own conclusions (and yes, the third one is a journalist on top of a wooden box to make her look taller).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A conversation with Walt Mossberg and Kara Swisher at NYU</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/a-conversation-with-walt-mossberg-and-kara-swisher-at-nyu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 11:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/a-conversation-with-walt-mossberg-and-kara-swisher-at-nyu/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday I went to New York University for a nice conversation in the Inside the Internet Garageseries, with journalists Walt Mossberg and Kara Swisher (AllThingsDigital, Wall Street Journal, etc).
Besides the very interesting bio/background overview of them that the interviewer did, here are some quotes that caught my attention.
Walt Mossberg:
 IT departments are the most regressive force in tech, blocking new tech adoption
The story goes that Larry Page asked Steve Jobs for advice, he said &amp;ldquo;Find the 5 things you do best, and focus on it&amp;rdquo;, which its what hes doing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letting data talk</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/letting-data-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 18:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/letting-data-talk/</guid>
      <description>Government debt does not explain it all:Unemployment is, indeed, quite inapelable:And minimum wage:So, perhaps, taking all those (and the last &amp;ldquo;devastating evidence&amp;rdquo; one) graphs into account, French and German governments have tricked, via manipulative markets and rating agencies, ignorant technocrat Spain`s PP government into cutting social spending (like education and health, which in turn becomes productivity, and minimum wage and job stability, which promotes spending and growth) so we go deeper into the hole, and they take advantage of our excellent engineers at a low rate, while speculating with debt and making sure Spain does not become a strong competitor&amp;hellip;Don`t they realise that with a monarchy that &amp;ldquo;shoots itself in the foot trying to hunt elephants and hiding corruption and scandalous ties&amp;rdquo;, a media that is so self complacent and ass kissing that feels more like brothels, politicians so entrenched in the corrupt game that with two degrees of separation you could not find an honest Spaniard anymore, a starch church mingling in public affairs, and a population so absorbed by soccer, celebrities and fear, they do not need to do that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I admire these criminals</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-admire-these-criminals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 15:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-admire-these-criminals/</guid>
      <description>In Spain, the conservative PP government is planning to make &amp;ldquo;passive resistance&amp;rdquo; a crime(as well as organizing demonstrations using internet technologies).
I have these 4 criminals` magnetic puppets on my fridge. 2 were outlawed (and had to flee) by German Nazis. 1 had to flee Spanish dictatorship because he was a Communist. And the other one was thrown in jail by British occupation forces for &amp;ldquo;passive resistance&amp;rdquo;.
 I will not let anyone walk through my mind with their dirty feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social-media inspired cocktails at Mandarin Oriental NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/social-media-inspired-cocktails-at-mandarin-oriental-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 11:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/social-media-inspired-cocktails-at-mandarin-oriental-ny/</guid>
      <description>seen in Tumblr (user: hragv)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marvel Marathon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/marvel-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 23:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/marvel-marathon/</guid>
      <description>From the #thisIsHowItsDone (not the movie adaptations, but special events to make people go more to the movie theaters) department, here is an awesome initiative from AMC movie theaters:
Get ready to watch the greatest Marvel movie event ever held at your local AMC Theatre on May 3rd! Experience THE ULTIMATE MARVEL MARATHON with six movies on one epic day. Watch the heroes’ stories unfold as they assemble for the midnight premiere of The Avengers 3D!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is your Mac infected? Find out (and fix it if it is)!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/is-your-mac-infected-find-out-and-fix-it-if-it-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 17:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/is-your-mac-infected-find-out-and-fix-it-if-it-is/</guid>
      <description>Over 600,000 Macs are infected with the FlashBack Trojan. Is yours one of those? Let`s find out.
Open the Terminal (c`mon, be a hacker, not a slacker) and type:
if it says:
 The domain/default pair of (/Applications/Safari.app/Contents/Info, LSEnvironment) does not exist
 that means your Mac is ok so far (otherwise, go here). Then type:
if it says:
 The domain/default pair of (/Users/[your user name here]/.MacOSX/environment, DYLD_INSERT_LIBRARIES) does not exist</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The price of standing up for your rights: Opt-Out at Atlanta`s airport scanner</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-price-of-standing-up-for-your-rights-opt-out-at-atlantas-airport-scanner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 14:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-price-of-standing-up-for-your-rights-opt-out-at-atlantas-airport-scanner/</guid>
      <description>Atlanta`s Hartsfield airport has been having one of those uselessscanners that show passengers naked for a while now. But the last time I was there, they were being tested, and most passengers did not go through them. Today, though, as I approached the security line, I saw that next to every metal detector, there was one of those scanners. &amp;ldquo;Wow, this is getting worse&amp;rdquo;, I thought, while seeing how almost everybody was going through the scanners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spain, second country in the world with the most &amp;quot;disappeared&amp;quot; after Cambodia</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/spain-second-country-in-the-world-with-the-most-quotdisappearedquot-after-cambodia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 18:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/spain-second-country-in-the-world-with-the-most-quotdisappearedquot-after-cambodia/</guid>
      <description>After 36 years of democracy, [Spain] is the second country in the world with the most &amp;ldquo;disappeared&amp;rdquo; after Cambodia
 SourceRegional President Campsfree, the Duke Urdangarínseems like is not going to be punished&amp;hellip; and judge Garzonbeing judged. And you ask me why I say I am &amp;ldquo;European&amp;rdquo; rather than &amp;ldquo;Spaniard&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Valencian&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almodovar and SGAE force cancellation of film screenings at NY Library</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/almodovar-and-sgae-force-cancellation-of-film-screenings-at-ny-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 17:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/almodovar-and-sgae-force-cancellation-of-film-screenings-at-ny-library/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went to the New York Public Library to see Pedro Almodovars &amp;quot;Talk to her&amp;quot;, as part of a &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.nypl.org/blog/2011/12/06/films-pedro-almodovar&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.nypl.org/blog/2011/12/06/films-pedro-almodovar&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;series&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; of Almodovars films screenings in the NYPL. But, to my surprise, the screening (and remainder ones) had been cancelled.
I talked to the person in the information desk, and she told me that the collecting society (that would be the despicable SGAE, which does not even deserve a link in my blog) and Almodovar`s Production company (El Deseo Producciones) had raised what they had previously been asking for as royalties or compensation for the (free) screening of the (not in movie theater) films, and the amount they were now asking was so high, the NYPL could not afford it, so they had to cancel the screenings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Akemashite omedetou (Happy New Year)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/akemashite-omedetou-happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 22:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/akemashite-omedetou-happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antony and the Johnsons at Radio City Music Hall... indescribable</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/antony-and-the-johnsons-at-radio-city-music-hall...-indescribable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 16:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/antony-and-the-johnsons-at-radio-city-music-hall...-indescribable/</guid>
      <description>Antony and the Johnsonsperformed last Thursday 26th, at the Radio City Music HallSWANLIGHTS, a one-night-only performance commissioned by the Museum of Modern Art (MoMA), NY, the most amazing concert I have ever been to.
One would think that the fact that the performance took place in the world`s largest (and one of the most reputed) theater/music venue, or that the place was chock-full of celebrities (I had Björk right next to me in the line to pick up the reserved tickets), would add to the glamour and grandiose of the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEDxManhattan: Changing the way we eat</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/tedxmanhattan-changing-the-way-we-eat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 16:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/tedxmanhattan-changing-the-way-we-eat/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow, January 21st, 2012, NY</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protest against SOPA on your site: easy code</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/protest-against-sopa-on-your-site-easy-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 09:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/protest-against-sopa-on-your-site-easy-code/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Sara, there is a very easy way to add code to your site to protest against SOPA:
Drop the following code in between your two tags on your site, your users will be redirected to the blackout page that describes what you are doing and why.
`Then, when the protest is over, simply remove the added code. The protest is starting at 12am on 1/18, and lasts 24 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia blackout protesting SOPA and PIPA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/wikipedia-blackout-protesting-sopa-and-pipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 19:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/wikipedia-blackout-protesting-sopa-and-pipa/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;div&amp;gt; Today, the Wikipedia community &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;w:en:Wikipedia:SOPA initiative/Action&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/en:Wikipedia:SOPA_initiative/Action&amp;quot;&amp;gt;announced its decision&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; to black out the English-language Wikipedia for 24 hours, worldwide, beginning at 05:00 UTC on Wednesday, January 18 (you can read the &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;Press releases/English Wikipedia to go dark&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Press_releases/English_Wikipedia_to_go_dark&amp;quot;&amp;gt;statement from the Wikimedia Foundation here&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;). The blackout is a protest against proposed legislation in the United States—the &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;w:en:Stop Online Piracy Act&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/en:Stop_Online_Piracy_Act&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Stop Online Piracy Act (SOPA)&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The absurd hypocrisy of the recent &amp;quot;Intelectual Property&amp;quot; legal abuse</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-absurd-hypocrisy-of-the-recent-quotintelectual-propertyquot-legal-abuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 17:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-absurd-hypocrisy-of-the-recent-quotintelectual-propertyquot-legal-abuse/</guid>
      <description>The USA has become the largest exporter of censorship.
Based on wrong beliefs, manipulated data, and self-declared ignorant politicians, their legislative body cooks up a law designed to restrict competition, serving the interests (apparently, although as any freshman Economics student will tell you, that is not really the case) of an oligopoly of media-(sic)culture megacorporations that would not recognized the present (not to say &amp;ldquo;future&amp;rdquo;) if it hit them in the face, represented by multi-million dollar copyright infringers, while stomping on basic citizens` rights (not that they seem to care anyway, since they allow such basic rights violations as warrantless GPS monitoring, or unlimited incarceration without trial).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook: couple breaker for drunks</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/facebook-couple-breaker-for-drunks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 05:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/facebook-couple-breaker-for-drunks/</guid>
      <description>Interesting couple of trivia about Facebook in UK:
 Facebook blamed for one-third marriage breakdowns British Facebook users intoxicated in 76% of their photos  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga Guru uses copyright to sue competitor</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 19:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</guid>
      <description>Ego, money, power, abuse, restriction&amp;hellip; shame on those who stain the &amp;ldquo;holy&amp;rdquo; teachings.
Source: NYT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art gallery inaugurations</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/art-gallery-inaugurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 23:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/art-gallery-inaugurations/</guid>
      <description>Tonight we went to the MaysonGallery inaugural inauguration &amp;ldquo;Launch&amp;rdquo; featuring works by Doug Henders, Scott Hewett, Michael Oatman, Jeff Quinn, Bastienne Schmidt, and Rodger Stevens. It was way too crowded to see the works, but it was fun. Particularly because we enjoyed dinner at almost next door JinJapanese restaurant.
But we wish we were at another art inauguration: IVAM`s Claudio Zirotti.
My dear friend and mentor presents &amp;ldquo;Without Time&amp;rdquo; (PDF), an excellent exhibit of his wonderful art at Valencia`s IVAM Modern Art Institute, until February 19th 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senate celebrates Bill of Rights authorizing indefinite detentions</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/senate-celebrates-bill-of-rights-authorizing-indefinite-detentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 19:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/senate-celebrates-bill-of-rights-authorizing-indefinite-detentions/</guid>
      <description>The US Senate &amp;ldquo;celebrates&amp;rdquo; the 220th anniversary of the ratification of the Bill of Rights by passing a defense billthat authorizes indefinite detentions of American terrorism suspects.
Beautiful irony. Source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approaching 1984</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/approaching-1984/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 12:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/approaching-1984/</guid>
      <description>Governments that use stats to lie, that shamelessly change political stands, that pocket millionaires paychecks and retirements in even in times of crisis&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, that &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.ij.org/about/4058&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.ij.org/about/4058&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;steal from citizens with any excuse&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, that &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://boingboing.net/2011/09/25/rejected-designs-for-the-federal-housing-finance-agency-seal.html?utm_source=pulsenews&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+boingboing%2FiBag+%28Boing+Boing%29&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://boingboing.net/2011/09/25/rejected-designs-for-the-federal-housing-finance-agency-seal.html?utm_source=pulsenews&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+boingboing%2FiBag+%28Boing+Boing%29&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;do not care to spend 400$ or 600,000€ in a logo&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, that allow an &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://youtu.be/6zZ_JfROhOE&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://youtu.be/6zZ_JfROhOE&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;out of control financial system&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (and force lower interest to finance a war driven by personal economic interests in a time that required higher interests) which places us at the edge of the cliff and dares to &amp;quot;rescue them&amp;quot; with everybodys money, with a cost higher than which would be needed to end poverty in the world, and not making any changes so it does not happen again in the financial or food markets&amp;hellip; all this and more, with complete impunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Die</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/die/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 10:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/die/</guid>
      <description>Everyday 156,000 people die in the world. Yesterday a Mexican flower seller died from shot wounds, a Chinese mother died giving birth, a Turkish photographer died, a kid soldier was killed in Uganda, a Japanese widower died in love, and an American computer entrepreneur died, amongst others.
Keep thinking different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignorants eat shit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/ignorants-eat-shit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 12:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/ignorants-eat-shit/</guid>
      <description>According to this articlethe food people usually eat (thanks to my wife and my conscience, I have slightly healthier eating habits than most people) is pure shit: wood celulose in many foods, fruit juices over a year old, ammonia in meat, artificial blueberries, &amp;ldquo;free-range chicken&amp;rdquo; that is not free at all, and other lies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>