<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Why not? Utopia? on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/why-not-utopia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Why not? Utopia? on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 08:45:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/why-not-utopia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool online presentations with free software</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/05/cool-online-presentations-with-free-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 08:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/05/cool-online-presentations-with-free-software/</guid>
      <description>It has been a while since I wrote a tutorial to Share The Wealth, so it’s about time I shared some practical (if basic) knowledge beyond reposting a link.
For years I have had a pet project in the backburner: I wanted to create presentations without the need of dedicated software, commercial (like PowerPoint or Keynote), or free (like LibreOffice or OpenOffice). That way I could avoid bringing my computer to a lecture, and not worry about what computer system would be available in the auditorium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding government intrusion in my latest trip to the USA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/avoiding-government-intrusion-in-my-latest-trip-to-the-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 14:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/avoiding-government-intrusion-in-my-latest-trip-to-the-usa/</guid>
      <description>February 18 to 23 I traveled to Orlando, Florida (USA) for the HIMSS trade show. As much as I have enjoyed the magic of Orlando parks in the past, this was a pure business trip. I am an EU citizen (Spain) living in the UK, and I took a direct flight from London to Orlando. I had recently renewed my passport and ESTA, so I should be able to enter the USA without a problem right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Revolution needs a Revolution</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 17:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went with my wife and son to visit the Victoria &amp;amp; Albert`s Museum exhibition You Say You Want a Revolution? Records and Rebels 1966-1970. The aim of the exhibition was quite clear:
 How have the finished and unfinished revolutions of the late 1960s changed the way we live today and think about the future?
 I was very much looking forward to visiting the exhibition. It is SO timely, and SO needed, I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My EU policy recommendation published: &#34;Hacking Policy. Exploring Innovative Ways to Advance Policy Reform&#34;</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/my-eu-policy-recommendation-published-hacking-policy.-exploring-innovative-ways-to-advance-policy-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 10:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/my-eu-policy-recommendation-published-hacking-policy.-exploring-innovative-ways-to-advance-policy-reform/</guid>
      <description>Under the title &amp;ldquo;Hacking Policy. Exploring Innovative Ways to Advance Policy Reform&amp;rdquo; StartupEurope has published a report listing the Policy Recommendations that came out of the Policy Hackathon in San Francisco, where my team won the competition.
Download it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spare time fun: protein structure analysis of mutations causing inheritable diseases</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/spare-time-fun-protein-structure-analysis-of-mutations-causing-inheritable-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 08:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/spare-time-fun-protein-structure-analysis-of-mutations-causing-inheritable-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Most people I know would not consider protein structure analysis of mutations causing inheritable diseases &amp;ldquo;spare time fun&amp;rdquo;. Then again, most people I know don`t think I am like most people they know.
This week I`m a &amp;ldquo;single-dad&amp;rdquo;, since my wife is traveling. So my spare time right now is almost non existent. Nevertheless, the thought of mutating a Proline into a Glycine at position 22 intrigued me, so I spent a few minutes simulating it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego day 4</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 16:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-4/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, October 11th, was day four, and last, at the Exponential Medicine Conference in San Diego.
Some of the talks I enjoyed the most:
Exponential Thinking &amp;amp; Future Predictions: Ray Kurzweil Co-founder &amp;amp; Chancellor, Singularity University
Exponential Entrepreneurship:
 Zayna Khayat, PhD Lead, MaRS Health and Director, MaRS EXCITE Stephanie Marrus, MBA Entrepreneurship Center Director, UCSF  Investing In The Future: Vinod Khosla Founder, Khosla Ventures
Visualizing the Future of Medical Education, from VR to the OR:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego day 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 14:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-3/</guid>
      <description>Monday, October 10th was day 3 at the Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego.
For me the highlights were:
Bold Innovation: Peter Diamandis, MD Co-Founder, Singularity University and Founder &amp;amp; Chair, XPRIZE
Redesigning Care: Tony Young, PhD FRCS National Clinical Director for Innovation, NHS England
Bakul Patel, MBA Associate Director of Digital Health, Food and Drug Administration/Center for Devices and Radiological Health
Getting the xMED Scrubs Photo on the Beach, with an awesome drone:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Award and Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego day 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/award-and-exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 14:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/award-and-exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-2/</guid>
      <description>Sunday, October 9th, was day two at Exponential Medicine Conference in San Diego.
Some of the highlights were:
From ‘Omics to Action
 Moira Gunn, PhD Host, NPR’s Biotech Nation Larry Smarr, PhD Professor, UCSD and Director, Calit2 George Poste, DVM PhD FRS Chief Scientist, Complex Adaptive Systems Initiative- Arizona State University  Mobile, Connected, Digital Health
 David Albert, MD Founder, AliveCor Stanley Shaw, MD PhD Co-Director, MGH Center for Assessment Technology &amp;amp; Continuous Health Bakul Patel, MBA Associate Director of Digital Health, Food and Drug Administration/Center for Devices and Radiological Health Ulrik Wisløff Professor: Faculty of Medicine, Norwegian University of Science and Technology  Innovating at Scale: John Mattison, MD CMIO and Assistant Medical Director, Kaiser Permanente</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 09:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-1/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, October 8th, I attended day 1 of the Singularity University Exponential Medicine Conference in San Diegoat the amazing Hotel Del Coronado.
The event was organized mainly by Will Weisman and the incomparable Daniel Kraft, MD (whom I met last year at the London Stock Exchange), both from Singularity University.
The Conference was fully packed with activities. Morning activities started at 7am and included Yoga, Meditation, Art, and Beach Run. Evening activities changed every day, and included things like Team Collaboration &amp;amp; Innovation Games, Gadget &amp;amp; S’mores Bar, Music &amp;amp; Magic at the Bar, UnConference, or Silent Disco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last day in San Francisco: ART</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/last-day-in-san-francisco-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 22:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/last-day-in-san-francisco-art/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, September 17, was my last day in San Francisco, and the only one I had with some spare time.
After breakfast, I went to but some gifts from Japan Town and then headed to Union Square, for the Korean Day (Chuseok) culture festival.
Then I went to the Yerba Buena Center for the Arts to check out Tom Sachs _Space Program: Europa_. As I feared, after the failure of _Sony Outsider,_ Tom Sachs obsession with demonstrating his hand-made &amp;ldquo;bricolage style&amp;rdquo; continues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I won the Anti-Patents Policy Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/i-won-the-anti-patents-policy-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 02:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/i-won-the-anti-patents-policy-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>On September 13, Mind the Bridge hosted a policy hackathon sponsored by Dell at the MTB Innovation Center in San Francisco. The Dell PolicyHack™ brought together entrepreneurs and U.S./EU policy experts to solve policy challenges. The goal is to productively brainstorm and to provide top-line thinking that can inspire and serve as basis to develop and implement full policies.
My team was formed by:
 Sara R. Klucking (Section Chief, Innovation &amp;amp; Programs, Office of Science and Technology Cooperation, US Department of State) Bogdan Ceobanu (Policy Officer, Startups &amp;amp; Innovation, European Commission) David Hodgson (CEO, Hummingbird Labs) me  The five teams had 75 minutes to come up with a policy solution to issue areas that impact entrepreneurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking to Prof. Church about machine learning applied to genomic research</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/talking-to-prof.-church-about-machine-learning-applied-to-genomic-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 12:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/talking-to-prof.-church-about-machine-learning-applied-to-genomic-research/</guid>
      <description>During my flight to Boston I read “Regenesis”, the interesting genomic science book by Professor George Church, which was a gift from my friend Dr. Raminderpal Singh.
On Wednesday evening I had a very interesting conversation in Boston with both of them. Neither of them needs an introduction in the genomics world, but for those of you outside the field:
 Raminder is Vice-president at Eagle Genomics and Advisor at Kanteron Systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s pretend none of this ever happened</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 10:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</guid>
      <description>Walking towards my London Shoreditch office
to meet the Swiss investor and his impeccable suit,
leaving the City bankers’s coffee-holding fast pace behind,
I notice the absence nobody seems to
Where did he go?
His sleeping sack and pillow still on the sidewalk
as annoyingly positioned in the corner as always
But he’s gone
.
I wonder and I worry
his failing body, almost as absent as his lost gaze</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Big Bang Data” and “Tintin” exhibitions at Somerset House, London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/01/big-bang-data-and-tintin-exhibitions-at-somerset-house-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 18:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/01/big-bang-data-and-tintin-exhibitions-at-somerset-house-london/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we went to see a couple exhibitions at Somerset House, in London.
The first exhibition we saw was “TINTIN: Hergé`s Masterpiece”. Basic but obviously appealing, it was too crowded to be enjoyable.
The second one was “Big Bang Data”.
While undoubtedly interesting, especially for someone who works in, teaches, and loves bid data and technology like myself, to me the most interesting aspect of this exhibition is that everyone who was there had already experienced the subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I stood up against a terrorist in a German train</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/i-stood-up-against-a-terrorist-in-a-german-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 12:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/i-stood-up-against-a-terrorist-in-a-german-train/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, after spending the day at a tradeshow in Düsseldorf, on my way by train to the hotel in Mülheim, I stopped in the town of Duisburg, which was on my way, because I heard they were setting up a Christmas market. The market was indeed being set up, but it was still closed, so I decided to go back to the station. To avoid the sprinkling rain I took the 901 tram at König-Heinrich Platz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reset the net</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning quantum computer programming</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/learning-quantum-computer-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 11:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/learning-quantum-computer-programming/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I started learning and experimenting with quantum computing programming. Its not easy to express the fun and excitement that experience brought me, but Ill try:
Programming a quantum computer is different than programming a binary (0 and 1) &amp;ldquo;digital&amp;rdquo; computer. To program a quantum system, you have to map a problem into a search for the “lowest point&amp;rdquo; in a very large pool of options, which corresponds to the best possible outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barack and Michelle Obama congratulate us on our wedding</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/11/barack-and-michelle-obama-congratulate-us-on-our-wedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 10:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/11/barack-and-michelle-obama-congratulate-us-on-our-wedding/</guid>
      <description>A couple days ago, when we returned home from the SVA Theatre at the School of Visual Arts, where we were invited to attend the screeningof selected videosby winners and finalists from the 2013 Los Angeles Music Video Festival(and an interesting panel discussion with Bob Giraldi, Christopher Walters, Steven Gottlieb, Scott Reich, August Schram, and others), we found this in our mailbox:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate cowardice, political hypocrisy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/corporate-cowardice-political-hypocrisy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 15:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/corporate-cowardice-political-hypocrisy/</guid>
      <description>On July 25 I was asked by someone at IBM to write an article about the use of the cloud in healthcare:
 I’d like to offer you the opportunity to author an article which we would look to promote across all of our social properties, other external communications as well as our paid media sponsorships, i.e. blogs.
 I was given suggestions on article length, topic, and keywords, but freedom to write whatever I wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am requested to take a link down and... Streisand effect!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 01:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</guid>
      <description>Today I received this email (it was in Spanish, I have translated it into English because that is the main language of this blog, and in order to give this issue the international coverage that it deserves – sorry for any translation mistake since I am not a lawyer and he writes like an old-fashioned one trying to sound intimidating; here is the original):
 Mr. Cortell:
Currently I am suing Greg Prévôt in the Courts of Barcelona, author of a defamatory site which infringes upon my honor, whose link appears in which you administer, at the following address:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And this is how the movie industry chokes itself</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/and-this-is-how-the-movie-industry-chokes-itself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 16:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/and-this-is-how-the-movie-industry-chokes-itself/</guid>
      <description>On May 13th, on my way to a friends apartment, we stumbled upon the set of Ben Stillers new movie right outside the 125th St. subway exit. They were filming in the middle of the street. What struck me the most was that one of the façades of the building had been completely redone (cast, cement, wood, paint&amp;hellip; it looked absolutely real and solid) for the film.
Really? No building façade will do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art or war?</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/04/art-or-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 16:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/04/art-or-war/</guid>
      <description>In the TV show Britain`s Got Talent, Hungarian shadow-theatre company Attraction shows with beauty the horror of war.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My gift, goodbye or new beginning</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/my-gift-goodbye-or-new-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 19:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/my-gift-goodbye-or-new-beginning/</guid>
      <description>If the world ends today, this is my goodbye soundtrack gift to you.
If it doesn`t, tomorrow it will be the soundtrack of a waterfall, my new beginning gift to you.
In any case, the first composition that I ever share with the world (&amp;ldquo;Waterfall in the winter&amp;rdquo;). Straight from my open heart. Enjoy. Peace. Love. Happiness.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After hurricane Sandy in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 20:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>From tilted posts to trees completely gone, after hurricane Sandy there were many signs of destruction around New York.
I had to stay at Stepahnie`s apartment (thank you again!) until Monday, because my building remained without power. And even after the power returned, the telephone and internet took two more days.
Some people were not so lucky, with all hotels fully booked, and had to stay at home for days without power or water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instead of Halloween party</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/instead-of-halloween-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 15:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/instead-of-halloween-party/</guid>
      <description>I`m still stuck in Baltimore, but it seems I will be able to return to NY late tonight, arrivingtomorrow morningafternoon, the day after Halloween (which reaches amazing levels, like Barbie special edition dolls).
So, instead of going to the Village Halloween parade(which has been cancelled for the first time in 39 years), or anyof the Halloween parties I was invited to (the New Museum and Cara`s parties have also been cancelled), and wear the cool and simple MineCraft Creeper costume Cory Doctorow twitted(from Comic Con NY):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>319 Scholes art opening of &amp;quot;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 12:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I went to 319 Scholes to attend the art opening of &amp;ldquo;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;rdquo;.
Beyond the anecdotal post/pre hispter crowd, the exhibition itself is a sad celebration of noise. Which, in itself is as valid, or invalid, as any other starting point in the endless debate about art (more so in regards with contemporary, electronic, net, etc).
But it is its legitimization attempt, with research project, curator, catalogue, and international tour, which brings the debate to a whole different level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It`s October and all I want is you</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 22:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</guid>
      <description>Lying on the carpet, poetry book and pencil in hand, U2 in the background.
October
 October
And the trees are stripped bare
Of all they wear
What do I care
October
And kingdoms rise
And kingdoms fall
But you go on&amp;hellip;and on&amp;hellip;
 So many literal meanings: the fear of wearing-out (The Edge was considering leaving the band like his brother did before they were even called U2), the false sense of security arising from self-defeat (&amp;ldquo;What do I care&amp;rdquo;), moving on after a loss (both Bono and Larry had just lost their mothers), the high hopes and expectations arising from new democracies in Eastern Europe only to become despair and dissapointment, and eventually resilience, surviving, going on&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round table at NYCBA about Campaign Reform</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/round-table-at-nycba-about-campaign-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 13:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/round-table-at-nycba-about-campaign-reform/</guid>
      <description>September 5th (I know, I have really fallen behind my posts; bear with me, there is just too much going on to keep up) I attended a very interesting and enlightening round table at the New York City Bar Associationtitled &amp;ldquo;How Will Recent Developments in the Law Influence the 2012 Elections&amp;rdquo;?
Moderated by Nan Aron (lecturer, author, and President of Alliance for Justice), the panel consisted of:
 Angelo Falcón: President and Founder of the National Institute for Latino Policy Keesha Gaskins: Senior Counsel in the Brennan Center`s Democracy Program Lawrence Lessig: Professor of Law at Harvard University (and much more) John Samples: Director of the Cato Institute Center for Representative Government  The discussion was quite interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft, derivative works, parodies...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 10:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</guid>
      <description>Hugo sends me thisamazing song/video made in Minecraft. Of course, that leads to 10more, 14more&amp;hellip; there are so many!
When you make the tools available to the people, and allow them to create (in this case under the safe harbor of &amp;ldquo;parody&amp;rdquo;) wonderful things happen. Its NOT all about the money, profit, control... Its about imagination, art, creativity, culture. Thats how it happens: copying, re-using, mixing, adjusting, modifying... thats what creativity is really about (or did you think it was about &amp;ldquo;inventing&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;making unheard of things out of thin air&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multidimensional matrix of epistemology</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/a-multidimensional-matrix-of-epistemology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 09:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/a-multidimensional-matrix-of-epistemology/</guid>
      <description>I have no clue about physics or philosophy. But just like, when thinking theoretical physics, I cant help but reach the conclusion that time is a form of energy, when I think of epistemology, I cant help but to think of it in a multidimensional matrix, of which we can usually only grasp part, because the interconnexions we trace are linear an unidirectional.
It`s a well known fact that our brain is not built to comprehend reality, but &amp;ldquo;to make sense&amp;rdquo; of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My art projects and pictures</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/my-art-projects-and-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 10:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/my-art-projects-and-pictures/</guid>
      <description>For a few years I have accumulated art projects and pictures, in that oh-so-common delusion &amp;ldquo;one day I will start working on this and&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
Well, reality, resource constraints, day-to-day life&amp;hellip; are all excuses not to take ones passion and live it. So I am going to live it. How? I dont know. But the first step is to share, and to make accessible, my plans, ideas, and projects.
So HERE ARE MY ART PROJECTS (tumblr), and HERE ARE MY PHOTOGRAPHS (500px).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I beat Watson at Jeopardy (more or less)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 18:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in my previous post, at IBM Innovation Center in Chicago they have a Watson(more info here) interactive kiosk with which to play an interactive game of Jeopardy. In case you have been living in a cave for the past few months, Watson beatJeopardy human champions on live TV, the significanceof which can not be overstated.
Now, remember: this is a &amp;ldquo;small version&amp;rdquo; of Watson, and a &amp;ldquo;self-contained&amp;rdquo; version of Jeopardy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYPL support and citizen budget involvement</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/nypl-support-and-citizen-budget-involvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 12:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/nypl-support-and-citizen-budget-involvement/</guid>
      <description>After supporting the NYPL efforts to fight back budget cuts, I have received a lovely message of thanks from Christine C. Quinn (Speaker, NYC Council), along with a very nice suggestion:
 Dear New Yorker, Many thanks for your email expressing your support for our city`s libraries. [&amp;hellip;]
We cant do it alone, though, and I hope youll consider signing up for Council &amp;ldquo;enews&amp;rdquo;. These issue-based e-mail updates are a great way for us to stay connected and engaged with you and other New Yorkers about the budget, healthcare, and other important issues affecting our city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts about the 15M</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/thoughts-about-the-15m/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 13:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/thoughts-about-the-15m/</guid>
      <description>May 15th I went to the #15M demosntration in Malaga (Spain). As I was by myself, and to document and support &amp;ldquo;the cause&amp;rdquo;, I took my camerca and zig-zagged thourgh the crowd, in a kind of amateur sociological analysis of the most interesting social movement in these turbulent times. Here are some not-so-random thoughts:
 While no particular spacial organization can be detected in the demonstration, the group dynamics and power hierarchy (even if perceived representation power) applied their invisible forces once more to take the radicals (or most outspoken at least) to march in the front line, families in the middle, and party goers and curious at the back Most &amp;ldquo;organizers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;speakers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;banner-holders and support van drivers&amp;rdquo; were foreign (mainly Argentinians) Although supposedly devoid of political affiliation, the only ones showing political signs were those without direct political representation in the form of &amp;ldquo;their own party&amp;rdquo; (anarchist, republicans, etc) While there was no &amp;ldquo;organized plan of action&amp;rdquo; (I wonder if the &amp;ldquo;assemblies&amp;rdquo; could get to one without some sort of non-hierarchical order and/or structure), the #cazerolada and #lacaixaesmordor seem to channel the discontempt towards the direct real cause (superficial, first and most apparent, but not necessarily the most important) of the dire social tensions of today: banks and the financial system&amp;hellip; although how about the political system that allowed that to happen (from corruption to &amp;ldquo;democratic&amp;rdquo; representation)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC anarchist book fair</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/nyc-anarchist-book-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 13:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/nyc-anarchist-book-fair/</guid>
      <description>Since I could not get a hold of tickts for New Museum`s Seven on Seven, I decided to make the most out of my day yesterday (defying my cold), so I even had time to visit the NYC anarchist book fair, at Judson Church (Washington Square).
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5731668030633382577]
I wish I had had more time to devote to exploring all the literature (great and aweful) on display. But at least I had time to notice:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I admire these criminals</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-admire-these-criminals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 15:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-admire-these-criminals/</guid>
      <description>In Spain, the conservative PP government is planning to make &amp;ldquo;passive resistance&amp;rdquo; a crime(as well as organizing demonstrations using internet technologies).
I have these 4 criminals` magnetic puppets on my fridge. 2 were outlawed (and had to flee) by German Nazis. 1 had to flee Spanish dictatorship because he was a Communist. And the other one was thrown in jail by British occupation forces for &amp;ldquo;passive resistance&amp;rdquo;.
 I will not let anyone walk through my mind with their dirty feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The price of standing up for your rights: Opt-Out at Atlanta`s airport scanner</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-price-of-standing-up-for-your-rights-opt-out-at-atlantas-airport-scanner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 14:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-price-of-standing-up-for-your-rights-opt-out-at-atlantas-airport-scanner/</guid>
      <description>Atlanta`s Hartsfield airport has been having one of those uselessscanners that show passengers naked for a while now. But the last time I was there, they were being tested, and most passengers did not go through them. Today, though, as I approached the security line, I saw that next to every metal detector, there was one of those scanners. &amp;ldquo;Wow, this is getting worse&amp;rdquo;, I thought, while seeing how almost everybody was going through the scanners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debt graph as main decoration in government office</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/debt-graph-as-main-decoration-in-government-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 20:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/debt-graph-as-main-decoration-in-government-office/</guid>
      <description>On Monday, I met the Chief Information Officer of a large US Government Administration in Washington DC.
His office was surprisingly small and functional compared to European &amp;ldquo;big government&amp;rdquo; offices. A nice reminder of how European bureaucracy and public sector spending in administration itself is burying us. But what caught my attention the most was the largest picture in the office: it was not Obama`s, a diploma, a family picture, a flag&amp;hellip; it was this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RePress: fight online censorship with a WP Plug-In</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/repress-fight-online-censorship-with-a-wp-plug-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 17:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/repress-fight-online-censorship-with-a-wp-plug-in/</guid>
      <description>I just installed RePress: This plug-in enables you to magically uncensor any website on the internet from your own WordPress installation. Why and How.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate MLK day with RX2008 mix</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/celebrate-mlk-day-with-rx2008-mix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 09:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/celebrate-mlk-day-with-rx2008-mix/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International teahouse office</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/international-teahouse-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 18:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/international-teahouse-office/</guid>
      <description>Pretty amazing: I am putting out fires with a customer in Colombia, with the help of an engineer in Japan, coordinated with the headquarters in Spain&amp;hellip; while sipping on a coconut white bubble tea at ArgoUnion Square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing private copies for moving to NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/preparing-private-copies-for-moving-to-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 16:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/preparing-private-copies-for-moving-to-ny/</guid>
      <description>In Spain we have a legal right called &amp;ldquo;private copy&amp;rdquo; by which anyone can make a copy (for non-commercial use) of their copyrighted content (movies, music, books, etc). To offset the supposed loss (many studies prove this &amp;ldquo;loss&amp;rdquo; to be a fallacy) we Spaniards pay the so-called &amp;ldquo;Digital canon&amp;rdquo;, a tax levied on blank media (CDs, HardDisks, printers, photocopiers, etc, etc) and managed by private monopolistic institutions called &amp;ldquo;collecting societies&amp;rdquo;, some run by supposed alcohol-consuming, whore-user, money-embezzler, tax-evading criminals (or so goes the accusations brought to a number of them by the Attorney General).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are charitable dinners and then charitable dinners</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/there-are-charitable-dinners-and-then-charitable-dinners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 10:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/there-are-charitable-dinners-and-then-charitable-dinners/</guid>
      <description>I hate charitable dinners where most (or almost all) of the money goes to caviar, tuxedos, valet parking and other hoopla.
Fortunately there are other charitable dinners, where you wont see any &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.escolar.net/MT/archives/2011/11/la-nueva-politica-de-igualdad.html&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.escolar.net/MT/archives/2011/11/la-nueva-politica-de-igualdad.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;PP mothers&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, like yesterdays organized by Didi, where people sit on the floor, eat off plastic plates, and enjoy Didis deliciously vegan cooking and sincere love, so just about all money collected goes to Calcuttas orphans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a movement!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-a-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 10:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-a-movement/</guid>
      <description>First things first: thanks to whomever thought I would be interested in joining MCAthrough RiseUp, BUT&amp;hellip;
 Don`t subscribe me to a list without my consent Don`t do so without at least letting me know who you are Don`t assume I might be interested in something because it sounds related to my interest Don`t align me with &amp;ldquo;scientific socialism&amp;rdquo; when I am a declared anarchist Don`t make me waste my time on a list where the first 20 or so messages are split between arguing troskist, marxist, rose of lenburguist, bujarinist, bakuninist, leninist, hotsiminist, guevarist, maoist, castrist&amp;hellip; and people who want to be taken off the list  So, thanks (and I show it by talking about your project here), but show a little respect for other people`s rights, please.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not so difficult (is it?)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/not-so-difficult-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 09:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/not-so-difficult-is-it/</guid>
      <description>In this cute decorative vinyl from chispum.com, the message says: &amp;ldquo;I want a boyfriend who only wants to sleep with me (and nobody else)&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>