<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 08:44:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spare time fun: protein structure analysis of mutations causing inheritable diseases</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/spare-time-fun-protein-structure-analysis-of-mutations-causing-inheritable-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 08:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/spare-time-fun-protein-structure-analysis-of-mutations-causing-inheritable-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Most people I know would not consider protein structure analysis of mutations causing inheritable diseases &amp;ldquo;spare time fun&amp;rdquo;. Then again, most people I know don`t think I am like most people they know.
This week I`m a &amp;ldquo;single-dad&amp;rdquo;, since my wife is traveling. So my spare time right now is almost non existent. Nevertheless, the thought of mutating a Proline into a Glycine at position 22 intrigued me, so I spent a few minutes simulating it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DHVF, participating in a collective art performance, and meetings in Oxford Science Park</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/dhvf-participating-in-a-collective-art-performance-and-meetings-in-oxford-science-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 19:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/dhvf-participating-in-a-collective-art-performance-and-meetings-in-oxford-science-park/</guid>
      <description>The last couple of weeks in October I went to Valencia to attend the Digital Health Venture Forum, where I received the Best Presentation Award.
After spending a few days with my family and my Spanish team, and participating in an art installation by the SuperFlex collective on the 25th, I returned to London.
October 27 I went to the beautiful Oxford Science Park to have a couple of business meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego day 4</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 16:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-4/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, October 11th, was day four, and last, at the Exponential Medicine Conference in San Diego.
Some of the talks I enjoyed the most:
Exponential Thinking &amp;amp; Future Predictions: Ray Kurzweil Co-founder &amp;amp; Chancellor, Singularity University
Exponential Entrepreneurship:
 Zayna Khayat, PhD Lead, MaRS Health and Director, MaRS EXCITE Stephanie Marrus, MBA Entrepreneurship Center Director, UCSF  Investing In The Future: Vinod Khosla Founder, Khosla Ventures
Visualizing the Future of Medical Education, from VR to the OR:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego day 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 14:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-3/</guid>
      <description>Monday, October 10th was day 3 at the Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego.
For me the highlights were:
Bold Innovation: Peter Diamandis, MD Co-Founder, Singularity University and Founder &amp;amp; Chair, XPRIZE
Redesigning Care: Tony Young, PhD FRCS National Clinical Director for Innovation, NHS England
Bakul Patel, MBA Associate Director of Digital Health, Food and Drug Administration/Center for Devices and Radiological Health
Getting the xMED Scrubs Photo on the Beach, with an awesome drone:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Award and Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego day 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/award-and-exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 14:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/award-and-exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-2/</guid>
      <description>Sunday, October 9th, was day two at Exponential Medicine Conference in San Diego.
Some of the highlights were:
From ‘Omics to Action
 Moira Gunn, PhD Host, NPR’s Biotech Nation Larry Smarr, PhD Professor, UCSD and Director, Calit2 George Poste, DVM PhD FRS Chief Scientist, Complex Adaptive Systems Initiative- Arizona State University  Mobile, Connected, Digital Health
 David Albert, MD Founder, AliveCor Stanley Shaw, MD PhD Co-Director, MGH Center for Assessment Technology &amp;amp; Continuous Health Bakul Patel, MBA Associate Director of Digital Health, Food and Drug Administration/Center for Devices and Radiological Health Ulrik Wisløff Professor: Faculty of Medicine, Norwegian University of Science and Technology  Innovating at Scale: John Mattison, MD CMIO and Assistant Medical Director, Kaiser Permanente</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 09:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-1/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, October 8th, I attended day 1 of the Singularity University Exponential Medicine Conference in San Diegoat the amazing Hotel Del Coronado.
The event was organized mainly by Will Weisman and the incomparable Daniel Kraft, MD (whom I met last year at the London Stock Exchange), both from Singularity University.
The Conference was fully packed with activities. Morning activities started at 7am and included Yoga, Meditation, Art, and Beach Run. Evening activities changed every day, and included things like Team Collaboration &amp;amp; Innovation Games, Gadget &amp;amp; S’mores Bar, Music &amp;amp; Magic at the Bar, UnConference, or Silent Disco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-designing a NASA interface</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/re-designing-a-nasa-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 14:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/re-designing-a-nasa-interface/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in many things. One of the main ones is technology. And within technology, software development to view telemetry data in different ways, within the same application.
Answering NASA’s call to help contribute to the exploration of the solar system, I got access to their next-generation mission control framework being developed at the NASA Ames Research Center in Silicon Valley being used for mission planning and operations in the lead up to the Resource Prospector mission, and at NASA`s Jet Propulsion Laboratory to view data from the Curiosity Rover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking to Prof. Church about machine learning applied to genomic research</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/talking-to-prof.-church-about-machine-learning-applied-to-genomic-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 12:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/talking-to-prof.-church-about-machine-learning-applied-to-genomic-research/</guid>
      <description>During my flight to Boston I read “Regenesis”, the interesting genomic science book by Professor George Church, which was a gift from my friend Dr. Raminderpal Singh.
On Wednesday evening I had a very interesting conversation in Boston with both of them. Neither of them needs an introduction in the genomics world, but for those of you outside the field:
 Raminder is Vice-president at Eagle Genomics and Advisor at Kanteron Systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Festival of Genomics Boston</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/festival-of-genomics-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 15:43:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/festival-of-genomics-boston/</guid>
      <description>June 28 and 29 I attended, along with my friend John Memarian, President &amp;amp; CCO of my company Kanteron Systems, the Festival of Genomics Boston, as a Microsoft Genomics Group partner.
Although the show was small, it was a great opportunity to network with industry and academic experts (from Harvard Professors to Illumina executives) and learn.
From scientific posters to the latest sequencing technologies, from robotic arms to genomics experiments in space, it was great #geekfun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to Microsoft Research Cambridge workshop: Computing in Cancer</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-microsoft-research-cambridge-workshop-computing-in-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 06:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-microsoft-research-cambridge-workshop-computing-in-cancer/</guid>
      <description>May 27 I was invited to participate in the “Computing in Cancer Workshop” organized by Microsoft Research in Cambridge.
It was a great opportunity to network, meet with colleagues and other researchers, and especially to learn a lot.
The fascinating lectures were:
 Antonio Criminisi (Principal Researcher, Microsoft Research): Machine Learning for Medical Image Analysis Jasmin Fisher (Senior Researcher, Microsoft Research): Virtual Models of Cancer Giles Maskell (President, Royal College of Radiologists): Current problems in diagnostic radiology Fiona Gilbert (Head of the Department of Radiology, University of Cambridge) Dennis Wang (Senior Bioinformatics Scientist, AstraZeneca): Predicting drug combinations and biomarkers of response: a crowd-sourced solution Florian Markowetz (University of Cambridge, CRUK Cambridge Institute): Quantifying patterns of tumour evolution Francesca Buffa (Associate Professor, Department of Oncology, University of Oxford): In-silico systems biology and functional genomics approaches to accelerate biomarker discovery Hoifung Poon (Researcher, Microsoft Research): Machine Reading for Cancer Panomics Raj Jena (Academic Consultant Clinical Oncologist, Cambridge University Hospitals): Computing for Radiation Oncology – from cell culture to the clinic Bertie Gottgens (Professor of Molecular Haematology, University of Cambridge): Defining Cell States and Regulatory Networks using Single Cell Genomics  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Oxford Alumni Weekend lectures</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/four-oxford-alumni-weekend-lectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 10:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/four-oxford-alumni-weekend-lectures/</guid>
      <description>[More pictures here]
Last Saturday I had the pleasure to attend Oxford’s Alumni Weekend with my son.
I knew he would not be the only teenager there, but I was surprised to see kids even younger than him accompanying their parents. The truth is that I wish I had brought him earlier. I’ll try to bring my daughter to the next one.
Besides the obvious networking opportunity, the true pleasure was to attend interesting lectures delivered by top academics, and to see my son actually interested in those lectures!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royal Society of Medicine 11th Medical Innovations Summit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/royal-society-of-medicine-11th-medical-innovations-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 14:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/royal-society-of-medicine-11th-medical-innovations-summit/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I attended the 11th Medical Innovations Summitheld at the Royal Society of Medicine.
Like everyone else, I usually attend these events because there is a chance you may get to actually listen to an interesting presenter, or learn about a true innovation. But I usually leave disappointed due to a number of reasons like too much hype and lack of substance, bad organisation, “innovations” that are not really innovations, or bad presenters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at MedTech London July 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/speaking-at-medtech-london-july-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 18:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/speaking-at-medtech-london-july-7/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday July 7th I was also invited, this time by Prof Tony Young (National Clinical Director for Innovation NHS England), to speak at the MedTech eventheld at University College London Partners.
The other three speakers also talked about different aspects of MedTech:
 Jim Dawton, Director Great Fridays “Disrupting Healthcare through Design” Henrietta Hughes, Regional Medical Director, NHS England ‘Innovation From the Frontline of Primary Care` Prof. Jo Martin, National Clinical Director for Pathology, ‘eCPD and More’  It was also another great event for networking, with over 100 people there, all related to MedTech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Kings College London July 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/speaking-at-kings-college-london-july-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 17:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/speaking-at-kings-college-london-july-7/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday July 7th, I was invited to participate in a round table at the &amp;ldquo;Annual Networking Conference on Healthcare Efficiency through Technology: BIG DATA and Clinical Genomics&amp;rdquo; event.
It was a pleasure and an honor to share the stage and discuss the state of Clinical Genomics with speakers as distinguished as Prof. Tim Hubbard, Head of Bioinformatics (Genomics England); Dr Johnny Marshall, Director of Policy (NHS Confederation); or my friend Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCL MechEng Party</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/ucl-mecheng-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 15:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/ucl-mecheng-party/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Mykal invited me to the University College London’s Mechanical Engineering Summer Session at Student Central.
It was a blast. A geek blast. Many featured projects, such as giant drone, hydrogen racing car prototype, alternative transportation infrastructure, robotic fish, or improved artificial heart valve design, along with entertainment: giant Scalextric racing, giant jinga, FIFA 15 tournament, impact simulators, pool, and a live concert by Cable Street Collective.
[Note: Congratulations on launching the UK’s first fully Open Access university press!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to participate in a round table about Healthcare Technology at King`s College</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/invited-to-participate-in-a-round-table-about-healthcare-technology-at-kings-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 18:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/invited-to-participate-in-a-round-table-about-healthcare-technology-at-kings-college/</guid>
      <description>I have been invited to participate in a round table about Healthcare Technology Integration at King`s College(London), July 7 at 2:00pm, Great Hall, Strand Campus.
Mark your calendars, and see you there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innomedyx, one of the companies I co-founded, establishes the Clinical Innovation Center at the Polytechnic University of Valencia</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/07/innomedyx-one-of-the-companies-i-co-founded-establishes-the-clinical-innovation-center-at-the-polytechnic-university-of-valencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 09:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/07/innomedyx-one-of-the-companies-i-co-founded-establishes-the-clinical-innovation-center-at-the-polytechnic-university-of-valencia/</guid>
      <description>Innomedyx(Twitter, LinkedIn, FaceBook), a company I`m a co-founder of, has established the Clinical Innovation Center at the Polytechnic University of Valencia(Spain), the best BioTechnology University in Spain according to Spanish newspaper El Mundo.photo © UPVThe Dean of the Polytechnic University of Valencia (UPV), Francisco Mora, and the general director of Innomedyx Knowledge in Action, Rosa Valenzuela, signed a partnership agreement that formalizes the chair of Clinical Innovation company on July 1st.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking at the CUNY President`s office</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/networking-at-the-cuny-presidents-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 19:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/networking-at-the-cuny-presidents-office/</guid>
      <description>On May 6th, having just returned from quick trips to Cleveland and Atlanta, I attended with my wife the round table debate &amp;ldquo;Curiosity, Understanding, and Utility: Science and the Creative Economy&amp;rdquo; held at the City University of New York Graduate Center`s Proshansky Auditorium.
William Bialek, director of the Graduate Center`s Initiative for the Theoretical Sciences, moderated a discussion with Jennifer Tour Chayes, distinguished scientist and managing director of Microsoft Research New England and Microsoft Research New York City; Fernando Pereira, research at Google; and Chris Wiggins, chief data scientist at the New York Times and faculty member in the Department of Applied Mathematics and Applied Physics at Columbia University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video for my class at the Open University of Catalonia</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/video-for-my-class-at-the-open-university-of-catalonia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 01:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/video-for-my-class-at-the-open-university-of-catalonia/</guid>
      <description>Since I was in Barcelona last April, I took the opportunity to shoot this video (&amp;ldquo;Change in the medical imaging computational paradigm&amp;rdquo;) as an introduction to the classes I teach (&amp;ldquo;Clinical innovation in networked medical imaging&amp;rdquo;) at the Telemedicine Master`s Degree, Open University of Catalonia:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In SPain in April 2014</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/in-spain-in-april-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 01:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/in-spain-in-april-2014/</guid>
      <description>April 8 to 17 I travelled to Valencia and Barcelona (Spain).
In Barcelona I participated in the II Emergence Forum by Transbio Sudoe, a gathering of academics, companies &amp;amp; technological platforms from Spain, France, Portugal with the objective of setting up collaborative projects. I gave a lecture and participated in an expert panel.
The event allowed me to meet very interesting people, and visiting the Barcelona Supercomputing Center(with its Mare Nostrum supercomputer, in the most amazing set-up you could even imagine) and the Barcelona Scientific Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossing the border for a genetic test</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/04/crossing-the-border-for-a-genetic-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 13:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/04/crossing-the-border-for-a-genetic-test/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, as part of an unusual birthday gift, my fiancé and I signed up to get our genetic test.
So we ordered the test kit online, and when we entered the state (NY), a big warning told us that according to state laws, we could not produce or mail the samples back to their labs from New York. WTF?! OK, whatever. As if a nonsensical law did not have many ways around it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I beat Watson at Jeopardy (more or less)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 18:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in my previous post, at IBM Innovation Center in Chicago they have a Watson(more info here) interactive kiosk with which to play an interactive game of Jeopardy. In case you have been living in a cave for the past few months, Watson beatJeopardy human champions on live TV, the significanceof which can not be overstated.
Now, remember: this is a &amp;ldquo;small version&amp;rdquo; of Watson, and a &amp;ldquo;self-contained&amp;rdquo; version of Jeopardy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The danger of graphs and cold data</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</guid>
      <description>After posting graphs and cold data (quite ilustrative, I believe), and the discussion it has generated (people, why don`t you use the &amp;ldquo;comment&amp;rdquo; instead all the other unstructured methods you are using?), please let me write a caveat about graphs and cold data.
In my high-tech gym, you have the option to have a lot of data collected, for your own, private and personal use. It seems like a great idea at first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autism news</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/autism-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 17:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/autism-news/</guid>
      <description>While generalizations are usually absurd and damaging (asking &amp;ldquo;What is it like to be in a relationship with someone who has Asperger`s?&amp;rdquo; is almost as ridiculous a generalization as asking &amp;ldquo;What is it like to be in a relationship with a blonde?&amp;quot;) it is true that in general, working with an autistic person may be hard, living with one could be unbearable, and being one is&amp;hellip;
Some, let`s seek relief and help in knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you like Science, you will like...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/if-you-like-science-you-will-like.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 18:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/if-you-like-science-you-will-like.../</guid>
      <description>Source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tragedy of probability ignorance</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-tragedy-of-probability-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 13:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-tragedy-of-probability-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>When a M. Phil. from Cambridge, A.B. from Harvard, and M.D. from UCal writes an articleinsisting on a probabilistic fallacy, a trap where, in one way or another, many have fallen (from Eccles to Nagel), and this article is echoed in many sites (such as BoingBoing) and an infographicis made and becomes staff pick at visual.ly&amp;hellip; then you know ignorance is everywhere and very dangerous.
Read the article, then read Roy Weatherford`s &amp;ldquo;Philosophical foundations of probability theory&amp;rdquo; (or maybe something simpler), and once you grasp the concept of &amp;ldquo;a priori theories of probability&amp;rdquo;, laugh at those who think each one of us is a miracle&amp;hellip; we all are, but not because the probability of us being born is extremely small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excellent lectures and conferences online</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/excellent-lectures-and-conferences-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 12:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/excellent-lectures-and-conferences-online/</guid>
      <description>We all know TED. But there is a lot of information and academic material freely available online. Luckily that material is growing (education and science have always been areas which, unlike what copyrights zealots might want you to think, have grown thanks to sharing knowledge).
Some examples that I have found amazing:
– Integrative Biology, UCBerkley (English)
– Videosfrom Nobel lectures at Gustavus Adolphus College (English)
– Lectureson current neuroscience issues by Professor Francisco Rubia (Spanish)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>