<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technolust on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/technolust/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technolust on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 08:45:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/technolust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool online presentations with free software</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/05/cool-online-presentations-with-free-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 08:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/05/cool-online-presentations-with-free-software/</guid>
      <description>It has been a while since I wrote a tutorial to Share The Wealth, so it’s about time I shared some practical (if basic) knowledge beyond reposting a link.
For years I have had a pet project in the backburner: I wanted to create presentations without the need of dedicated software, commercial (like PowerPoint or Keynote), or free (like LibreOffice or OpenOffice). That way I could avoid bringing my computer to a lecture, and not worry about what computer system would be available in the auditorium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting the London Design Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/visiting-the-london-design-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 08:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/visiting-the-london-design-museum/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I visited the Design Museum(&amp;ldquo;The world`s leading museum devoted to contemporary design in every form from architecture and fashion to graphics, product and industrial design&amp;rdquo;) in its spectacular new location on High Street Kensington (London), with my son.
The #newdesignmuseum opened its doors in its new location only 5 days ago. The building and renovation are great, and in a nice location: on the edge of Holland Park, with the added bonus of being near the Kyoto Garden, Muji, and not far from the Serpentine Gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Award and Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego day 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/award-and-exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 14:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/award-and-exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-2/</guid>
      <description>Sunday, October 9th, was day two at Exponential Medicine Conference in San Diego.
Some of the highlights were:
From ‘Omics to Action
 Moira Gunn, PhD Host, NPR’s Biotech Nation Larry Smarr, PhD Professor, UCSD and Director, Calit2 George Poste, DVM PhD FRS Chief Scientist, Complex Adaptive Systems Initiative- Arizona State University  Mobile, Connected, Digital Health
 David Albert, MD Founder, AliveCor Stanley Shaw, MD PhD Co-Director, MGH Center for Assessment Technology &amp;amp; Continuous Health Bakul Patel, MBA Associate Director of Digital Health, Food and Drug Administration/Center for Devices and Radiological Health Ulrik Wisløff Professor: Faculty of Medicine, Norwegian University of Science and Technology  Innovating at Scale: John Mattison, MD CMIO and Assistant Medical Director, Kaiser Permanente</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-designing a NASA interface</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/re-designing-a-nasa-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 14:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/re-designing-a-nasa-interface/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in many things. One of the main ones is technology. And within technology, software development to view telemetry data in different ways, within the same application.
Answering NASA’s call to help contribute to the exploration of the solar system, I got access to their next-generation mission control framework being developed at the NASA Ames Research Center in Silicon Valley being used for mission planning and operations in the lead up to the Resource Prospector mission, and at NASA`s Jet Propulsion Laboratory to view data from the Curiosity Rover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking to Prof. Church about machine learning applied to genomic research</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/talking-to-prof.-church-about-machine-learning-applied-to-genomic-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 12:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/talking-to-prof.-church-about-machine-learning-applied-to-genomic-research/</guid>
      <description>During my flight to Boston I read “Regenesis”, the interesting genomic science book by Professor George Church, which was a gift from my friend Dr. Raminderpal Singh.
On Wednesday evening I had a very interesting conversation in Boston with both of them. Neither of them needs an introduction in the genomics world, but for those of you outside the field:
 Raminder is Vice-president at Eagle Genomics and Advisor at Kanteron Systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Festival of Genomics Boston</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/festival-of-genomics-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 15:43:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/festival-of-genomics-boston/</guid>
      <description>June 28 and 29 I attended, along with my friend John Memarian, President &amp;amp; CCO of my company Kanteron Systems, the Festival of Genomics Boston, as a Microsoft Genomics Group partner.
Although the show was small, it was a great opportunity to network with industry and academic experts (from Harvard Professors to Illumina executives) and learn.
From scientific posters to the latest sequencing technologies, from robotic arms to genomics experiments in space, it was great #geekfun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Father’s Day gift: building a Picade with my son</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/ultimate-fathers-day-gift-building-a-picade-with-my-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 13:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/ultimate-fathers-day-gift-building-a-picade-with-my-son/</guid>
      <description>For Father’s Day (we live in London, so we celebrate it today, unlike in Spain which is March 19) my wife gave me the “Ultimate Father`s Day” gift, from TechCamp UK. [Thank you, love!]
It consisted of a workshop with other father-son / father-daughter “teams”, held at the Iron Yard (The Leathermarket – London), where we built a desktop arcade machine in 5 hours (including lunch break), following the directions from Tom and Tom, using the Picadeset, setting up and using the Raspberry Pi, custom OS, emulators, ROMs, loudspeakers, power supply, LCD screen, etc:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to InfoSecurity Europe</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-infosecurity-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 15:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-infosecurity-europe/</guid>
      <description>Today I was invited to attend InfoSecurity Europe, Europe`s largest Information Security industry event.
As always, it was interesting to have a chance to catch up with this rapidly moving field, and a great opportunity to chat with old friends.
Apart from gimmicks (VR everywhere, car racing and helicopter simulators, giant robots, etc), swag (all kinds of Star Wars and other Sci-Fi related giveaways, from toys to t-shirts) and junk food (from candy to icecream to chips, the booths did not have healthy alternatives, although the food vendors did), the most interesting part of these events is always the talks, specifically the hands-on demos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited with my son to Intel Buzz videogame developer workshop</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-with-my-son-to-intel-buzz-videogame-developer-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 17:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-with-my-son-to-intel-buzz-videogame-developer-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Today I was invited, along with my son, who at 14 has been a videogame developer for years, to attend the Intel Buzz videogame developer workshop. It was not only a lot of fun, but WONDERFUL to attend with him!
Although a small event, it ended up being extremely interesting, with an area to try indie games and new technologies, and a long list of talks and panels, including one-on-ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A couple days in Zürich</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/a-couple-days-in-z%C3%BCrich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 10:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/a-couple-days-in-z%C3%BCrich/</guid>
      <description>I spent Wednesday evening and most of Thursday in Zürich.
On Wednesday I had dinner with some business partners; “business as usual”.
But on Thursday, after my business presentation to potential customers, I had the very rare and exclusive opportunity to visit one of the main data centers in Switzerland. Here are some impressive facts about them:
 they host 1/3 of Swiss banks data internet traffic = 40% of Switzerland’s internet traffic energy bill = 2 million Swiss Franks per annum 2 different energy suppliers from 2 different access points, with preferential oil supply in case of a failure (full reserves for 5 days for the generators) almost 50 telecoms suppliers, from many different countries, providing direct access for their customers worldwide RFIDs paired with 3D fingerprint scanners which measure the fingerprint but also the morphology, pulse and temperature separate isolated room to open packages, to minimize the risk of fire single person magnetic doors temperature, movement, and sound sensors double-gated entrance even to the parking lot!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working at Google Campus London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/working-at-google-campus-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 11:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/working-at-google-campus-london/</guid>
      <description>I have been working at the Google-TechHub Campus in Shoreditch (the “Silicon Roundabout”) London for a few weeks. It is really cool. In no particular order, here are some things I love about this place:
 A cafeteria (open to anyone) with terrace, foosball table, bitcoin machine, device bar (to test your developments in many different devices) and even a spacesuit! A small but well stocked library of tech books Very nice team, from security to reception, to admin, to social media… all of them Two levels of office space, one of them (supposedly) “quiet zone” Unlimited supplies of toast and tea, great wifi, and good scanners/printers A ton of areas to sit down and have a meeting, not just the “meeting rooms” Most importantly: the events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin and block chain event in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/02/bitcoin-and-block-chain-event-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/02/bitcoin-and-block-chain-event-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>On Monday, February 9, I attended a Bitcoin – Blockchain eventwith my wife at law firm Latham &amp;amp; Watkins in New York, organized by Hedgeable.

Over 100 bitcoin enthusiasts, investors, journalists, lawyers, and entrepreneurs networking over food and beverages, with demos from:
and a round table of Bitcoin innovation experts:
Since I have already started researching the application of the block chain technology for healthcare, it was quite a useful event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have invites for OnePlus and Ello</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/i-have-invites-for-oneplus-and-ello/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 13:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/i-have-invites-for-oneplus-and-ello/</guid>
      <description>If anyone wants an invite to buy a OnePlus, the best phone in the market, or to join Ello, the social network that does not sell your data, send me a message.
STW</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wearable review: Withings Pulse Ox, WS-30 WiFi scale, and Blood Pressure Monitor</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/wearable-review-withings-pulse-ox-ws-30-wifi-scale-and-blood-pressure-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 20:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/wearable-review-withings-pulse-ox-ws-30-wifi-scale-and-blood-pressure-monitor/</guid>
      <description>Due to the launch of the biosensors module for my company`s medical imaging and data solution a few days ago, the Withings company sent me a biosensor (wearable) Withings Pulse Ox, manometer BPM and WiFi WS-30 scale for testing and integration tests ahead of some national projects we are about to sign in London and Santiago de Chile.
All three came in luxury packaging, and were relatively easy to connect and set up, at least for a &amp;ldquo;tinkerer&amp;rdquo; (there are people who gets annoyed if I use &amp;ldquo;hacker&amp;rdquo; as a synonym, although it is) like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My new OnePlus One phone is amazing</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/my-new-oneplus-one-phone-is-amazing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 22:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/my-new-oneplus-one-phone-is-amazing/</guid>
      <description>I have just bought a OnePlusOne phone, and have been using it for a couple of days. Let me tell you: it`s AMAZING.
If you have never heard of the company, dont worry, youre not alone. But you should definitely check it out, because their phones are incredibly high quality, high specs, and low price (mine was $349). No catch:
 Qualcomm© Snapdragon™ 801 processor with 2.5GHz Quad-core CPUs Adreno 330 GPU, 578MHz 64 GB eMMC 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I was forced to hack into Schiphol Airport wifi</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/i-was-forced-to-hack-into-schiphol-airport-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 12:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/i-was-forced-to-hack-into-schiphol-airport-wifi/</guid>
      <description>A couple weeks ago I was at Schiphol Airport in Amsterdam. Of course, when I arrive in an airport with enough time ahead of my boarding, I look for a plug and wifi. Luckily Schiphol is an excellent airport, offering both. The only problem is that every time I clicked on the &amp;ldquo;Enjoy unlimited free wifi – Connect&amp;rdquo; button, I got an &amp;ldquo;Unknown error 0&amp;rdquo; message back.
 Don`t tell me &amp;ldquo;Enjoy unlimited free wifi&amp;rdquo; and then try to prevent me from accessing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning quantum computer programming</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/learning-quantum-computer-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 11:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/learning-quantum-computer-programming/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I started learning and experimenting with quantum computing programming. Its not easy to express the fun and excitement that experience brought me, but Ill try:
Programming a quantum computer is different than programming a binary (0 and 1) &amp;ldquo;digital&amp;rdquo; computer. To program a quantum system, you have to map a problem into a search for the “lowest point&amp;rdquo; in a very large pool of options, which corresponds to the best possible outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited by Google to the Google Cloud Platform presentation</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-by-google-to-the-google-cloud-platform-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-by-google-to-the-google-cloud-platform-presentation/</guid>
      <description>March 25 Google NY invited me to their Google Cloud Platformpresentation in their Chelsea offices, 8 blocks away from my apartment.
Besides the interesting new features (here are the videos), and the delicious and healthy lunch buffet, I networked quite a lot, and had a few laughs about the highest concentration of Google Glasses per person I have seen so far. One thing is clear: genomics, which is one of the main things my two companies deal with, and the cloud, are closely related, and they will be even more in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromecast &#43; Hola = Multimedia freedom</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/02/chromecast-hola-multimedia-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 18:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/02/chromecast-hola-multimedia-freedom/</guid>
      <description>How many times have you tried to access online media that was not available in your country? How many times have you gotten frustrated with proxy services?
How many times have you wished there was an easy way to wirelessly display online content on your TV without paying for expensive privative boxes?
Enter Hola.org+ ChromecastHola is a free browser extension used by 14 million people to access geographically restricted online media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the introduction of IBM Watson at WTC NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/invited-to-the-introduction-of-ibm-watson-at-wtc-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 13:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/invited-to-the-introduction-of-ibm-watson-at-wtc-ny/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday January 8th I was asked to hold a meeting regarding the potential involvement of my company (Kanteron Systems) in IBM’s Watson. It was a late night meeting, on the 54th floor of the still under construction World Trade Center. The reason why the meeting took place there is because the IBM team was finishing the set up of the next day’s Watson presentation.
What is Watson, you may ask?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with the robot (Roomba)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/08/playing-with-the-robot-roomba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 15:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/08/playing-with-the-robot-roomba/</guid>
      <description>We got great gifts for our wedding, but hands down, the best (ever!) is A ROBOT.
My mother-in-law got us a robot. Got that? How cool is that!?
And it is not to make her daughter’s life easier, because I am the one who vacuums at home. She did it because it is cool. Heck yeah it is!
So the Roombais nothing new. It has been around for a decade already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting NY tech companies</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/meeting-ny-tech-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 17:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/meeting-ny-tech-companies/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5879766487788118305]
Friday May 17th I took the day to meet some of the interesting tech companies present in New York. There are over 1,200 tech companies in NY(including CodeAcademy, KickStarter, Foursquare, MakerBot, ZocDoc, Guilt, AppNexus, Tumblr, Etsy, KickStarter, Automatic&amp;hellip; and mine!), most between the Flat Iron and SoHo areas of Manhattan (Silicon ALley). So I chose a few that, for one reason or another, I was interested in meeting and talk to their founders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look at the data, just look at it!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/look-at-the-data-just-look-at-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 14:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/look-at-the-data-just-look-at-it/</guid>
      <description>Carna botnet offers us this amazing 24 hour visualization of relative IPv4 utilization observed using ICMP Ping requests.
Look at the data, just look at it! Dont you see peoples sleeping patterns, internet usage patterns, eating schedule habit, cultural differences, urban influence, regional inequalities&amp;hellip;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two biggest Lytro pitfalls</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/two-biggest-lytro-pitfalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 11:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/two-biggest-lytro-pitfalls/</guid>
      <description>After playing with it for a while, beyond it limitations (light, format, movement&amp;hellip;) here are the two biggest pitfalls with the Lytro camera:
  It is still for Mac OSX only. They NEED to come out with Open Source / Free Software (both their software AND platform support for GNU/Linux).
  Picture library size and location. BIG unresolved issue.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I beat Watson at Jeopardy (more or less)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 18:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in my previous post, at IBM Innovation Center in Chicago they have a Watson(more info here) interactive kiosk with which to play an interactive game of Jeopardy. In case you have been living in a cave for the past few months, Watson beatJeopardy human champions on live TV, the significanceof which can not be overstated.
Now, remember: this is a &amp;ldquo;small version&amp;rdquo; of Watson, and a &amp;ldquo;self-contained&amp;rdquo; version of Jeopardy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Kagemu video</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/awesome-kagemu-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 21:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/awesome-kagemu-video/</guid>
      <description>Although I can not embed it (the author has disabled the option) this videoby Japanese performer and CGI artist Kagemu is really worth looking at. Enjoy. (Via Nebula).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with my new Lytro</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/playing-with-my-new-lytro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 18:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/playing-with-my-new-lytro/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I received my new Lytrocamera. Although it is an incredible technology, and allows things that were unthinkable until now, so far I am mixed.
Pros:
 Compact and discreet Extremely easy to use New ways of taking pictures Novelty Supercool &amp;ldquo;focus later&amp;rdquo;  Cons:
 You have to get used to a different way of thinking and framing a shot (square! and distance) Low performance under low light (although better than my crappy Samsung Galaxy IIS camera)  Check out this online gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A conversation with Walt Mossberg and Kara Swisher at NYU</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/a-conversation-with-walt-mossberg-and-kara-swisher-at-nyu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 11:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/a-conversation-with-walt-mossberg-and-kara-swisher-at-nyu/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday I went to New York University for a nice conversation in the Inside the Internet Garageseries, with journalists Walt Mossberg and Kara Swisher (AllThingsDigital, Wall Street Journal, etc).
Besides the very interesting bio/background overview of them that the interviewer did, here are some quotes that caught my attention.
Walt Mossberg:
 IT departments are the most regressive force in tech, blocking new tech adoption
The story goes that Larry Page asked Steve Jobs for advice, he said &amp;ldquo;Find the 5 things you do best, and focus on it&amp;rdquo;, which its what hes doing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The danger of graphs and cold data</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</guid>
      <description>After posting graphs and cold data (quite ilustrative, I believe), and the discussion it has generated (people, why don`t you use the &amp;ldquo;comment&amp;rdquo; instead all the other unstructured methods you are using?), please let me write a caveat about graphs and cold data.
In my high-tech gym, you have the option to have a lot of data collected, for your own, private and personal use. It seems like a great idea at first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newspaper map (with translations)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/newspaper-map-with-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 12:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/newspaper-map-with-translations/</guid>
      <description>Map + Newspapers + Translations = Simple and AWESOME!!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In 3D with Firefox`s new TILT inspector</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/in-3d-with-firefoxs-new-tilt-inspector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 12:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/in-3d-with-firefoxs-new-tilt-inspector/</guid>
      <description>Lego web design, anyone? 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with face.com face recognition technology</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/playing-with-face.com-face-recognition-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 17:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/playing-with-face.com-face-recognition-technology/</guid>
      <description>While I am preparing a loooooong post about technology and privacy (with a provocative twist, for a change 😈 ), I have decided to play with face.com‘s face recognition technology.
What do you think? On target (hint: no, not on target, I am not THAT old, and definitely I AM a male)? Scary (hint: only if we are unaware of these technologies and their uses)?&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real convergence</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/real-convergence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 05:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/real-convergence/</guid>
      <description>Reading RSS on my smartphone, click on a YouTube video, send it to the computer via Phone2Chrome&amp;hellip;
I read on a newspaper tablet version that TED is now on Netflix, turn on the Google TV Logitech Revue with Able Remote on my phone and start Netflix, adding TED to my Instant Que&amp;hellip;
Remember all that &amp;ldquo;convergence&amp;rdquo; talk?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better privacy through your browser</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/better-privacy-through-your-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 17:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/better-privacy-through-your-browser/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to improve your online privacy? Go ahead, install HTTPSand Collusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArtHack Exhibit closing party in Brooklyn</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 22:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday I went to the ArtHack Exhibitclosing party at 319 ScholesSt, Brooklyn (New York).
Located in an industrial complex in Brooklyn, at night, loooong two blocks from the subway, graffiti all over, small door&amp;hellip; that gave way to heaven: young (I was the oldest hacker in that space, but I did not feel that way) energetic happy people tinkering with technology and proudly showing their &amp;ldquo;toys&amp;rdquo; (hacks, mashups, creations, or whatever).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RePress: fight online censorship with a WP Plug-In</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/repress-fight-online-censorship-with-a-wp-plug-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 17:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/repress-fight-online-censorship-with-a-wp-plug-in/</guid>
      <description>I just installed RePress: This plug-in enables you to magically uncensor any website on the internet from your own WordPress installation. Why and How.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>