<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Proposals for Equality on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/proposals-for-equality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Proposals for Equality on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 16:08:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/proposals-for-equality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Very interesting insights from the UBS Forum 2017</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/very-interesting-insights-from-the-ubs-forum-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 16:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/very-interesting-insights-from-the-ubs-forum-2017/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Giles and Magda invited me to attend the annual UBS Forum at the beautiful Rosewood Hotel, one of those hotels in a renovated palace in the heart of London, with a resident dog.
Held in major financial cities across Europe, the UBS Forum is presented under the banner &amp;ldquo;sharper opinions – smarter decisions”, where UBS specialists and external experts provide insights on key topics. This years` speakers and topics were:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Revolution needs a Revolution</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 17:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went with my wife and son to visit the Victoria &amp;amp; Albert`s Museum exhibition You Say You Want a Revolution? Records and Rebels 1966-1970. The aim of the exhibition was quite clear:
 How have the finished and unfinished revolutions of the late 1960s changed the way we live today and think about the future?
 I was very much looking forward to visiting the exhibition. It is SO timely, and SO needed, I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last day in San Francisco: ART</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/last-day-in-san-francisco-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 22:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/last-day-in-san-francisco-art/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, September 17, was my last day in San Francisco, and the only one I had with some spare time.
After breakfast, I went to but some gifts from Japan Town and then headed to Union Square, for the Korean Day (Chuseok) culture festival.
Then I went to the Yerba Buena Center for the Arts to check out Tom Sachs _Space Program: Europa_. As I feared, after the failure of _Sony Outsider,_ Tom Sachs obsession with demonstrating his hand-made &amp;ldquo;bricolage style&amp;rdquo; continues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco, day 5</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/san-francisco-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 02:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/san-francisco-day-5/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday, September 14 I spent the whole day at K&amp;amp;L Gates, one of the largest law firms in the world, which has customers like Microsoft (the “Gates” in K&amp;amp;L Gates is for Bill Gates’ father), Amazon, etc.
It was a typical upscale law firm setup: expensive video conference equipment and giant screens (I liked their “rear projector and mirror” trick) in a high-rise building with impressive views, and some art, like the “flying dildos” in reception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the Amazon Web Services Summit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/invited-to-the-amazon-web-services-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 07:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/invited-to-the-amazon-web-services-summit/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday and Thursday, I was invited to attend the Amazon Web Services Summit in London’s Excel center.
Besides an exhibition area with many vendors (some of them already suppliers to my company) like NewRelic, DataDog, GitHub, Chef, Alscient, Teradici, DataPipe, Ruxit, CloudCheckr, Amazon Activate, Elastic, Redis, etc, all with their great swag (mostly t-shirts and stickers, but lots of giveaways, from drones to iWatches), the highlight was the conference sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s pretend none of this ever happened</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 10:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</guid>
      <description>Walking towards my London Shoreditch office
to meet the Swiss investor and his impeccable suit,
leaving the City bankers’s coffee-holding fast pace behind,
I notice the absence nobody seems to
Where did he go?
His sleeping sack and pillow still on the sidewalk
as annoyingly positioned in the corner as always
But he’s gone
.
I wonder and I worry
his failing body, almost as absent as his lost gaze</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I stood up against a terrorist in a German train</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/i-stood-up-against-a-terrorist-in-a-german-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 12:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/i-stood-up-against-a-terrorist-in-a-german-train/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, after spending the day at a tradeshow in Düsseldorf, on my way by train to the hotel in Mülheim, I stopped in the town of Duisburg, which was on my way, because I heard they were setting up a Christmas market. The market was indeed being set up, but it was still closed, so I decided to go back to the station. To avoid the sprinkling rain I took the 901 tram at König-Heinrich Platz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Million masks march</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/million-masks-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 14:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/million-masks-march/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday, coming back home from a meeting, I run into the Million Masks March. While I assume I agree with most of their anti-system protests (the truth is I did not bother to read them), I think their choice of Guy Fawkes as an &amp;ldquo;icon&amp;rdquo;, even if a graphical one as proposed by the comic/movie &amp;ldquo;V for Vendetta&amp;rdquo;, is a very stupid one. Just read about what that historical figure had in mind and judge for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My talk at the Circumvention Tech Festival, March 4th</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/my-talk-at-the-circumvention-tech-festival-march-4th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 23:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/my-talk-at-the-circumvention-tech-festival-march-4th/</guid>
      <description>This past winter I met Sandy and James from Open ITP in New York, and Pepe from Valencia. They were organizing the Circumvention Tech Festivalto be held in Las Naves, Valencia (Spain) March 1-6.
They invited me to give a talk, which was eventually scheduled for March 4th at 3pm. I titled the talk “When privacy does not mean the same to you and me”. It was meant to generate debate, to expose other people’s points of view, rather than to be a unidirectional speech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reset the net</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the love of basketball</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/for-the-love-of-basketball/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 17:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/for-the-love-of-basketball/</guid>
      <description>I have decided to join the Chelsea Recreation Center.
It`s right around the corner from our apartment, and for $150/year it has everything I need:
But mainly
Two days ago I went in for the first time.
I checked out a basketball from the office (the best basketball I have played with in my long career), and went straight to the court.
There were around a dozen kids (18 year olds, high school seniors) playing around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The key to the use of cloud in healthcare</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/the-key-to-the-use-of-cloud-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 12:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/the-key-to-the-use-of-cloud-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>In a single word: security.
By now there is no doubt about the advantages of the cloud: easy collaboration, scalability, ubiquity, sync, cost savings (21% on average, according to AFCOM 2011, 40% according to our own customers), rapid deployment, etc.
There is also no doubt about the need for a move to the cloud in healthcare: according to Enterprise Strategy Group, by 2015 an average of 665TB of data will be generated per hospital per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And this is how the movie industry chokes itself</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/and-this-is-how-the-movie-industry-chokes-itself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 16:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/and-this-is-how-the-movie-industry-chokes-itself/</guid>
      <description>On May 13th, on my way to a friends apartment, we stumbled upon the set of Ben Stillers new movie right outside the 125th St. subway exit. They were filming in the middle of the street. What struck me the most was that one of the façades of the building had been completely redone (cast, cement, wood, paint&amp;hellip; it looked absolutely real and solid) for the film.
Really? No building façade will do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After hurricane Sandy in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 20:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>From tilted posts to trees completely gone, after hurricane Sandy there were many signs of destruction around New York.
I had to stay at Stepahnie`s apartment (thank you again!) until Monday, because my building remained without power. And even after the power returned, the telephone and internet took two more days.
Some people were not so lucky, with all hotels fully booked, and had to stay at home for days without power or water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instead of Halloween party</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/instead-of-halloween-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 15:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/instead-of-halloween-party/</guid>
      <description>I`m still stuck in Baltimore, but it seems I will be able to return to NY late tonight, arrivingtomorrow morningafternoon, the day after Halloween (which reaches amazing levels, like Barbie special edition dolls).
So, instead of going to the Village Halloween parade(which has been cancelled for the first time in 39 years), or anyof the Halloween parties I was invited to (the New Museum and Cara`s parties have also been cancelled), and wear the cool and simple MineCraft Creeper costume Cory Doctorow twitted(from Comic Con NY):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Norse vs Inuit approach</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-norse-vs-inuit-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-norse-vs-inuit-approach/</guid>
      <description>The Norse vs Inuit approach
There are many seemingly &amp;ldquo;small events&amp;rdquo; in history to which we do not pay much attention, when actually they provide very important lessons. I always talk about historical examples of perfectly successful cooperatives and anarchist self government. But this time I want to comment on a very different historical event: the Norse attempt to colonize Greenland.
When the Norse tried to colonize Greenland, the Inuit already lived there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The longest war in US history</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-longest-war-in-us-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-longest-war-in-us-history/</guid>
      <description>Afghanistan already is the longest (official) war in US history.
In order to begin to understand that mess, as usual in modern history, we may have to go back to the end of World War II, when Pakistan`s colonial nominees, the &amp;ldquo;Taliban&amp;rdquo;, were sent to take over Afghanistan to give them a strategic edge over India in the war over Kashmir.
Today the Taliban and Pakistans ISI (Directorate for Inter-Service Intelligence) alliance are at the heart of why the USA is stuck in an endless war: the USA aligns, or so it would seem, much more with India in terms of values, policy, economy, etc, than with Pakistan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High culture might will numb you, how stay true? On &amp;quot;Graffiti&amp;quot; screening and panel at New Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 15:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I was invited to the New Musuem for the screening of &amp;ldquo;Graffiti – PostGraffiti&amp;rdquo; documentary and panel discussion.Your usual suspects were there. Besides the panelist (Pattie Astor, Fab Five Freddy, Lady Pink, and Lee Quinones), there were many old glories and a couple of aspiring bomber kids in the audience that I am sure were tagging walls late that night.
What started as a celebration, a remembrance, and a comunion, as the liturgy advanced ended up becoming a hurtful vindication and even a flat out purist attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It`s October and all I want is you</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 22:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</guid>
      <description>Lying on the carpet, poetry book and pencil in hand, U2 in the background.
October
 October
And the trees are stripped bare
Of all they wear
What do I care
October
And kingdoms rise
And kingdoms fall
But you go on&amp;hellip;and on&amp;hellip;
 So many literal meanings: the fear of wearing-out (The Edge was considering leaving the band like his brother did before they were even called U2), the false sense of security arising from self-defeat (&amp;ldquo;What do I care&amp;rdquo;), moving on after a loss (both Bono and Larry had just lost their mothers), the high hopes and expectations arising from new democracies in Eastern Europe only to become despair and dissapointment, and eventually resilience, surviving, going on&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for Sugar Man</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/searching-for-sugar-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2012 14:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/searching-for-sugar-man/</guid>
      <description>Last Sunday I went to see Searching for Sugar Manbio/docu/picat Lincoln Plaza Theaters.
 Two South Africans set out to discover what happened to their unlikely musical hero, the mysterious 1970s rock ‘n` roller, Rodriguez.
 While the movieis a very good one, and the story quite powerful (not only a human story about an incredible musiciancalled Rodriguez, better than Bob Dylan if you allow me the heresy), there are two aspects that go well beyond the typical in this kind of documentary:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round table at NYCBA about Campaign Reform</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/round-table-at-nycba-about-campaign-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 13:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/round-table-at-nycba-about-campaign-reform/</guid>
      <description>September 5th (I know, I have really fallen behind my posts; bear with me, there is just too much going on to keep up) I attended a very interesting and enlightening round table at the New York City Bar Associationtitled &amp;ldquo;How Will Recent Developments in the Law Influence the 2012 Elections&amp;rdquo;?
Moderated by Nan Aron (lecturer, author, and President of Alliance for Justice), the panel consisted of:
 Angelo Falcón: President and Founder of the National Institute for Latino Policy Keesha Gaskins: Senior Counsel in the Brennan Center`s Democracy Program Lawrence Lessig: Professor of Law at Harvard University (and much more) John Samples: Director of the Cato Institute Center for Representative Government  The discussion was quite interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft, derivative works, parodies...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 10:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</guid>
      <description>Hugo sends me thisamazing song/video made in Minecraft. Of course, that leads to 10more, 14more&amp;hellip; there are so many!
When you make the tools available to the people, and allow them to create (in this case under the safe harbor of &amp;ldquo;parody&amp;rdquo;) wonderful things happen. Its NOT all about the money, profit, control... Its about imagination, art, creativity, culture. Thats how it happens: copying, re-using, mixing, adjusting, modifying... thats what creativity is really about (or did you think it was about &amp;ldquo;inventing&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;making unheard of things out of thin air&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYPL support and citizen budget involvement</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/nypl-support-and-citizen-budget-involvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 12:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/nypl-support-and-citizen-budget-involvement/</guid>
      <description>After supporting the NYPL efforts to fight back budget cuts, I have received a lovely message of thanks from Christine C. Quinn (Speaker, NYC Council), along with a very nice suggestion:
 Dear New Yorker, Many thanks for your email expressing your support for our city`s libraries. [&amp;hellip;]
We cant do it alone, though, and I hope youll consider signing up for Council &amp;ldquo;enews&amp;rdquo;. These issue-based e-mail updates are a great way for us to stay connected and engaged with you and other New Yorkers about the budget, healthcare, and other important issues affecting our city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal action against Bankia and Rato</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/legal-action-against-bankia-and-rato/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 17:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/legal-action-against-bankia-and-rato/</guid>
      <description>The citizen platform #15MpaRato is preparing legal action to take Rodrigo Rato to court.
Today they started asking small Bankia stockholders to file an anonymous report, so it can be used in a lawsuit.
Here is their news release [ES]:
https://15mparato.wordpress.com/2012/05/29/accionesparato/
Here is their website:
https://15mparato.wordpress.com/2012/05/29/accionesparato/
Here is their twitter:
@15MpaRato
Hashtag:
#accionpaRato
If you know any Bankia stockholder, ask him/her to contact:
15mparato@gmail.com
Good luck!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts about the 15M</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/thoughts-about-the-15m/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 13:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/thoughts-about-the-15m/</guid>
      <description>May 15th I went to the #15M demosntration in Malaga (Spain). As I was by myself, and to document and support &amp;ldquo;the cause&amp;rdquo;, I took my camerca and zig-zagged thourgh the crowd, in a kind of amateur sociological analysis of the most interesting social movement in these turbulent times. Here are some not-so-random thoughts:
 While no particular spacial organization can be detected in the demonstration, the group dynamics and power hierarchy (even if perceived representation power) applied their invisible forces once more to take the radicals (or most outspoken at least) to march in the front line, families in the middle, and party goers and curious at the back Most &amp;ldquo;organizers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;speakers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;banner-holders and support van drivers&amp;rdquo; were foreign (mainly Argentinians) Although supposedly devoid of political affiliation, the only ones showing political signs were those without direct political representation in the form of &amp;ldquo;their own party&amp;rdquo; (anarchist, republicans, etc) While there was no &amp;ldquo;organized plan of action&amp;rdquo; (I wonder if the &amp;ldquo;assemblies&amp;rdquo; could get to one without some sort of non-hierarchical order and/or structure), the #cazerolada and #lacaixaesmordor seem to channel the discontempt towards the direct real cause (superficial, first and most apparent, but not necessarily the most important) of the dire social tensions of today: banks and the financial system&amp;hellip; although how about the political system that allowed that to happen (from corruption to &amp;ldquo;democratic&amp;rdquo; representation)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The danger of graphs and cold data</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</guid>
      <description>After posting graphs and cold data (quite ilustrative, I believe), and the discussion it has generated (people, why don`t you use the &amp;ldquo;comment&amp;rdquo; instead all the other unstructured methods you are using?), please let me write a caveat about graphs and cold data.
In my high-tech gym, you have the option to have a lot of data collected, for your own, private and personal use. It seems like a great idea at first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letting data talk</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/letting-data-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 18:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/letting-data-talk/</guid>
      <description>Government debt does not explain it all:Unemployment is, indeed, quite inapelable:And minimum wage:So, perhaps, taking all those (and the last &amp;ldquo;devastating evidence&amp;rdquo; one) graphs into account, French and German governments have tricked, via manipulative markets and rating agencies, ignorant technocrat Spain`s PP government into cutting social spending (like education and health, which in turn becomes productivity, and minimum wage and job stability, which promotes spending and growth) so we go deeper into the hole, and they take advantage of our excellent engineers at a low rate, while speculating with debt and making sure Spain does not become a strong competitor&amp;hellip;Don`t they realise that with a monarchy that &amp;ldquo;shoots itself in the foot trying to hunt elephants and hiding corruption and scandalous ties&amp;rdquo;, a media that is so self complacent and ass kissing that feels more like brothels, politicians so entrenched in the corrupt game that with two degrees of separation you could not find an honest Spaniard anymore, a starch church mingling in public affairs, and a population so absorbed by soccer, celebrities and fear, they do not need to do that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC anarchist book fair</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/nyc-anarchist-book-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 13:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/nyc-anarchist-book-fair/</guid>
      <description>Since I could not get a hold of tickts for New Museum`s Seven on Seven, I decided to make the most out of my day yesterday (defying my cold), so I even had time to visit the NYC anarchist book fair, at Judson Church (Washington Square).
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5731668030633382577]
I wish I had had more time to devote to exploring all the literature (great and aweful) on display. But at least I had time to notice:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newspaper map (with translations)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/newspaper-map-with-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 12:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/newspaper-map-with-translations/</guid>
      <description>Map + Newspapers + Translations = Simple and AWESOME!!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curators` thoughts</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/curators-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 00:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/curators-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>On September 28, 2011, Hou Hanru, Director of Exhibitions and Public Programs at the San Francisco Art Institute said on a lecture (Curator`s Perspective) in New York:
 I think the worst exhibition in the world is the exhibition that is organized like a book. We see this a lot, an exhibition that takes the artwork as an illustration of a concept. I think an exhibition is not necessary for this: frankly, it`s too expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infographic on the Hypocrisy in Hollywood</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/infographic-on-the-hypocrisy-in-hollywood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 01:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/infographic-on-the-hypocrisy-in-hollywood/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context in Art as Political Discussion: Amalia Pica`s Venn Diagrams</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/context-in-art-as-political-discussion-amalia-picas-venn-diagrams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 19:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/context-in-art-as-political-discussion-amalia-picas-venn-diagrams/</guid>
      <description>One of the multiple interesting pieces currently being exhibited at the New Museums &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://cortell.net/blog/2012/03/the-ungovernables-party-at-new-museum/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://cortell.net/blog/2012/03/the-ungovernables-party-at-new-museum/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;The Ungovernables&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; is Amalia Picas Venn Diagrams. The text under this piece says:
 During the period of dictatorship in Argentina in the 1970s, gatherings of citizens were closely monitored as they were considered a threat to the government. At the same time group theory and venn diagrams were banned from primary school programs as they could provide a model for subversive thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better privacy through your browser</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/better-privacy-through-your-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 17:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/better-privacy-through-your-browser/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to improve your online privacy? Go ahead, install HTTPSand Collusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debt graph as main decoration in government office</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/debt-graph-as-main-decoration-in-government-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 20:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/debt-graph-as-main-decoration-in-government-office/</guid>
      <description>On Monday, I met the Chief Information Officer of a large US Government Administration in Washington DC.
His office was surprisingly small and functional compared to European &amp;ldquo;big government&amp;rdquo; offices. A nice reminder of how European bureaucracy and public sector spending in administration itself is burying us. But what caught my attention the most was the largest picture in the office: it was not Obama`s, a diploma, a family picture, a flag&amp;hellip; it was this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MLK speech &amp;quot;I have a dream&amp;quot; under restrictive copyright</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/mlk-speech-quoti-have-a-dreamquot-under-restrictive-copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 18:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/mlk-speech-quoti-have-a-dreamquot-under-restrictive-copyright/</guid>
      <description>Embarrassing. We should all be ashamed. At least we can access his words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RePress: fight online censorship with a WP Plug-In</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/repress-fight-online-censorship-with-a-wp-plug-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 17:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/repress-fight-online-censorship-with-a-wp-plug-in/</guid>
      <description>I just installed RePress: This plug-in enables you to magically uncensor any website on the internet from your own WordPress installation. Why and How.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic reactions: Twitter censorship, Google campaign, and magenta trade-marked</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/automatic-reactions-twitter-censorship-google-campaign-and-magenta-trade-marked/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 15:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/automatic-reactions-twitter-censorship-google-campaign-and-magenta-trade-marked/</guid>
      <description>The net was all up in arms this week. After the marvelous uprising against SOPA and PIPA, the new battle ground was Twitter`s announcement of country specific censorship. Never mind that they are open about it (unlike Facebook), never mind that they are talking about their offices and employees in those countries where censorship is the law&amp;hellip; if you hear &amp;ldquo;censorship&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;net&amp;rdquo; get up and scream! Wired has a nice pieceabout it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Zen ad making me sick</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/anti-zen-ad-making-me-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 10:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/anti-zen-ad-making-me-sick/</guid>
      <description>As I walk towards my office, I see an ad that makes me sick (as a matter of fact, I see many, but this one points to something other that the consumerism-sexism-excess that we are so dangerously getting used to).
The ad says &amp;ldquo;Turn now into memories&amp;rdquo;. How wrong is that?!!
Now is now. Now has to be now. Now should be now. Now has to remain now.
When you strive to &amp;ldquo;turn now into memories&amp;rdquo;, you are missing out on the real now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protest against SOPA on your site: easy code</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/protest-against-sopa-on-your-site-easy-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 09:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/protest-against-sopa-on-your-site-easy-code/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Sara, there is a very easy way to add code to your site to protest against SOPA:
Drop the following code in between your two tags on your site, your users will be redirected to the blackout page that describes what you are doing and why.
`Then, when the protest is over, simply remove the added code. The protest is starting at 12am on 1/18, and lasts 24 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia blackout protesting SOPA and PIPA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/wikipedia-blackout-protesting-sopa-and-pipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 19:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/wikipedia-blackout-protesting-sopa-and-pipa/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;div&amp;gt; Today, the Wikipedia community &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;w:en:Wikipedia:SOPA initiative/Action&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/en:Wikipedia:SOPA_initiative/Action&amp;quot;&amp;gt;announced its decision&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; to black out the English-language Wikipedia for 24 hours, worldwide, beginning at 05:00 UTC on Wednesday, January 18 (you can read the &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;Press releases/English Wikipedia to go dark&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Press_releases/English_Wikipedia_to_go_dark&amp;quot;&amp;gt;statement from the Wikimedia Foundation here&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;). The blackout is a protest against proposed legislation in the United States—the &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;w:en:Stop Online Piracy Act&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/en:Stop_Online_Piracy_Act&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Stop Online Piracy Act (SOPA)&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate MLK day with RX2008 mix</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/celebrate-mlk-day-with-rx2008-mix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 09:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/celebrate-mlk-day-with-rx2008-mix/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Uncanny Valley as an approach to the pseudo-empathy of Aperger Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/the-uncanny-valley-as-an-approach-to-the-pseudo-empathy-of-aperger-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 18:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/the-uncanny-valley-as-an-approach-to-the-pseudo-empathy-of-aperger-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>According to Wikipedia:
 The uncanny valley is a hypothesis in the field of robotics and 3D computer animation, which holds that when human replicas look and act almost, but not perfectly, like actual human beings, it causes a response of revulsion among human observers. The &amp;ldquo;valley&amp;rdquo; in question is a dip in a proposed graph of the positivity of human reaction as a function of a robot`s human likeness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing private copies for moving to NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/preparing-private-copies-for-moving-to-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 16:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/preparing-private-copies-for-moving-to-ny/</guid>
      <description>In Spain we have a legal right called &amp;ldquo;private copy&amp;rdquo; by which anyone can make a copy (for non-commercial use) of their copyrighted content (movies, music, books, etc). To offset the supposed loss (many studies prove this &amp;ldquo;loss&amp;rdquo; to be a fallacy) we Spaniards pay the so-called &amp;ldquo;Digital canon&amp;rdquo;, a tax levied on blank media (CDs, HardDisks, printers, photocopiers, etc, etc) and managed by private monopolistic institutions called &amp;ldquo;collecting societies&amp;rdquo;, some run by supposed alcohol-consuming, whore-user, money-embezzler, tax-evading criminals (or so goes the accusations brought to a number of them by the Attorney General).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are charitable dinners and then charitable dinners</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/there-are-charitable-dinners-and-then-charitable-dinners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 10:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/there-are-charitable-dinners-and-then-charitable-dinners/</guid>
      <description>I hate charitable dinners where most (or almost all) of the money goes to caviar, tuxedos, valet parking and other hoopla.
Fortunately there are other charitable dinners, where you wont see any &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.escolar.net/MT/archives/2011/11/la-nueva-politica-de-igualdad.html&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.escolar.net/MT/archives/2011/11/la-nueva-politica-de-igualdad.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;PP mothers&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, like yesterdays organized by Didi, where people sit on the floor, eat off plastic plates, and enjoy Didis deliciously vegan cooking and sincere love, so just about all money collected goes to Calcuttas orphans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCW: Art in Spanish</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/ocw-art-in-spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/ocw-art-in-spanish/</guid>
      <description>I have been interested in OCW (Open CourseWare) since the year 2000, when I tried to convince Polytechnic University of Valencia to upload all materials and lectures from the Master`s Degree (where I was lecturing) to the web for anyone to access.
Although quite slowly, OCW has come a long way. Years ago MIT and some others made a strong commitment for the OCW. But it has taken Spanish universities years to wake up and start to follow that lead.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>