<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NY on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/ny/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NY on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 14:48:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/ny/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Next Event: NY vs London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/google-next-event-ny-vs-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 14:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/google-next-event-ny-vs-london/</guid>
      <description>On June 23 I was invited to attend the Google Next Event, as a customer of Google and a potential partner.
It was quite a shock comparing the overall tone and spirit to the same event in New York, last year.
In New York everything was oriented toward networking, and you had the feeling that anyone could be anyone, and it didn`t matter if they represented a large company or a &amp;ldquo;start-up wannabe&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 8</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 12:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-8/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, May 2, was our last day at sea. We got up late, but still on time to have breakfast at the Britannia restaurant. At 10 am we attended a very interesting lecture by Aldon Ferguson on Covert Operations in the Cold War. After yet another time change, we had lunch followed by an unexpected nap.
We graciously avoided the Guest Talent Show, and went to the Library instead, to catch up on some work and return the books we had checked out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 12:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-7/</guid>
      <description>On Friday, May 1, our bodies finally caught up with all the pre-cruise accumulated stress, by sleeping until 1pm, taking into account the time change. So we headed straight to lunch (“would you like some coffee with your steak and kidney pie, dear?”), followed by a very nice walk around the deck.
After the afternoon tea we worked with our laptops in the Library. My wife decided to go back to the room early, so she could get ready for the formal dinner and Masquerade Ball, while sipping rosé champagne.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 6</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 12:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-6/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday, April 30, we made a resolution to get up early (7am is early even if you are not on a Transatlantic crossing!) so we could have breakfast at 8am and join the fencing class at 9am. There is something wonderfully stylish and timeless about fencing in the ballroom of Cunard’s Queen Victoria.
After the fencing class we went back to the stateroom to shower, and then straight to a Galley Tour, where we inspected the cooking areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 5</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 12:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-5/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday, April 29, as the Commodore announced we were right “in the middle of our crossing,” we woke up really late. You realize how late when the steward greets you “good afternoon,” and you go straight to lunch (right after my wife’s immigration procedure). It was surprising, at least to me, that although we were half an hour late for that scheduled process, 80 people were still to show up, most of the from the USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 4</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 11:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-4/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday, April 28, we finally woke up early enough to enjoy a full service breakfast at the Britannia restaurant and attend the morning lecture “Meteors, Meteorites and Comets”, by Howard L.G. Parkin. While the Royal Court Theater was fairly full, by the time his lecture was over, it completely filled out for the next lecture: “Survival in Solitude”, where Terry Waite told us how, while working as negotiator for the Archbishop of Canterbury, he was taken hostage in Beirut and survived for 5 years, 4 of which he spent in solitary confinement, enduring torture and a mock execution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 11:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-3/</guid>
      <description>On Monday, April 27, we woke up quite late again, so we had breakfast at the Lido restaurant, and went straight to the Royal Court Theater to listen to the lecture by Howard L. G. Parkin “The Constellations – Myth, Legend And Mystery”, right after which we attender another lecture, this time by Simon Dinsdale, in which he shared some of his experiences as a Royal Family bodyguard.
After a light lunch, we went to the library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 10:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-2/</guid>
      <description>April 26 we woke up quite late, with the wonderful feeling of not having to rush, and enjoyed a nice breakfast buffet at the Lido restaurant.
After breakfast we took a walk around the ship, exploring the different venues, from the card room to the library. It is definitely not a “flashy” ship, with the decor being elegantly subtle and conservative. Perhaps the weakest point, as with so many cruise ships, being the artwork, and the most interesting one being the Cunardia (the first Cunard museum at sea) celebrating 175 years of history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 15:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-1/</guid>
      <description>April 25, to celebrate my wifes birthday and to move from New York to London in style, we boarded &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.cunard.com/cruise-ships/queen-victoria/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Cunards Queen Victoriafor a trans-Atlantic crossing (not cruising) onboard the luxury ocean liner (V509).
The night before we had a farewell dinner with some friends in New York at White Street restaurant, which was full of movie industry VIPs already invading Manhattan for the Tribeca Film Festival; our friend Jill, who could not attend the dinner, had a very nice gesture sending a bottle of champagne and a card from Washington DC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My talk at the Circumvention Tech Festival, March 4th</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/my-talk-at-the-circumvention-tech-festival-march-4th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 23:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/my-talk-at-the-circumvention-tech-festival-march-4th/</guid>
      <description>This past winter I met Sandy and James from Open ITP in New York, and Pepe from Valencia. They were organizing the Circumvention Tech Festivalto be held in Las Naves, Valencia (Spain) March 1-6.
They invited me to give a talk, which was eventually scheduled for March 4th at 3pm. I titled the talk “When privacy does not mean the same to you and me”. It was meant to generate debate, to expose other people’s points of view, rather than to be a unidirectional speech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last weekend in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/02/last-weekend-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 16:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/02/last-weekend-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>Yes, the rumor is true: my wife and I are moving to London.
Now that Kanteron USA is solidly stablished, and profitable, I must proceed with the expansion plan, and make sure to grow both Asia and EMEA markets, which I plan to do from London.
So, although we are moving April 25th (more on that in another post, since it will be quite a singular &amp;ldquo;adventure&amp;rdquo;), this was our last weekend in New York because this upcoming weekend we will be in Canada, and next Friday we fly to Europe, where we will be visiting Lisbon, Valencia, Rome and London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin and block chain event in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/02/bitcoin-and-block-chain-event-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/02/bitcoin-and-block-chain-event-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>On Monday, February 9, I attended a Bitcoin – Blockchain eventwith my wife at law firm Latham &amp;amp; Watkins in New York, organized by Hedgeable.

Over 100 bitcoin enthusiasts, investors, journalists, lawyers, and entrepreneurs networking over food and beverages, with demos from:
and a round table of Bitcoin innovation experts:
Since I have already started researching the application of the block chain technology for healthcare, it was quite a useful event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend geek fun</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/01/weekend-geek-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 18:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/01/weekend-geek-fun/</guid>
      <description>I have been lucky enough to experience a couple of weekends in a row at home in NY, which means friends and fun. From having dinner at a friends apartment in the upper East side, and with another heterogeneous group of friends (New York Times journalists, lawyers, and people from the food and restaurant industry) at &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://mercatonyc.com/&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;https://mercatonyc.com/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Mercato&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;; to more geeky things like having lunch in &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.macondonyc.com/&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Christmas in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/01/family-christmas-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 17:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/01/family-christmas-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>This Christmas was the best ever!
We had the kids visit NY from Spain. As usual I never post pictures or give details of other family members in my blog, but we did have a blast: Empire State Building, Central Park, Museum of Math (MoMath), Museum of Modern Art (MoMA), twice dinner at Cafeteria and ice-cream at Amorinos, American Museum of Natural History, the Christmas tree at Rockefeller Center, chatting with the squirrels at Washington Square Park, Forbidden Planet comics, The Strand bookstore, Grand Central Station&amp;hellip; and to top it off we spent a day at the Poconos Camelback mountain snow-tubbing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the MoMA member reception “The Tomorrow Now…”</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/invited-to-the-moma-member-reception-the-tomorrow-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 16:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/invited-to-the-moma-member-reception-the-tomorrow-now/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday my wife and I were invited to the MoMA member reception “The Forever Now: Contemporary Painting in an Atemporal World”, which opens officially tomorrow for the general public.
Obviously the rain did not prevent hordes of socialites to flock to MoMA and gather around one of the three open bars. But that was great because it gave us, and quite a few other &amp;ldquo;they must be on a How About We date&amp;rdquo; couples to visit some of the galleries without having to use our elbows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home pleasures in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/home-pleasures-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 16:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/home-pleasures-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>After all this traveling and going out, it feels wonderful to spend some time at home.
Some things I have been enjoying this week:
 Hanging the art piece my sisterpainted for (and titled after) my wife. By the way, congratulations on your latest solo exhibition, sis! My wife`s cooking: Amazing and unique caribbean stew, banana-chocolate-coconut cake&amp;hellip; Reading (Simone de Beauvoir, Douglas Hofstadter&amp;hellip;) Watching The Newsroom season 2 and some How I met your mother  Traveling, going out and business is all good and fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walks around Manhattan and Dinner at Chefs Club by Food and Wine (twice)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/walks-around-manhattan-and-dinner-at-chefs-club-by-food-and-wine-twice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 15:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/walks-around-manhattan-and-dinner-at-chefs-club-by-food-and-wine-twice/</guid>
      <description>For a few days after Thanksgiving we enjoyed having my parents stay with us in our Chelsea apartment. Visitors are always a great excuse to go to those places that are “too touristy” to go to, even if we like them.
This time we devoted almost a whole day (November 30) to Chinatown, where we enjoyed delicious (and really affordable) dim sum at Dim Sum Go Go.
We also had a blast at the “AllCityStyletoy subway trains for graffiti” display in Grand Central Station, and enjoyed a great lunch at Kitchen by David Burkeon our way to the 9/11 Memorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family road trip to Ithaca, Niagara and Thanksgiving in Buffalo</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/family-road-trip-to-ithaca-niagara-and-thanksgiving-in-buffalo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 13:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/family-road-trip-to-ithaca-niagara-and-thanksgiving-in-buffalo/</guid>
      <description>Since my parents were visiting from Spain, we decided to drive with them to Buffalo to spend Thanksgiving all together with my in-law family.
Wednesday, November 26 we drove over 400 miles (650 Km) through the snow stormfrom New York City to Niagara Falls. Well, my wife drove. I don’t think anyone else in the car could have managed all that snow and ice on the road, but fortunately she has a lot of experience with it, so while it took us four more hours than expected (and forced us to stop at a diner in the middle of the road for lunch, instead of making it to Ithaca as it was our plan), we made it across the Canadian border at Niagara Falls safe and sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the inaugural cruise of the Quantum of the Seas</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/invited-to-the-inaugural-cruise-of-the-quantum-of-the-seas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 16:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/invited-to-the-inaugural-cruise-of-the-quantum-of-the-seas/</guid>
      <description>My wonderful wife invited me to the inaugural cruise of the Quantum of the Seas, which sailed from New York (actually, New Jersey, across the river) and into the Atlantic Ocean, November 18-21.
I love those “inaugurals”. Although their official destination is “nowhere”, I get to enjoy the ship, with its restaurants, and entertainment, in just 3 days. Of course I prefer full cruises (and next April we are taking a very awesome one), but right now I can’t be away from cell coverage and internet for more than 3 days, so this is perfect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Circumvention Tech Festival</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/the-circumvention-tech-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 15:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/the-circumvention-tech-festival/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetings in New York: ICEX, IBM Research, and lawyers at Wilmerhale</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/meetings-in-new-york-icex-ibm-research-and-lawyers-at-wilmerhale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 11:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/meetings-in-new-york-icex-ibm-research-and-lawyers-at-wilmerhale/</guid>
      <description>On Monday November 3rd, right after a call with a Frost &amp;amp; Sullivan analyst, I was invited to the seminar “Spain: Global Platform for International Business Investment”. The event took place in the evening at Jones Day’s headquarters. The usual suspects were there, all in their dark suits and ties. The usual message was there too “Spain is a great place to invest, the government has taken the right steps and now things are finally looking up”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My wife modeling in a photo shooting session for the &#34;I am Warrior&#34; book</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/my-wife-modeling-in-a-photo-shooting-session-for-the-i-am-warrior-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 20:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/my-wife-modeling-in-a-photo-shooting-session-for-the-i-am-warrior-book/</guid>
      <description>While I was in Peru, my wife sent me this picture of her modeling for photographer Shirin Tinati. The photographs will be featured in the upcoming &amp;ldquo;I am Warrior&amp;rdquo; book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pina Bausch dance company at the Howard Gilman Opera House Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/pina-bausch-dance-company-at-the-howard-gilman-opera-house-brooklyn-academy-of-music-bam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 20:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/pina-bausch-dance-company-at-the-howard-gilman-opera-house-brooklyn-academy-of-music-bam/</guid>
      <description>Between my trip to Mexico and the next one to Peru and Colombia, I spent a weekend in New York, and took the opportunity to go with my wife and her ex-husband to see &amp;ldquo;Kontakthof&amp;rdquo; by Pina Bausch dance company at the Howard Gilman Opera House Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM).
Before the show we went to a South African restaurant in Brooklyn called Madiba. Interesting mix of flavors and decor, great seafood imported directly from Mozambique, rustic atmosphere and somewhat &amp;ldquo;hipster&amp;rdquo; but not too much despite being in Brooklyn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice weekend in New York with my in-laws</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/nice-weekend-in-new-york-with-my-in-laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 16:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/nice-weekend-in-new-york-with-my-in-laws/</guid>
      <description>Three weeks ago I enjoyed a nice week at home in New York. My in-laws came to visit from Canada, and my wife took the opportunity to try new recipes using some very fresh ingredients bought in the weekend-only Farmer`s Market just around the corner, on 23rd st in Chelsea. Despite being small, they seem to carry everything, even &amp;ldquo;tea champagne&amp;rdquo; (fermented kombucha with ginger).
From polenta with swiss chards and mushrooms, to homemade apple pie (New Yorkers know their apples: whenever you can, try the &amp;ldquo;honey crisp&amp;rdquo;, you wont regret it), its a real pleasure to enjoy such delicious and healthy dishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting at Dell Solution Center in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/meeting-at-dell-solution-center-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 21:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/meeting-at-dell-solution-center-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>Last Thursday I met with executives from Dell in the Dell Solution Center in New York to explore potential collaborations between my company and Dell.
Funny how large companies have adopted this system of offices / &amp;ldquo;solution&amp;rdquo; centers to make presentations to clients spread across major cities in the world. With telecommuting gaining ground but face to face still being something fundamental in business, it makes much more sense than it seems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spain – U.S. Chamber of Commerce Reception</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/spain-u.s.-chamber-of-commerce-reception/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 21:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/spain-u.s.-chamber-of-commerce-reception/</guid>
      <description>Last Wednesday I was invited to attend a reception honoring the new Chairman of the Spain – U.S. Chamber of Commerce, retired Ambassador Alan D. Solomon, at Hunton &amp;amp; Williams.
Located at 200 Park Avenue, NY – Met Life building, floor 52 (if I remember correctly) the views were outstanding.
It was definitely a “business attire” reception, with everyone wearing a suit, and only a couple of us “daring” not to wear a tie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acquiring a work of art from the Guggenheim Museum in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/acquiring-a-work-of-art-from-the-guggenheim-museum-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 20:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/acquiring-a-work-of-art-from-the-guggenheim-museum-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>August 30th my wife and I acquired another work of art for our collection.
In this case we chose Colombian contemporary artist Carlos Motta: &amp;ldquo;Brief history of US Interventions in Latin America since 1946, 2005/14&amp;rdquo; (Guggenheim UBS MAP Purchase Fund 2014.39).
It is part of a series produced by Carlos Motta between 2005 and 2009 that present two chronologies of events in Latin America: one of U.S. interventions in the region since 1946, and one of the areas leftist guerrilla movements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graffiti show at 21 Precinct, New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/graffiti-show-at-21-precinct-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 19:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/graffiti-show-at-21-precinct-new-york/</guid>
      <description>On August 24th we were invited to the graffiti show at 21 Precinct.
The show ironically took place in the old 21st police Precinct (327 East 22nd Street) which, from 1863 and for 50 years was notorious for corruption and brutality in a [formerly]seedy part of town.
Curated by Robert Aloia &amp;amp; VNA Mag, it featured Adam Dare, Al Diaz, Amanda Marie, ASVP, Bad Pedestrian, Ben Angotti , Bill Claps, Bishop203, Bunny M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cicerone in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/cicerone-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 19:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/cicerone-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>These past 10 days I have been acting as a Cicerone for my sister and her partner. We really enjoyed having them in our Chelsea apartment. It was also a great opportunity to see NY from the eyes of a tourist again, which I sometimes fail to do since I have been living here for 3 years now.
There are a ton of anecdotes and discoveries behind these pictures, but you have to come to New York to experience them 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From VIP breakfast to party to another party... in a day</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/from-vip-breakfast-to-party-to-another-party...-in-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 20:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/from-vip-breakfast-to-party-to-another-party...-in-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday was a long day.
First I was invited to a VIP breakfast executive briefing and presentation by IBM at 7:45am. The event, in which IBM showcased their Watson technology and three partner companies talked about how they are leveraging NLP capabilities, lasted until 12:30pm, but I stayed for an extra hour for a meeting with an IBM executive.
Then I headed back to the office for 3 conference calls. By 7:00pm I was ready to go to the Social Radar startup launch party Stephanie and I had been invited to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIP pass for Basel art show and Amos Lee concert in Brooklyn</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/vip-pass-for-basel-art-show-and-amos-lee-concert-in-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 16:59:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/vip-pass-for-basel-art-show-and-amos-lee-concert-in-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>A friend got me a VIP pass for the 2014 Scope Basel Art Show(thank you, Jorge!). I had it all planned out: since I had a meeting in Stuttgart the day before, I could drive to nearby Basel, attend the VIP opening, and then fly back to New York. But the Stuttgart meeting was cancelled, so I changed my plane ticket, and returned to New York in time to go to the Amos Lee concert in Brooklyn`s Prospect Parkwith my wife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to a gala reception aboard the four-masted tall ship Juan Sebastian de Elcano</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-to-a-gala-reception-aboard-the-four-masted-tall-ship-juan-sebastian-de-elcano/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 21:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-to-a-gala-reception-aboard-the-four-masted-tall-ship-juan-sebastian-de-elcano/</guid>
      <description>The Spanish Consul General in New York, Juan Ramón Martínez Salazar, and the Commander of the Training Ship Juan Sebastián de Elcanoinvited my wife and I to a gala reception aboard the beautiful sail ship (the third largest four-masted tall ship in the world, built in 1927), which is currently docked in New York`s pier 88.
It turned out to be a spectacular evening. The vessel was filled with celebrities: military, politicians with their secret service bodyguards, diplomats, sports, business and entertainment people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to Downtown modern&#43;contemporary art fair</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-to-downtown-modern-contemporary-art-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 20:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-to-downtown-modern-contemporary-art-fair/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I was invited along with my wife by New York art gallery Lyons Wier Galleryto the Downtown modern+contemporary art fairheld at the 69th Regiment Armory in New York.
14,000 international collectors and art enthusiasts, over the course of four-days, gathering to discover paintings, sculptures, photographs and mixed-media works by over 600 artists from around the globe, exhibited by more than 50 international dealers. Seasoned as well as new collectors, curators, museum professionals, cultural foundations, dealers, art advisors and consultants enjoying works by mid-career and emerging artists as well as blue chip works by Picasso, De Kooning, Ruscha, Wesselmann, Rauschenberg, Warhol, Calder and other artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking at the CUNY President`s office</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/networking-at-the-cuny-presidents-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 19:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/networking-at-the-cuny-presidents-office/</guid>
      <description>On May 6th, having just returned from quick trips to Cleveland and Atlanta, I attended with my wife the round table debate &amp;ldquo;Curiosity, Understanding, and Utility: Science and the Creative Economy&amp;rdquo; held at the City University of New York Graduate Center`s Proshansky Auditorium.
William Bialek, director of the Graduate Center`s Initiative for the Theoretical Sciences, moderated a discussion with Jennifer Tour Chayes, distinguished scientist and managing director of Microsoft Research New England and Microsoft Research New York City; Fernando Pereira, research at Google; and Chris Wiggins, chief data scientist at the New York Times and faculty member in the Department of Applied Mathematics and Applied Physics at Columbia University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I acquired a new piece of art from the New Museum New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/i-acquired-a-new-piece-of-art-from-the-new-museum-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 18:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/i-acquired-a-new-piece-of-art-from-the-new-museum-new-york/</guid>
      <description>For my wifes birthday I acquired a piece of art from &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.newmuseum.org/exhibitions/view/pawel-althamer&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.newmuseum.org/exhibitions/view/pawel-althamer&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Paweł Althamers &amp;ldquo;The Neighbors&amp;quot;, which run through April 13 at the New Museum in New York city.
 Since the early 1990s, Althamer (b. 1967 Warsaw, Poland) has established a unique artistic practice featuring an expanded approach to sculptural representation and consistently experimental models of social collaboration.
 It was great to discuss with a museum curator which piece to select (we agreed without a doubt), and it`s a pleasure to have this piece in the living room of our Chelsea apartment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited by Google to the Google Cloud Platform presentation</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-by-google-to-the-google-cloud-platform-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-by-google-to-the-google-cloud-platform-presentation/</guid>
      <description>March 25 Google NY invited me to their Google Cloud Platformpresentation in their Chelsea offices, 8 blocks away from my apartment.
Besides the interesting new features (here are the videos), and the delicious and healthy lunch buffet, I networked quite a lot, and had a few laughs about the highest concentration of Google Glasses per person I have seen so far. One thing is clear: genomics, which is one of the main things my two companies deal with, and the cloud, are closely related, and they will be even more in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delicious kaiseki Japanese dinner at Kyo Ya</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/delicious-kaiseki-japanese-dinner-at-kyo-ya/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 23:06:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/delicious-kaiseki-japanese-dinner-at-kyo-ya/</guid>
      <description>My wife took me to the amazing and discreet Japanese restaurant Kyo Yafor my birthday last month. What an amazing treat!
The menu were 11 courses that were all incredibly delicious:
 &amp;ldquo;Zatsuki&amp;rdquo;: Spring Gobo Kara-age with Sansho Salt &amp;ldquo;Sakizuke&amp;rdquo;: Silky White Turnip Tofu Uni, Caviar, Umadashi-an &amp;ldquo;Oshinogi&amp;rdquo;: Ginger Sticky Mochi Rice Arima Sansho Miso-yaki &amp;ldquo;Owan&amp;rdquo;: Hakusai Cabbage Potage Tricolor Saitomo Patato Dango &amp;ldquo;Zensai&amp;rdquo;: Watercress Yellow Chive and Grilled Shitake Ohitashi; Oyster Moto-yaki on the Shell; Snow Crab and Yamato Potato Isobe-age; &amp;ldquo;Noresore&amp;rdquo; Noodle Like a Fresh Baby Sea Eel; Poached Hotaru Squid with Wakame Seaweed &amp;ldquo;Otsukuri&amp;rdquo;: Sashimi of the Day (Chef`s Selection) &amp;ldquo;Yakimono&amp;rdquo;: Washu Tajima Beef Hot Stone Grill; Sawara Spanish Mackerel Wakasa-yaki; Green Asparagus, Renkon and Shitake &amp;ldquo;Nimono&amp;rdquo;: Clay Potato Soup with Mozzarella Cheese, Ebishinjo, Turnip, Carrot, Wood Ear Mushroom and Poached Quail Egg &amp;ldquo;Tomezakama&amp;rdquo;: Braised Baby Octopus, Apple and Broccoli Rabe, Califlower and Kiwi Puree Vinegar &amp;ldquo;Oshokuji&amp;rdquo;: Canadian Shishamo and Yaki-daikon Kamadaki Rice, Asari Clam Miso Soup and Pickles Desert: Kyoya &amp;ldquo;Monaka&amp;rdquo; Red Bean Sandwich and Soba-cha Sorbet  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the inaugural cruise of Norwegian Getaway</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/invited-to-the-inaugural-cruise-of-norwegian-getaway/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 16:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/invited-to-the-inaugural-cruise-of-norwegian-getaway/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I were invited to the inaugural cruise for the Norwegian Getaway. A &amp;ldquo;sister ship&amp;rdquo; to the Norwegian Breakaway, in which inaugural we cruised last year, this ship is almost exactly identical. We enjoyed fine dining at Le Bistro, Taste, and The Tropicana, cocktails and music at Bliss, and particularly entertainment:
 Comedian Ralph Harrisat the Headliners Comedy Club  Burn the Floorthe musical Illusionarium, a pretty good steam-punk themed magic show with dinner Buddy Valastro (Cake Boss) live cake decorating session  The return to port and docking gave us a nice view of Manhattan`s skyline, along with the scary view of the Hudson river with big chunks of ice (locals say that was unseen since 1977).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the introduction of IBM Watson at WTC NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/invited-to-the-introduction-of-ibm-watson-at-wtc-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 13:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/invited-to-the-introduction-of-ibm-watson-at-wtc-ny/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday January 8th I was asked to hold a meeting regarding the potential involvement of my company (Kanteron Systems) in IBM’s Watson. It was a late night meeting, on the 54th floor of the still under construction World Trade Center. The reason why the meeting took place there is because the IBM team was finishing the set up of the next day’s Watson presentation.
What is Watson, you may ask?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In a private booth at the Madison Square Garden</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/in-a-private-booth-at-the-madison-square-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 20:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/in-a-private-booth-at-the-madison-square-garden/</guid>
      <description>I have been twice at the Madison Square Garden recently. The first time around I was invited, along with my wife, to an NBA New York Knicks vs San Antonio Spurs game. Great seats, we enjoyed the show (since the game was pretty lame). It amazed me how many food stands (from hot dogs to sushi), souvenirs, and paraphernalia stalls there were. Even the popcorn basket had the Knicks logo on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It was so cold, it was funny</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/it-was-so-cold-it-was-funny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 19:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/it-was-so-cold-it-was-funny/</guid>
      <description>The other day my wife and I had to put on several layers of warm clothes to leave our apartment.
Then, when we got back home, we saw this online and we could not stop laughing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This IS cold -23ºF in New York right now with ice inside the window</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/this-is-cold-23%C2%BAf-in-new-york-right-now-with-ice-inside-the-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 16:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/this-is-cold-23%C2%BAf-in-new-york-right-now-with-ice-inside-the-window/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barack and Michelle Obama congratulate us on our wedding</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/11/barack-and-michelle-obama-congratulate-us-on-our-wedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 10:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/11/barack-and-michelle-obama-congratulate-us-on-our-wedding/</guid>
      <description>A couple days ago, when we returned home from the SVA Theatre at the School of Visual Arts, where we were invited to attend the screeningof selected videosby winners and finalists from the 2013 Los Angeles Music Video Festival(and an interesting panel discussion with Bob Giraldi, Christopher Walters, Steven Gottlieb, Scott Reich, August Schram, and others), we found this in our mailbox:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When &amp;quot;progressive media&amp;quot; is ultra conservative</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/when-quotprogressive-mediaquot-is-ultra-conservative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 17:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/when-quotprogressive-mediaquot-is-ultra-conservative/</guid>
      <description>Last Tuesday, October 1, I attended a panel at the City University of New York Graduate Center, titled &amp;ldquo;Into Left Field: Progressive Media in the Age of Austerity&amp;rdquo;.
The Graduate Center’s Peter Beinart (@PeterBeinart), senior political writer for the Daily Beast, discussed the health of progressive media with Katha Pollitt (@KathaPollitt), longtime columnist for The Nation; Joy-Ann Reid (@TheReidReport), managing editor of NBC’s TheGrio.com; and Nermeen Shaikh (@nermeendn), co-host of Democracy Now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precolumbian Einstein</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/precolumbian-einstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 00:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/precolumbian-einstein/</guid>
      <description>Seen at the MET Museum in NY.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NY ComicCon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/ny-comiccon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 23:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/ny-comiccon/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5934418147899482241]
After going the other day with Maker Fairewith my parents, yesterday we went backto ComicCon. The usual: cosplay, crowds, swag&amp;hellip; FUN!!
UPDATE: here is a list of interesting links (artists, publishing houses, software, etc) we collected there.
Artists/Comics:
 Bill Plympton (studio, blog, store, tumblr), whom I have admired for many years, was there in person. Cool! Dylan (UpsideDownGrin) Rich Miller (FilthWorks) Selina Briggs (The Jelly Empire) The Gate Crashers  Studios/Stores:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the love of basketball</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/for-the-love-of-basketball/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 17:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/for-the-love-of-basketball/</guid>
      <description>I have decided to join the Chelsea Recreation Center.
It`s right around the corner from our apartment, and for $150/year it has everything I need:
But mainly
Two days ago I went in for the first time.
I checked out a basketball from the office (the best basketball I have played with in my long career), and went straight to the court.
There were around a dozen kids (18 year olds, high school seniors) playing around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banksy in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/banksy-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 16:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/banksy-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>Banksy is in New York for a month.
With the title &amp;ldquo;Better Out than In&amp;rdquo;, there is a blog, unofficial twitter account(along with the hashtag #banksyny) since it is not linked in the blog, and Instagram(really? Instagram?&amp;hellip; good grief; Im glad I dont have FaceBook so I can`t check if there is also a FB page)&amp;hellip; even a phone number (1 800 6564271) for each piece for which you can call and listen to a great message about (also accessible through the blog).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our beautiful Niagara Falls wedding</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/08/our-beautiful-niagara-falls-wedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 14:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/08/our-beautiful-niagara-falls-wedding/</guid>
      <description>We were originally planning on getting married in Valencia (Spain). Bureaucracy made it too hard. So we decided to change our plans, and get married were we got engaged: Niagara Falls!
[Nevertheless, we will still hold a wedding party in Valencia (Spain) for friends and family, at the Westin Hotel, as it was originally planned, but during the last weekend of August]
We flew from New York to Buffalo Thursday, August 1st, at night and drove to my in-laws across the Canada border to spend the night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VII Japan Society CUTS Contemporary Japanese Film Festival</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/vii-japan-society-cuts-contemporary-japanese-film-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 15:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/vii-japan-society-cuts-contemporary-japanese-film-festival/</guid>
      <description>The Japan Society CUTS Contemporary Japanese Film Festivalis one of my favorites.
This year we saw four very different but delightful (in their own way) fims, all of them USA premieres and Co-presented with the New York Asian Film Festival:
The Festival Opening Film, with Introduction and Q&amp;amp;A with Director Toshiaki Toyoda, and after film party. Interesting story about death, life, cults&amp;hellip;
Of course, while we were in the area, with so many Japanese restaurants in 47th, we tried:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Möbius wedding bands</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/m%C3%B6bius-wedding-bands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 15:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/m%C3%B6bius-wedding-bands/</guid>
      <description>This weekend we bought our wedding bands. After an extremely special and personal engagement ring, the wedding bands had to be special too!:
MÖBIUS – a Danish design classic. We bought it at Georg Jensen– 687 Madison Ave., NY.
 The MÖBIUS ring is inspired by geometry, a magnificent example of post-modern innovation. In math, a MÖBIUS is a shape with one surface and one edge (boundary). It is a fluid, infinite shape that inspires reflection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend in the city, July 11-14</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/weekend-in-the-city-july-11-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 13:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/weekend-in-the-city-july-11-14/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5900883957501185345]
The good weather means more outdoors. In NYC it means more &amp;ldquo;city&amp;rdquo;, but also &amp;ldquo;more things going on in the city&amp;rdquo;.
This weekend we have walked a lot, and seen quite a few interesting things around town (caveat: I am no expert in NY, although Spanish newspaper Expansion interviewed meabout it last week), like:
 A Chinese-Spanish cuisine restaurant (no, I have no desire to try it any time soon; there are many others higher on my list) Yoga in Bryant Park A looooooong line of police cars going by The Orly Genger art installation at Madison Sq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delicious home treats: chick pea cookies and more</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/delicious-home-treats-chick-pea-cookies-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 12:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/delicious-home-treats-chick-pea-cookies-and-more/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5899800239557635921]
Last week we had a few home cooked treats at home: paella (or as close as it gets with local ingredients), sangria, and peanut butter – chocolate chip – chick pea cookies! Try those cookies with hazelnut &amp;ldquo;milk&amp;rdquo;. Delicious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Severe weather warning</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/severe-weather-warning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 14:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/severe-weather-warning/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to celebrate 4th of July: defending our rights</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/how-to-celebrate-4th-of-july-defending-our-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 15:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/how-to-celebrate-4th-of-july-defending-our-rights/</guid>
      <description>I started my 4th of July&amp;ldquo;celebrations&amp;rdquo; one day early, by visiting the Declaration of Independence &amp;amp; Bill of Rights, handwritten by Thomas Jefferson, exhibited for the first time together, at the NYPL.
 Then, today (4th of July) I went to a protest to demand the restoration of the Fourth Amendment:
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5896836194188971633]
  “The right of the people to be secure in their persons, houses, papers, and effects, against unreasonable searches and seizures, shall not be violated&amp;hellip;”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese fun</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/japanese-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 15:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/japanese-fun/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, on my way to a financial presentation, I stopped at Kinokuniya Bookstoreto browse books and to enjoy the origami they had on display as part of the OrigamiAsArtexhibition.
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5896481691678261089]
To round the Japanese-themed day up, I went in the New York Public Libraryand got two films:
 Densha Otoko (Train_Man) Fish Story  ^_^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoHo surprises</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/soho-surprises/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 15:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/soho-surprises/</guid>
      <description>Lately I have been going to the office more than usual. The FDA inspection, then the PILOT health tech NY day (which was held in the coworking space where my office is), and a few other things have made me walk around SoHo quite a lot these days. Here are a few of the surprises I have encountered in the always colorful neighborhood:  The Pearl River Market store, right next door to my offices entrance, is &amp;quot;SoHos best kept secret&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy of an FDA inspection</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/anatomy-of-an-fda-inspection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 15:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/anatomy-of-an-fda-inspection/</guid>
      <description>On April 25th I attended my first FDA (U.S. Food and Drug Administration) Medical Device Establishment Inspection. Agent (Investigator) Kimberley A. Ricketts called me a couple days before to let me know that as a registered medical device manufacturing company, Kanteron Systems (the company I founded in 2005) had been selected for an Establishment Inspection. It was the &amp;ldquo;Notice of Inspection pursuant to Section 704(a)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetics Act [21 U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun event at Garden City hotel</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/fun-event-at-garden-city-hotel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 14:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/fun-event-at-garden-city-hotel/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5894592732529447057]
On Thursday our friend Marsha invited us to attend the Garden City Hotel Gilded Revelry event: reopening of Grand Ballroom.
At first it did not seem that interesting, specially taking into account that we had to ride the LIRR train for 40 minutes from Penn Station (changing in Jamaica) to Long Island. But once we arrived, we quickly admitted it was a good idea.
A renovated Grand Ballroom hosting two acrobats, an electric violin and a DJ with projections of historic photos from the hotel in the background for entertaining, and the real highlight of the night: the most amazing sushi bar I have ever had the pleasure to experience on one side, and an awesome and delicious hors d`oeuvres buffet on the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supermoon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/supermoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 22:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/supermoon/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And this is how the movie industry chokes itself</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/and-this-is-how-the-movie-industry-chokes-itself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 16:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/and-this-is-how-the-movie-industry-chokes-itself/</guid>
      <description>On May 13th, on my way to a friends apartment, we stumbled upon the set of Ben Stillers new movie right outside the 125th St. subway exit. They were filming in the middle of the street. What struck me the most was that one of the façades of the building had been completely redone (cast, cement, wood, paint&amp;hellip; it looked absolutely real and solid) for the film.
Really? No building façade will do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Columbia University</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/columbia-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 15:50:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/columbia-university/</guid>
      <description>After a work meeting (and seeing a colorful piano, being fine tuned, in a public space) I took the opportunity to visit Columbia University (it was about time).
The first building I enter is called &amp;ldquo;The Library at Columbia University&amp;rdquo;. But, alas, is not a library!
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5886802933387406849]
It ceased to be a library in the late 30s, and now happens to be the Administrative Offices. Across the lawn, where students and visitors were chilling out and enjoying the sunny day, I find one of the many libraries:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robataya NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/robataya-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 15:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/robataya-ny/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5883108291816300705]
Meaning to go to a Tibetan restaurant which happened to be closed Memorial Day, we ended up in Robataya NY(sister of the great Robatoya Roppongi Hills, Tokyo). Easily one of the finest Japanese restaurants in the city. Cute, fun and delicious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Council Of Protocol Executives event India House, New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/council-of-protocol-executives-event-india-house-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 15:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/council-of-protocol-executives-event-india-house-new-york/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5880615132510590913]
May 21st (sorry that is taking me so long to write posts, but unlike what this blog seems to convey, I also do work. A lot) I was invited to a Council Of Protocol Executivesevent India House, New York.
It was a wonderful mix of C-level executives from all kinds of industries (healthcare, advertising, travel, banking&amp;hellip;). A great networking opportunity, with delicious food (seafood risotto, truffle and porcini ricotta, fried oysters, choclate covered strawberries&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home culinary delights in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/home-culinary-delights-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 14:56:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/home-culinary-delights-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5879887825546630113]
(Photo of a Paella cooked by my friend Paul in his new apartment in the UWS, New York)
My friends and family in Valencia have serious doubts that one can eat in the USA as well as in Spain.
Granted, Spain is a foodie`s paradise (by the way, amazing how many of the top 50 restaurants in the worldI have had the pleasure to try, the latest one being Dinner by Heston Blumenthal in London thanks to Stephanie).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting NY tech companies</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/meeting-ny-tech-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 17:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/meeting-ny-tech-companies/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5879766487788118305]
Friday May 17th I took the day to meet some of the interesting tech companies present in New York. There are over 1,200 tech companies in NY(including CodeAcademy, KickStarter, Foursquare, MakerBot, ZocDoc, Guilt, AppNexus, Tumblr, Etsy, KickStarter, Automatic&amp;hellip; and mine!), most between the Flat Iron and SoHo areas of Manhattan (Silicon ALley). So I chose a few that, for one reason or another, I was interested in meeting and talk to their founders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Day at Central Park</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/japan-day-at-central-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 19:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/japan-day-at-central-park/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5877241182002662785]
On Sunday, after returning to New York from the inaugural cruise, we went to Central Park to spend the afternoon and enjoy Japan Day!
Tents with huge lines to get free Japanese food (udon, okonomiyaki, gyozas, panda chocolate snacks, tea&amp;hellip;), activities (calligraphy, kimonos, origami, yoyo-fishing&amp;hellip;) and performances (karate, taiko&amp;hellip;), all very well organized and full of mostly Japanese people in a very fun and nice event.
There were even so many cosplayers that it reminded me of Jing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norwegian Breakaway inaugural cruise day 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/norwegian-breakaway-inaugural-cruise-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 19:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/norwegian-breakaway-inaugural-cruise-day-3/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5877236967059231169]
All things must come to an end, so today we sadly had to disembark. After a nice breakfast and a last stroll through the ship, we disembarked very fast and easily, and in a few minutes we were back home in Chelsea (after going through the most absurd and disorganized taxi system I have seen in this country).
What`s my verdict? It is an exceptionally nice ship for a mass market, even considering its gigantic size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norwegian Breakaway inaugural cruise day 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/norwegian-breakaway-inaugural-cruise-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 19:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/norwegian-breakaway-inaugural-cruise-day-2/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5877235646228621073]
Day 2 of our cruise started waking up to the sound of the waves and with a buffet breakfast at Garden Café, which we took in an outside table.
The day was fully packed of activities, and given my terrible memory, I`m sure I would have forgotten some of them by now. But thanks to the fact that the cruise line gave us access to the net (although only for Twitter, Facebook and Instagram), I was able to tweet my activities, and then use the TL to remember them easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norwegian Breakaway inaugural cruise day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/norwegian-breakaway-inaugural-cruise-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 19:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/norwegian-breakaway-inaugural-cruise-day-1/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5877234291045425713]
We were invited to board the Norwegian Breakaway inauguralcruise last Friday. A huge (146,600 tones and 1,062 feet for 4,000 passengers and 1,595 crew) and brand new ship.
It was a short inaugural cruise, 100 miles into the Atlantic Ocean, for VIPs (the bankers that financed the construction of the ship, Norwegian Cruise Lines executives, journalists, &amp;ldquo;star&amp;rdquo; travel agents&amp;hellip; even Mayor Bloomberg). Many well known people aboard: artist Peter Max, who designed the hull and was signing posters, Iron Chef Geoffrey Zakarian (with his Ocean Blue restaurant as one of the 27 the ship has)&amp;hellip; As we went through the very fast and easy boarding procedure at Pier 88, even President Obama flew over the ship in his helicopter!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The System: true injustice</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/the-system-true-injustice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 14:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/the-system-true-injustice/</guid>
      <description>One of the friends having dinner with us yesterdaywas a lawyer that used to be a Public Defender in NY. Of all the many interesting stories she had to tell, one struck me as the perfect example of all that is wrong with The System.
 Once she had to defend a homeless man who was accused of stealing a candy bar from a drugstore. Since he had breached a non-trespass order from a previous similar incident, the prosecutor was asking for a 3 year prison sentence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NY Shorewalkers The Great Saunter 2013</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/ny-shorewalkers-the-great-saunter-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 14:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/ny-shorewalkers-the-great-saunter-2013/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5874557463298386241]
Yesterday we joined a few friends in part of the NY Shorewalkers The Great Saunter 2013walk. While the Shorewalkers started early in the morning and walked all along the West side of Manhattan, we started much later, and to the subway to Carl Schurz Park, where we had fun watching the dogs at the dog park, visiting Major Bloomberg`s official residence (although he does not really live there, he only uses it as a nice reception place), enjoying the trees blooming and flowers, and strolling up the East side to meet them half way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working distractions</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/working-distractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 13:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/working-distractions/</guid>
      <description>If I go to the office, I complain that there are too many distractions: whether it is the boom-boom music form the downstairs SoHo store, my coworkers playing ping-pong, street art that requires my attention, or the temptation of a Japanese bento box or mochi with tea&amp;hellip;
But if I stay at home, Calvin makes sure I am not as productive as I could be.
OK, I admit it, this was a very silly excuse to try a new slider plugin with Pinterest non-official API&amp;hellip; and trying those things is not a diversion or distraction, is part of my job, I swear!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TAO NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/tao-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 19:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/tao-ny/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5872049082409447089]
Last weekend we went to TAOto celebrate a birthday. For a large size restaurant that has been in operation as long as they have, it is amazing that the service was decent, the vibe cool, and the food good (special mention for the ruby dragon cocktail). It was fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seen in the streets of NY until april 2013</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/seen-in-the-streets-of-ny-until-april-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 19:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/seen-in-the-streets-of-ny-until-april-2013/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5867858717493854113]
Now that the good weather seems to have arrived to NY, I will be walking more (more than my two hours daily that I already walk), and will be more willing to stop and take photographs of the crazy stuff one sees on the streets every day. Here are some images before April 2013.
(Note: the fun Einstein and Freud images were taken at Chelsea Market, from an exhibition by FunnyFoodArt).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossing the border for a genetic test</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/04/crossing-the-border-for-a-genetic-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 13:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/04/crossing-the-border-for-a-genetic-test/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, as part of an unusual birthday gift, my fiancé and I signed up to get our genetic test.
So we ordered the test kit online, and when we entered the state (NY), a big warning told us that according to state laws, we could not produce or mail the samples back to their labs from New York. WTF?! OK, whatever. As if a nonsensical law did not have many ways around it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Triple art opening at MAD</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/triple-art-opening-at-mad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/triple-art-opening-at-mad/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we were invited to a triple art opening at the Museum of Art and Design(MAD):  After the Museum: &amp;ldquo;As artists, designers, and corporations have increasingly begun to stage exhibitions, lectures, and workshops modeled from the role of museums in the 20th century, current museum forms are increasingly called into question.&amp;rdquo; (March 12, 2013 to June 9, 2013) Wear it or Not: The exhibition features nearly 130 works from around the world, recently acquired by the MAD (March 12, 2013 to June 2, 2013) Against the Grain: Featuring nearly 90 installations, sculptures, furniture, and objects, the exhibition explores some of the most cutting-edge conceptual and technical trends in woodworking today (March 19, 2013 to September 15, 2013)  We also took the opportunity to re-visit &amp;ldquo;Playing with Fire&amp;rdquo;: 50 Years of Contemporary Glass (November 20, 2012 to August 25, 2013).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New City art fair: Japanese contemporary art</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/new-city-art-fair-japanese-contemporary-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 17:57:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/new-city-art-fair-japanese-contemporary-art/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5853820841512126817]
Today we went to New Cityart fair, Japanese contemporary art at hpgrp Galleryin Chelsea.
Almost everything, from Satoru Tamuras machines from Tezukayama Gallery (who also carried and showed works by Yayoi Kusama, Tomohiro Kato, and Takao Machiba), to the works at Art-U room (by Kazuo Shiraga, Atsuko Tanaka, Jiro Yoshihara, Sadamasa Motonaga, Chiyu Uemae, and Takesada Matsutani), the ones at hprgp (Hisaharu Motoda and Yuichi Hirako), to Satelites ART LAB (Shingo Iguchi, Ben Mori, and Anna Tsubaki), to Fuko Ueadas paintings on Gallery Kogure (along with Takahiro Hirabayashi, Hidenori Yamaguchi, Hiroyuki Matsuura, Takahiro Sanda, Yuwa Kato and Takato Yamamoto), to Gallery TEN (who carries Eishi Takaoka, Michio Kono, Jumpei Yamamuro, Masataka Kitamono, and Kazuko Kaneda), to Shusuke Ao`s installation on eitoeiko (who was also showing Shusuke Ao, Ichiro Irie, Yuki Yoshida and Junta Egawa), almost everything was outstanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At Independent art show</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/at-independent-art-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 23:12:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/at-independent-art-show/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5853532342637394897]
Today we have gone to the Independentart show at Center 548. Two floors (starts in the second floor, and the roof top only has a bar). The second floor has some, very few, interesting works. The third floor? Don`t even bother. From childish to improvised, without even being outsider or brut.
When I go to art shows like this I exit with a strange happy grin. The reason? I realize I still have a personal taste, and I know what I don`t like, no matter how crowded the space is, or if it is in Chelsea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inauguration of Edo Pop at Japan Society</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/inauguration-of-edo-pop-at-japan-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 23:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/inauguration-of-edo-pop-at-japan-society/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5853531658541752273]
Yesterday we were invited by Miwako Tezuka (domo arigato!) to the inauguration of Edo Popat Japan Society. It was wonderful!
Besides the classic and beautiful nishiki-e works by the masters Katsushika Hokusai (yes, Under the Wave off Kanagawa from the series Thirty-six Views of Mount Fuji, was there), Utagawa Hiroshige, Toshusai Sharaku, Toyota Hokkei, Utagawa Kunisada, Utagawa Kuniyoshi, and Suzuki Harunobu, there were contemporary works by graffiti artist Aiko, strikingly &amp;ldquo;Japanese&amp;rdquo; transparencies by Emily Allchurch, reinterpreted iconic portraits by Paul Binnie, political criticism in the work of Ishii Toru and Kazama Sachiko (amazing the large format Alas!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freak snow storm</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/freak-snow-storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 22:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/freak-snow-storm/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5853068702144573873]
On Thursday I woke up to a message from a friend, professor at MIT, who was flying to SXSW and was stuck onboard the plane with the Boston airport closed. We had a freak snow storm: it started snowing in the morning. The snow accumulated throughout the day. By night it stopped and temperatures went up. In two days we have gone from 20ºF to 54ºF. New York weather: unpredictable and not for the faint of heart 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Image contemporary video art fair</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/moving-image-contemporary-video-art-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 22:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/moving-image-contemporary-video-art-fair/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5853065109523333633]
A couple days ago we were invited to the inauguration of Moving Imagecontemporary video art fair at the Terminal Stores (Waterfront Tunnel).
Interesting initiative, in a spectacular space, but as always some works were more appealing than others. This time, without a doubt, the only ones that I would definitely recommend are the ones shown by Ted Victoria(represented by Schröder Romero &amp;amp; Shredder). Very objectual, but quite imaginative and evocative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online access to the art shows I`ll miss</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/online-access-to-the-art-shows-ill-miss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 22:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/online-access-to-the-art-shows-ill-miss/</guid>
      <description>Since this week there are way too many art shows to visit, I`ll miss some, for sure.
Luckily, these events are getting better and better with their online access and info, and now we have Volta‘s catalogue online:We also have a good portion of Armory‘s show online, by Artsy.
Enjoy 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCOPE contemporary art show</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/scope-contemporary-art-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 21:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/scope-contemporary-art-show/</guid>
      <description>This is the Armory art weekin New York: Armory, SCOPE, Volta, Independent, Spring/Break, PooL, New City, Moving Image, ADAA, and Fountain.
My friend Jorge (thank you, Jorge!) gave us a VIP pass so we attended the inaugural party of the SCOPE contemporary art show.
I enjoyed it for the same reasons I enjoyed Volta last year: international, interesting, refreshing, criticism, political charge, varied&amp;hellip; There were too many interesting artists and works to mention, but in the photo gallery you have a few examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carnegie Hall concert Royal Stockholm Philharmonic Orchestra with Ray Chen</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/carnegie-hall-concert-royal-stockholm-philharmonic-orchestra-with-ray-chen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 12:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/carnegie-hall-concert-royal-stockholm-philharmonic-orchestra-with-ray-chen/</guid>
      <description>Tonight my friend Caterina has invited us (thank you Cat!!) to the Carnegie Hall concert: Royal Stockholm Philharmonic Orchestra featuring her friend, awesome violinist Ray Chen.
Performers
 Royal Stockholm Philharmonic Orchestra Sakari Oramo, Conductor Ray Chen, Violin Elin Rombo, Soprano  Program
 ROLF MARTINSSON Open Mind GRIEG &amp;ldquo;Våren,&amp;rdquo; Op. 34, No. 2 STENHAMMAR &amp;ldquo;Fylgia,&amp;rdquo; Op. 16, No. 4 STENHAMMAR &amp;ldquo;Flickan kom ifrån sin älsklings möte,&amp;rdquo; Op. 4, No. 1 BRUCH Violin Concerto No.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet VD</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/sweet-vd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 12:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/sweet-vd/</guid>
      <description>When a coconut milk seared wild salmon with basmati rice dinner at home ends with these three desserts/gifts, you know it is sweet:
– I received an incredible Japanese assorted wagashi box from Minamoto Kitchoan(with a beautiful Hokusai &amp;ldquo;The Great Wave off Kanagawa&amp;rdquo; Ukiyo-e card)
– I gave her Momofuku MilkBarassorted cookies (of course, with the &amp;ldquo;compost&amp;rdquo; in the assortment) and b`day truffles
– Plus Wholefoods Market Dark Chocolate Pear Almond (Lindt had that flavor, and the discontinued it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concert and museum opening night</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/concert-and-museum-opening-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 12:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/concert-and-museum-opening-night/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday we went to the &amp;ldquo;Tribute to Elliott Carter&amp;rdquo; concert at City University of New York Graduate Center (34th st &amp;amp; 5th Ave). A varied roster of (mostly) great (mostly) young performers, and Elliott Carters unmistakables compositions. I must admit it is not my favorite kind of music to say the least, but I do keep trying to expand my horizons. Always learning, or trying to. Experience, expose, try&amp;hellip; isnt that the hackers attitude?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day of wine and snow</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/day-of-wine-and-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 17:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/day-of-wine-and-snow/</guid>
      <description>February 9th was truly a day of wine and snow.
A big snowfall came down the night before, leaving the pretty pictures we have all seen in the media, along with 6,000 cancelled flights and 400,000 homes without power in the Boston area.
So I had no plans to get out of my comfortable Chelsea apartment, but Jill (a friend who works at the New York Times, and who is moving to Washington DC to head the DC Bureau of the NYT) invited us to the NYC Winter Wine Fest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in NY: Wired Magazine and IBM Smart Camp</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/back-in-ny-wired-magazine-and-ibm-smart-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 17:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/back-in-ny-wired-magazine-and-ibm-smart-camp/</guid>
      <description>After MIT`s crazy week, back in NY I needed a couple of days of sleep and relax to get back into the normal rhythm. Luckily it was SuperBowl weekend, so the streets (and Chelsea Market) were fairly empty!
So on Tuesday I was ready to get going full speed ahead. First, after meeting with P. Oberton in the NYPL, then I went to Condé Nast publications` building, into Wired Magazine, to discuss a PR campaign/project along with Valencia Regional Minister of Industry (&amp;amp; etc) Max Buch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lima and Valencia in January</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/lima-and-valencia-in-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/lima-and-valencia-in-january/</guid>
      <description>The second week of January I flew to Lima (Peru) for an important business meeting. It was a hard trip: overnight flight from New York, straight to meeting, and overnight flight back. But there was no other way to fit the trip in my schedule.
A few days later I flew with my fiancée to Valencia both for business and for pleasure.It was a cloudy and &amp;ldquo;cold&amp;rdquo; week (for Valencia anyway, because 58ºF could hardly count as &amp;ldquo;cold&amp;rdquo;, considering it is 11ºF now in New York).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas at Niagara Falls</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/christmas-at-niagara-falls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 08:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/christmas-at-niagara-falls/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5826431747820457009]
This year I spent Christmas at Niagara Falls.
While it is one of the natural wonders of the world, I had not thought about visiting it before because I did not expect it to be &amp;ldquo;worth it&amp;rdquo;. How wrong I was! Not only it is a lovely area (the Canadian side, at least), albeit certainly quite &amp;ldquo;touristic&amp;rdquo;, but the waterfalls indeed are amazing. You stand so close to the water, intense green, that you can feel it rush, precipitate, and crash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&amp;quot;Cat on a Hot Tin Roof&amp;quot; at Richard Rodgers Theatre with Scarlett Johansson</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/quotcat-on-a-hot-tin-roofquot-at-richard-rodgers-theatre-with-scarlett-johansson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 18:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/quotcat-on-a-hot-tin-roofquot-at-richard-rodgers-theatre-with-scarlett-johansson/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday Stephanie [thank you!] invited me to see &amp;ldquo;Cat on a Hot Tin Roof&amp;rdquo; at Richard Rodgers Theatre (Broadway, New York) with Scarlett Johansson.
Although I had seen the movie, perhaps because I was too young to understand, or perhaps because in the movie the plot is not as clear, the truth is that I enjoyed and understood Tennessee Williams play much better this time. And it has a much broader appeal than what I initially guessed (being a _Southern Gothic_ work).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Montevideo in December</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/montevideo-in-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 20:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/montevideo-in-december/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5821499441712215169]
December 2nd I flew to Montevideo. I stayed at the Radisson Hotel, Plaza de la Independencia. Very conveniently located with some impressive views from the top floor. Good thing it had a pool, because it is not easy to keep my exercise regime when traveling so much.
Besides very productive meetings with IBM (very nice, professional, and friendly executives, by the way) and presentation to several hospital groups (one of the meetings at the Presidential Building, another one at the country`s largest hospital, and a presentation at the Solis Theater), I enjoyed the promenade by the river which seems like a sea, the old town, and a weird Ice Bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>007 Skyfall at MoMA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/007-skyfall-at-moma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 21:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/007-skyfall-at-moma/</guid>
      <description>Although it may not be too obvious, I have been going through a few very hard weeks for several reasons. So someone who knows me well told me I should not be stupid, and should have fun. Let`s be it, then!
As part of their James Bond 50 years celebration, MoMA has been showing some of 007 movies in their collection (the largest by any museum in the world). So yesterday I was invited, and I of course invited Stephanie to be my guest, to the screening of the latest James Bond movie: &amp;ldquo;007 Skyfall&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After hurricane Sandy in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 20:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>From tilted posts to trees completely gone, after hurricane Sandy there were many signs of destruction around New York.
I had to stay at Stepahnie`s apartment (thank you again!) until Monday, because my building remained without power. And even after the power returned, the telephone and internet took two more days.
Some people were not so lucky, with all hotels fully booked, and had to stay at home for days without power or water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Sandy in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 20:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>To go from Baltimore to NY has been a real nightmare. I had a return train ticket for the 29th at night, but that was obviously cancelled. Amtrak then rebooked me on the first train out of Baltimore (at 03:45am on November 1st), and since flights or buses were not operating, I took it.
The nice lady at the travel agency got me a reservation on a flight to La Guardia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instead of Halloween party</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/instead-of-halloween-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 15:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/instead-of-halloween-party/</guid>
      <description>I`m still stuck in Baltimore, but it seems I will be able to return to NY late tonight, arrivingtomorrow morningafternoon, the day after Halloween (which reaches amazing levels, like Barbie special edition dolls).
So, instead of going to the Village Halloween parade(which has been cancelled for the first time in 39 years), or anyof the Halloween parties I was invited to (the New Museum and Cara`s parties have also been cancelled), and wear the cool and simple MineCraft Creeper costume Cory Doctorow twitted(from Comic Con NY):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Sandy in Baltimore</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/hurricane-sandy-in-baltimore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 23:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/hurricane-sandy-in-baltimore/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Film screening at the portal of power and party at the Whitney</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/film-screening-at-the-portal-of-power-and-party-at-the-whitney/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 23:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/film-screening-at-the-portal-of-power-and-party-at-the-whitney/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday I was invited to the screening of the documentary &amp;ldquo;Gregory Crewdson Brief Encounters&amp;rdquo; at the Core Club(that has been called the &amp;ldquo;Portal of Power&amp;rdquo; by The New York Times, or &amp;ldquo;Where the 1 Percent Go to Lunch&amp;rdquo; by CNBC), with popcorn, M&amp;amp;Ms, wine bar and all.
Both Ben Shapiro and Gregory Crewdson(and his mother) were there introducing the film. But their shyness made them refuse a formal Q&amp;amp;A session, so to talk to them one had to go to the reception area after the film and mingle and chat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaos and Cosmos</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/chaos-and-cosmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 22:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/chaos-and-cosmos/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday I went to listen to Mitchell J. Feigenbaum and Albert J. Libchaber (mathematical physicists) discuss chaos theory at CUNY Graduate Center.
After that I went to McNally Jackson Books, a great book store in SoHo, and to the opening reception for “Rosemarie Trockel: A Cosmos&amp;rdquo;, at the New Museum, organized by Massimiliano Gioni, Associate Director and Director of Exhibitions, and Jenny Moore, Associate Curator, in collaboration with Rosemarie Trockel and Lynne Cooke, chief curator of the Museo Nacional Centro de Arte Reina Sofía, Madrid (Spain).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20,000 homeless kids in NYC</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/20000-homeless-kids-in-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 02:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/20000-homeless-kids-in-nyc/</guid>
      <description>Number of homeless kids in NYC last year: 16,000
Number of homeless kids in NYC this year: 20,000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slavoj Žižek lecture &amp;quot;Conditions of Possibility&amp;quot; with M. Hägglund and A. Johnston</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/slavoj-%C5%BEi%C5%BEek-lecture-quotconditions-of-possibilityquot-with-m.-h%C3%A4gglund-and-a.-johnston/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 13:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/slavoj-%C5%BEi%C5%BEek-lecture-quotconditions-of-possibilityquot-with-m.-h%C3%A4gglund-and-a.-johnston/</guid>
      <description>Note: Start video on 33:33 (absolutely nothing happening before that, but just people waiting for the panelist to go on stage).On Friday I was invited to attend Slavoj Žižeks lecture &amp;quot;Conditions of Possibility&amp;quot; with M. Hägglund &amp;amp; A. Johnston at City University of New Yorks Graduate Center.
Martin Hägglund (associate professor of comparative literature and humanities at Yale University) and Adrian Johnston (professor in the department of philosophy at the University of New Mexico at Albuquerque and a faculty member at the Emory Psychoanalytic Institute in Atlanta) both read legthy and endogamic discourses about Heidegger, classic philosophical concepts, and stubbornly narrow minded &amp;ldquo;canons&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seen in NY: skaters, cheese and a record selling truck</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/seen-in-ny-skaters-cheese-and-a-record-selling-truck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 12:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/seen-in-ny-skaters-cheese-and-a-record-selling-truck/</guid>
      <description>A big band of skaters (I only captured a few in my photograph becuase they were left behind in a stoplight, but there were many many more) rolling down south on Broadway. As they passed, people on the side walk greeted and cheered them. More play and less politics, or the return of the playful society, please. [Update.- there is a big story behind it: the Broadway Bomb] Beecher`s Handmade Cheese, where you can sample and purchase artisanal cheese, have some wine and small apetizers in the cellar downstairs, but even more fun to just sit and watch them make cheese live, through a big glass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>319 Scholes art opening of &amp;quot;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 12:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I went to 319 Scholes to attend the art opening of &amp;ldquo;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;rdquo;.
Beyond the anecdotal post/pre hispter crowd, the exhibition itself is a sad celebration of noise. Which, in itself is as valid, or invalid, as any other starting point in the endless debate about art (more so in regards with contemporary, electronic, net, etc).
But it is its legitimization attempt, with research project, curator, catalogue, and international tour, which brings the debate to a whole different level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silver Wind: The Arts of Sakai Hoitsu</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/silver-wind-the-arts-of-sakai-hoitsu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 11:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/silver-wind-the-arts-of-sakai-hoitsu/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, October 2nd I was invited to the member`s viewing and reception of &amp;ldquo;Silver Wind: The Arts of Sakai Hoitsu&amp;rdquo; exhibition at Japan Society. This exhibition is the first American retrospective of Sakai Hoitsu (1761-1828), a samurai aristocrat turned Buddhist monk who dedicated his life to art and poetry. On exhibit there were also a few works by his chief pupil Suzuki Kiitsu, although I must admit the difference between the two is quite notable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections from NY Comic Con</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 09:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I went to NY Comic Con, like everyone else, I guess, with the idea of having fun, of experiencing first hand one of the &amp;ldquo;major events&amp;rdquo; that a true nerdy geek can attend. I also wanted to meet Cory Doctorow (although we actually ended up not meeting). It has been years since I last met him, and it was the perfect &amp;ldquo;excuse&amp;rdquo; to attend the conference.
When I arrived, I was really surprised to see the size of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September gone</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/september-gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/september-gone/</guid>
      <description>I can`t seem to be able to keep up. Too much going on at all levels. So my &amp;ldquo;done this and that&amp;rdquo; posts are going to be reduced to the minimum expression.
September 5th I went to thisevent I already talked about.
September 7th I was invited to attend the premiere of a documentary about Gerhard Richter at the New Museum. It was very revealing and sad to see how Richters art critic/historian proposed an interpretation of one of his paintings that Richter did not seem to agree on, but after a few minutes of conversation, he &amp;quot;accepted&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High culture might will numb you, how stay true? On &amp;quot;Graffiti&amp;quot; screening and panel at New Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 15:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I was invited to the New Musuem for the screening of &amp;ldquo;Graffiti – PostGraffiti&amp;rdquo; documentary and panel discussion.Your usual suspects were there. Besides the panelist (Pattie Astor, Fab Five Freddy, Lady Pink, and Lee Quinones), there were many old glories and a couple of aspiring bomber kids in the audience that I am sure were tagging walls late that night.
What started as a celebration, a remembrance, and a comunion, as the liturgy advanced ended up becoming a hurtful vindication and even a flat out purist attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I`m the man and the boy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/im-the-man-and-the-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 22:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/im-the-man-and-the-boy/</guid>
      <description>I`m the man that fears rejection
Im the man that cant sleep because of problems
I`m the man that will fight and defend the castle</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It`s October and all I want is you</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 22:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</guid>
      <description>Lying on the carpet, poetry book and pencil in hand, U2 in the background.
October
 October
And the trees are stripped bare
Of all they wear
What do I care
October
And kingdoms rise
And kingdoms fall
But you go on&amp;hellip;and on&amp;hellip;
 So many literal meanings: the fear of wearing-out (The Edge was considering leaving the band like his brother did before they were even called U2), the false sense of security arising from self-defeat (&amp;ldquo;What do I care&amp;rdquo;), moving on after a loss (both Bono and Larry had just lost their mothers), the high hopes and expectations arising from new democracies in Eastern Europe only to become despair and dissapointment, and eventually resilience, surviving, going on&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for Sugar Man</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/searching-for-sugar-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2012 14:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/searching-for-sugar-man/</guid>
      <description>Last Sunday I went to see Searching for Sugar Manbio/docu/picat Lincoln Plaza Theaters.
 Two South Africans set out to discover what happened to their unlikely musical hero, the mysterious 1970s rock ‘n` roller, Rodriguez.
 While the movieis a very good one, and the story quite powerful (not only a human story about an incredible musiciancalled Rodriguez, better than Bob Dylan if you allow me the heresy), there are two aspects that go well beyond the typical in this kind of documentary:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round table at NYCBA about Campaign Reform</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/round-table-at-nycba-about-campaign-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 13:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/round-table-at-nycba-about-campaign-reform/</guid>
      <description>September 5th (I know, I have really fallen behind my posts; bear with me, there is just too much going on to keep up) I attended a very interesting and enlightening round table at the New York City Bar Associationtitled &amp;ldquo;How Will Recent Developments in the Law Influence the 2012 Elections&amp;rdquo;?
Moderated by Nan Aron (lecturer, author, and President of Alliance for Justice), the panel consisted of:
 Angelo Falcón: President and Founder of the National Institute for Latino Policy Keesha Gaskins: Senior Counsel in the Brennan Center`s Democracy Program Lawrence Lessig: Professor of Law at Harvard University (and much more) John Samples: Director of the Cato Institute Center for Representative Government  The discussion was quite interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The second half of August</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/the-second-half-of-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 18:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/the-second-half-of-august/</guid>
      <description>August is over. What did the second half bring?
August 17th, after a lovely walk on the HighLine, Lytroorganized a photowalk on the Lower East Side (LES).
August 18th I had a nice talk about Russian art with the former Artistic Director of the State Russian Theater of Estonia, who is now working at the Lincoln Centerin New York.
August 19th morning I had another very interesting conversation with an NYU Philosophy professor regarding learning, engagement&amp;hellip; and reality, while having a delicious coconut ice cream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First half of August gone by</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/first-half-of-august-gone-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 17:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/first-half-of-august-gone-by/</guid>
      <description>Before more days go by and I forget the things I have been doing, here is a quick run-down for the first half of August (the last day of July I went to a Sigur Rós concert in Prospect Park):
August 1st I went to the MoMA to watch Hitchcock`s &amp;ldquo;To catch a thief&amp;rdquo; and eat at the nearby Le Pain Quotidien.
August 2nd, instead of taking advantage of the invitation to the Park Avenue Armory for the opening night party for Janet Cardiff &amp;amp; George Bures Miller: &amp;ldquo;The Murder of Crows&amp;rdquo;, I went to AlphaOne Labs for a 3D printing session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With Keanu Reeves and Chris Kenneally at &amp;quot;Side by side&amp;quot; premiere, MoMA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/with-keanu-reeves-and-chris-kenneally-at-quotside-by-sidequot-premiere-moma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 18:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/with-keanu-reeves-and-chris-kenneally-at-quotside-by-sidequot-premiere-moma/</guid>
      <description>The first one was the archiving and preservation of film. While an interesting debate by itself, it is not as important as it seemed to them, since, as I see it, technology will catch up and surpass the needs and expectations in a matter of very few years. Although a lot could be said about culture, preservation, archiving, formats, etc. Which leads us to&amp;hellip; The second one: it was a very brief moment, when upon the comment &amp;ldquo;somebody has to be the taste maker&amp;rdquo; by one of the producers being interviewed, Keanu, as interviewer said &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No unions admitted at the Intrepid Museum, NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/no-unions-admitted-at-the-intrepid-museum-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2012 13:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/no-unions-admitted-at-the-intrepid-museum-ny/</guid>
      <description>New York`s Intrepid Museum, new home of the Space Shuttle Enterprise, does not allow unions. You can see it (point number 13) in their &amp;ldquo;code of conduct&amp;rdquo;. WTF!!??
via Alvaro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My art projects and pictures</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/my-art-projects-and-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 10:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/my-art-projects-and-pictures/</guid>
      <description>For a few years I have accumulated art projects and pictures, in that oh-so-common delusion &amp;ldquo;one day I will start working on this and&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
Well, reality, resource constraints, day-to-day life&amp;hellip; are all excuses not to take ones passion and live it. So I am going to live it. How? I dont know. But the first step is to share, and to make accessible, my plans, ideas, and projects.
So HERE ARE MY ART PROJECTS (tumblr), and HERE ARE MY PHOTOGRAPHS (500px).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&amp;quot;All White Party&amp;quot; at the New Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/quotall-white-partyquot-at-the-new-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 10:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/quotall-white-partyquot-at-the-new-museum/</guid>
      <description>Five days ago, the New Museum invited me to the &amp;ldquo;All White Party&amp;rdquo;. It`s one of those events I would not normally go by myself, but Jane told me about the rooftop bar that only opens on weekends and during parties, so I decided to go and check it out. Plus, I was told it was the only chance I would have to see new yorkers dressed in white.
As it was to be expected, lot of people, quite a few &amp;ldquo;celebrities&amp;rdquo;, and 95% wearing white (with your typical &amp;ldquo;I am wearing black, to signal I am bad, or odd, or fun, or whatever&amp;rdquo;, two or three &amp;ldquo;ooops, I thought they were joking about the white – or I don`t have white clothes – and I am wearing my grey/orange shirt&amp;rdquo; and a petite blonde wearing black skirt and white top).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/july-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 00:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/july-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>Before I forget more (I am sure I am leaving out a lot), here is a little recap of things I`ve done, tried, or discovered in NY during July:
July 1st I went to Strand, my favorite bookstore, with its cool graffiti outside.
and then went to the &amp;ldquo;Exquisite Corpses: Drawing and Disfiguration&amp;rdquo; Party at the MoMA with Nebula.
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5761705319543704769]
The next day, in SoHo, I took a picture of this robot figure on my way to the gym.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun at Hackers On Planet Earth 9 – New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/fun-at-hackers-on-planet-earth-9-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 17:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/fun-at-hackers-on-planet-earth-9-new-york/</guid>
      <description>July 13th-15th Alvaro and I attended Hope9(Hackers On Planet Earth number 9) conference in New York`s Hotel Pennsylvania.
It was a lot of fun, as usual. Besides the many and informative talks(we gave one on &amp;ldquo;Digital Security in Health Care Institutions&amp;rdquo;, the first day), there was music, booths (FSF, EFFwith a girl that wanted to come to Spain to help the #indignados, Free Manning, No Starch PressBooks and more), arduino and lock-picking classes, a pro-ponies and against-zombies USA Presidential Candidate wearing a boot on his head, MakerBot3D printers, the IMMI, Hackers For Charity, AlphaOneHackerSpace (will be visiting it next Thursday with Audrey), StartUpHire, SparkleLabs(awesome presents for kids and n00bies!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incredible photo of last night`s &amp;quot;derecho&amp;quot; storm in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/incredible-photo-of-last-nights-quotderechoquot-storm-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 10:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/incredible-photo-of-last-nights-quotderechoquot-storm-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>Last night`s storm was, again, AMAZING. I was not exactly in a position to take a picture, &amp;ldquo;too concentrated on something else&amp;rdquo; (although I would have loved it), but this is a great shot by Ryan Brenizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting videos</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/interesting-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 22:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/interesting-videos/</guid>
      <description>Let me share some odd videos I have watched recently, thanks to Leaitrice and Patricia:
The famous &amp;quot;Sunscreen&amp;rdquo; music video(the text comes from an essaywritten in 1997 by Mary Schmich, a columnist at the Chicago Tribune, as a graduation speech for the class of `97) which gives some amazing advice for life. There is even a StarWars Version.
Drunk History: get some history students drunk, have them narrate historical events, while reenacting them&amp;hellip; more fun than it seems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazing storm in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/amazing-storm-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 18:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/amazing-storm-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>I have been under tropical storms several times in the jungle. But I have never seen anything like today`s storm over Manhattan. Absolutely incredible.The Guardian. Photo: Inga Sarda-Sorensen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay for Nebula`s new photobook</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/essay-for-nebulas-new-photobook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 13:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/essay-for-nebulas-new-photobook/</guid>
      <description>I have contributed an essay to the book (PDF soon available for free online, and for purchase in book format -a few sample images shown here-) of an exhibition I am curating. 3 years in the making, &amp;ldquo;Gaze, Reflexion, Fusion&amp;rdquo; is the highly poetical but politically charged work of one of the most interesting new photographers in the New York art scene: NEBULA.
From Tokyo to San Francisco, Madrid to Seoul, the Spanish photographer Nebula has traveled to 10 cities in 4 countries in order to find inspiration and the right images (somethimes a fleeting reflexion of it) to bring to life what she feels about art, identity, apropriationism, feminism, and psychoanalysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning bugs in Central Park instead of Oliver Stone debate</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/lightning-bugs-in-central-park-instead-of-oliver-stone-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 03:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/lightning-bugs-in-central-park-instead-of-oliver-stone-debate/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was invited to a member`s only screening of Born on the Fourth of July (1989) and post-screening discussion with Oliver Stone and Ron Kovic at MoMA Film Theater 1.
What do I do instead? I end up at Central Park, with lightning bugs around me. I think I am still there. For some reason, I have gotten trapped there, and I do not want to leave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two June weeks in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/two-june-weeks-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 17:06:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/two-june-weeks-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>In a sort of &amp;ldquo;NY diary&amp;rdquo;, here is what the last two weeks of June had in store for me.
 June 17th:  I went to Cha`Anin the heart of the East Village, for a very delicious tea ceremony. And it was delicious not just because of the great matcha tea (usucha) and wagashi, but also because Noriko-san was such an excellent host, performing an excellent otemae. Being a public restaurant, and not a private house, not everything was &amp;ldquo;perfect&amp;rdquo;, like in the tokonoma, where the scroll was obviously generic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 10th: Tea and Sympathy and Smörgås Chef</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/june-10th-tea-and-sympathy-and-sm%C3%B6rg%C3%A5s-chef/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 13:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/june-10th-tea-and-sympathy-and-sm%C3%B6rg%C3%A5s-chef/</guid>
      <description>Two places I tried June 10th in West Village:  Tea &amp;amp; Sympathy: UK charm (irony intended) and Tea+Scones, at high prices, minimum consumption ($11 per person!!), and they don`t even know how to serve tea (full pot, loose leaves&amp;hellip; no way to get them out to avoid over infusion of second cup). Avoid. Smörgås Chef: decent Scandinavian restaurant, with their own eco-farm.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun days, June 1st and 2nd</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/fun-days-june-1st-and-2nd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 12:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/fun-days-june-1st-and-2nd/</guid>
      <description>Trying to catch up with fun days, here is what June 1st looked like: first some crêpes for lunch at Vive La CrepeUnion Square (delicious crêpes and funny chair backs embedded in concrete).
Then, after browsing around at Beacons Closet&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, and going to &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.tibethouse.us/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.tibethouse.us/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Tibet House&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; to gather info (Tuesdays meditation classes, here I go), it was finally time to visit Rubin Museum of Art. While Modernist Art from India, Illuminated, and Casting the Divine were very interesting and delightful, I must admit the nerdy geek in me enjoyed Hero, Villain, Yeti like a real kid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering snow today at near 100ºF in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/remembering-snow-today-at-near-100%C2%BAf-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 12:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/remembering-snow-today-at-near-100%C2%BAf-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>Today, #HelloSummer, at almost 100ºF in NY, is a good day to remember the snow. I took this picture of a promo stunt May 31st at Times Square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYPL support and citizen budget involvement</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/nypl-support-and-citizen-budget-involvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 12:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/nypl-support-and-citizen-budget-involvement/</guid>
      <description>After supporting the NYPL efforts to fight back budget cuts, I have received a lovely message of thanks from Christine C. Quinn (Speaker, NYC Council), along with a very nice suggestion:
 Dear New Yorker, Many thanks for your email expressing your support for our city`s libraries. [&amp;hellip;]
We cant do it alone, though, and I hope youll consider signing up for Council &amp;ldquo;enews&amp;rdquo;. These issue-based e-mail updates are a great way for us to stay connected and engaged with you and other New Yorkers about the budget, healthcare, and other important issues affecting our city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with my new Lytro</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/playing-with-my-new-lytro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 18:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/playing-with-my-new-lytro/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I received my new Lytrocamera. Although it is an incredible technology, and allows things that were unthinkable until now, so far I am mixed.
Pros:
 Compact and discreet Extremely easy to use New ways of taking pictures Novelty Supercool &amp;ldquo;focus later&amp;rdquo;  Cons:
 You have to get used to a different way of thinking and framing a shot (square! and distance) Low performance under low light (although better than my crappy Samsung Galaxy IIS camera)  Check out this online gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brooklyn market, Tibetan restaurant and Japanese supermarket... in a day</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/brooklyn-market-tibetan-restaurant-and-japanese-supermarket...-in-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 18:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/brooklyn-market-tibetan-restaurant-and-japanese-supermarket...-in-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Saturday was one action packed day.
First, off to Brooklyn Flea Market(Fort Greene this time). Sure enough, the subway is a mess like any weekend, but one gets used to it. With a punishing sun, the first thing upon arrival is to hydrate (limenade, although I was tempted to try something they called &amp;ldquo;orchata&amp;rdquo; which was not, since it was made from coconut and rice), and eat something (palak dosa, and zucchini cheese pupusa&amp;hellip; I missed Mimi&amp;amp;CoCo‘s teriyaki balls or TheRegalVegantreats).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real strength</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/real-strength/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 17:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/real-strength/</guid>
      <description>As I head for the shower at the gym, wondering if I should stay longer on the bike, lift more weights, or try a new boxing class, I find the real meaning of strength lying right there in front of me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom of religion, freedom of expression, and public spaces</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/freedom-of-religion-freedom-of-expression-and-public-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 17:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/freedom-of-religion-freedom-of-expression-and-public-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Picture.
Question: why do I have to cross the street on my way home?
Debate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoHo (window)shopping</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/soho-windowshopping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 17:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/soho-windowshopping/</guid>
      <description>Some people enjoy shopping. Some enjoy the action, other the object, others the fantasy of being able to &amp;ldquo;acquire&amp;rdquo; that which they feel (or society made them feel) they &amp;ldquo;lack&amp;rdquo; (beauty, strength, appeal&amp;hellip; whatever).
Last week, while at the SoHo, I found myself enjoying window shopping. The design. Pure art. Beauty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Saturday: MET and Madison Sq. Park</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/last-saturday-met-and-madison-sq.-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 17:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/last-saturday-met-and-madison-sq.-park/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday I went to the MET for the symposium &amp;ldquo;Michelangelo and His World in the 1490s&amp;rdquo;. Presented by some of the most distinguished Michelangelo`s scholars, there was a lot of in-depth info on this very exceptional artist. Here are some of the most curious trivia I learned:
 He was an exceptional painter and art forger from a very early age (when he was 12 years old he forged and smoked to make it look old, church paintings) and that`s why his father enrolled in an art studio at 13, even though the minimum age was 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journalists covering FB IPO</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/journalists-covering-fb-ipo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 13:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/journalists-covering-fb-ipo/</guid>
      <description>May 18th, on my way to the subway, outside my office.
Look at the pictures. The making of the circus. Draw your own conclusions (and yes, the third one is a journalist on top of a wooden box to make her look taller).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Queens Museum of Art</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/queens-museum-of-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 13:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/queens-museum-of-art/</guid>
      <description>Last Thursday I went to Queens Museum of Art for a talk about NYFA Immigrant Art Project.
Besides interesting art, and an interesting (although basic) talk, here are some things that caught my attention (and yes, that IS a model of the park inside the elevator!): </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Monique Péan`s studio</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/in-monique-p%C3%A9ans-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 10:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/in-monique-p%C3%A9ans-studio/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday I went to the studio of jewelry designer Monique Péan, with Margot Norton (curatorial associate, New Museum, New York).
While it was interesting (in a &amp;ldquo;makes me sick but I need to learn this even if it seems impossible to achieve without the right connexions&amp;rdquo; forensics approach) to hear her perfectly polished &amp;ldquo;politically correct and marketing saavy&amp;rdquo; bio and artist statement, what really interested me was the striking beauty of fossilized ivory and minerals from the Artic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A conversation with Spanish Philosopher Fernando Sabater at Instituto Cervantes NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/a-conversation-with-spanish-philosopher-fernando-sabater-at-instituto-cervantes-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 13:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/a-conversation-with-spanish-philosopher-fernando-sabater-at-instituto-cervantes-ny/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday May 2nd, I had the pleasure to meet Fernando Sabaterat Instituto Cervantes, NY.
The conversation was lighthearted and included many anecdotes and trvia, but also a good dose of Philosophy and Psychology wisdom and aphorisms (like those by Andrés Newman). Here are some delicious quotes by him:
  Dont attack, dont comply Childhood is always bad: wether because it was bad and left you a trauma, or because it was good and it frustrates you to leave it behind Happyness is also hard to bear Skepticism grows, and thats why when I am about to make a statement (particularly if it is a grand one) I end up laughing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese dance at Japan Society and dinner at Sakagura</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/japanese-dance-at-japan-society-and-dinner-at-sakagura/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 12:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/japanese-dance-at-japan-society-and-dinner-at-sakagura/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went to Japan Society for the Kota Yamazaki/Fluid hug-hug (glowing)dance.
I must admit, regardless of having read the description and program, that I did not understand anything at all. Not even after hearing Kota Yamazaki explain his work after the show. So, I did the only thing a reasonable person can do when approaching art and not understanding: feel.
While the apparent lack of linear narrative or character identification makes it hard to approach, the dancers movements (rather than the much touted but ineffective light design), unobtrusive (and minimal) sound landscape by Kohji Setoh, and the elegant twist with the hanging wooden props becoming physical space at the end, played together surprisingly well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guggenheim curator tour and SVA computer arts</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/guggenheim-curator-tour-and-sva-computer-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 11:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/guggenheim-curator-tour-and-sva-computer-arts/</guid>
      <description>On Friday, at lunch time, I went to the Guggenheim to meet Susan Thompson, Curatorial Assistant, for a tour of Francesca Woodman exhibition.
Although Francesca Woodman`s photographs are undeniably subtle and portray the mind of a troubled young woman (body, space, self, disgust, identity, etc), it is a pity she took her life so early, leaving us with what is obviously a truncated body of work, one that begins, explores, promises&amp;hellip; but never concludes because death found her first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A conversation with Walt Mossberg and Kara Swisher at NYU</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/a-conversation-with-walt-mossberg-and-kara-swisher-at-nyu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 11:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/a-conversation-with-walt-mossberg-and-kara-swisher-at-nyu/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday I went to New York University for a nice conversation in the Inside the Internet Garageseries, with journalists Walt Mossberg and Kara Swisher (AllThingsDigital, Wall Street Journal, etc).
Besides the very interesting bio/background overview of them that the interviewer did, here are some quotes that caught my attention.
Walt Mossberg:
 IT departments are the most regressive force in tech, blocking new tech adoption
The story goes that Larry Page asked Steve Jobs for advice, he said &amp;ldquo;Find the 5 things you do best, and focus on it&amp;rdquo;, which its what hes doing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At MoMA: New Vision exhibition, The Modern restaurant, and a russian silent film about celebrities</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-moma-new-vision-exhibition-the-modern-restaurant-and-a-russian-silent-film-about-celebrities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 11:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-moma-new-vision-exhibition-the-modern-restaurant-and-a-russian-silent-film-about-celebrities/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday, given that the Anarchist Art Festival seemed a little weak, I decided to spend the day at the MoMA (Museum of Modern Art, New York).
First, a nice tour of &amp;ldquo;The Shaping of New Visions: Photography, Film, Photobook&amp;rdquo; exhibition (Edward Steichen Photography Galleries, third floor) by Dr. Elizabeth Cronin, assistant curator of photography at MoMA and NYPL. This exhibition, covering the period from 1910 to today, offers a critical reassessment of photographys role in the avant-garde and neo-avant-garde movements—with a special emphasis on the mediums relation to Dada, Bauhaus, Surrealism, Constructivism, New Objectivity, Conceptual, and Post-Conceptual art—and in the development of contemporary artistic practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A tour of selected pieces at MET Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/a-tour-of-selected-pieces-at-met-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 12:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/a-tour-of-selected-pieces-at-met-museum/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I went to the MET, and took a tour of their &amp;ldquo;highlights&amp;rdquo; with a curator, stopping at a few particularly interesting pieces in their collection. Here are some of them, and what makes them particularly interesting:
 In the Greek/Roman hall, the sculpture of fabric: while the greek sculptors portrayed the idealized human figure (even turning it into a mathematical formula) and the romans followed that tradition, fabric was the only part that was sculpted as it was, from thick to almost transparent, with embroidery, motifs, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The danger of graphs and cold data</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</guid>
      <description>After posting graphs and cold data (quite ilustrative, I believe), and the discussion it has generated (people, why don`t you use the &amp;ldquo;comment&amp;rdquo; instead all the other unstructured methods you are using?), please let me write a caveat about graphs and cold data.
In my high-tech gym, you have the option to have a lot of data collected, for your own, private and personal use. It seems like a great idea at first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC anarchist book fair</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/nyc-anarchist-book-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 13:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/nyc-anarchist-book-fair/</guid>
      <description>Since I could not get a hold of tickts for New Museum`s Seven on Seven, I decided to make the most out of my day yesterday (defying my cold), so I even had time to visit the NYC anarchist book fair, at Judson Church (Washington Square).
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5731668030633382577]
I wish I had had more time to devote to exploring all the literature (great and aweful) on display. But at least I had time to notice:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian film at MoMA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/russian-film-at-moma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 13:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/russian-film-at-moma/</guid>
      <description>After j-CATION and having lunch at Mr. Ks&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (one of the best Chinese restaurants in Manhattan), yesterday I went to &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.moma.org/visit/calendar/film_screenings/14846&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.moma.org/visit/calendar/film_screenings/14846&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;MoMA&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; Film to see Gosfilmofonds copy of the 1935 USSR film Loss of the Sensation (87 min.), directed by Aleksandr Andriyevsky.
Virtually unseen in the U.S., Andriyevskys liberal film version of Karel Capeks popular 1920 play, R.U.R. (in which the notion of robots was introduced), the movie tells the story of Jim Ripple, an engineer, who invents robots controlled by saxophones and radio signals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At Japan Society`s j-CATION 2012</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-japan-societys-j-cation-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 12:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-japan-societys-j-cation-2012/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday`s j-CATION(&amp;ldquo;Japan+Vacation&amp;rdquo;) festival at Japan Society was great fun: food (particularly delicious wagashi by Minamoto Kitchoan), live game-show (hosted by awesome Kenji America), workshops (shodo, block-stamping, origami, Japanese languaje basics, storytelling, games), movie, concert&amp;hellip;
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5731667869648627745]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Person of Interest filming around the corner</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/person-of-interest-filming-around-the-corner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 13:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/person-of-interest-filming-around-the-corner/</guid>
      <description>Today, as I headed to work, I exit my apartment, turn the corner onto 5th Ave. and see the film crew of Person of Interest. It doesn`t surprise me any more. Am I getting used to living in Manhattan?
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5730569373684857169]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At Deco Japan exhibit and excellent soba lunch (SEO)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-deco-japan-exhibit-and-excellent-soba-lunch-seo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 16:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-deco-japan-exhibit-and-excellent-soba-lunch-seo/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, since I had to go to the Japan Society to take care of some business, I took the opportunity to visit the Deco Japan: Shaping Art and Culture, 1920–1945 exhibition (I was invited to the opening, but I could not make it that day).
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5730180317126910177]
 Curated by Dr. Kendall Brown, Deco Japan: Shaping Art and Culture, 1920–1945 subtly conveys the complex social and cultural tensions in Japan during the Taisho and early Showa periods through dramatically designed examples of metalwork, ceramics, lacquer, glass, furniture, jewelry, sculpture and evocative ephemera such as sheet music, posters, postcards, prints and photography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social-media inspired cocktails at Mandarin Oriental NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/social-media-inspired-cocktails-at-mandarin-oriental-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 11:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/social-media-inspired-cocktails-at-mandarin-oriental-ny/</guid>
      <description>seen in Tumblr (user: hragv)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curators` thoughts</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/curators-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 00:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/curators-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>On September 28, 2011, Hou Hanru, Director of Exhibitions and Public Programs at the San Francisco Art Institute said on a lecture (Curator`s Perspective) in New York:
 I think the worst exhibition in the world is the exhibition that is organized like a book. We see this a lot, an exhibition that takes the artwork as an illustration of a concept. I think an exhibition is not necessary for this: frankly, it`s too expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marvel Marathon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/marvel-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 23:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/marvel-marathon/</guid>
      <description>From the #thisIsHowItsDone (not the movie adaptations, but special events to make people go more to the movie theaters) department, here is an awesome initiative from AMC movie theaters:
Get ready to watch the greatest Marvel movie event ever held at your local AMC Theatre on May 3rd! Experience THE ULTIMATE MARVEL MARATHON with six movies on one epic day. Watch the heroes’ stories unfold as they assemble for the midnight premiere of The Avengers 3D!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tatsumi at the MoMA Film</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/tatsumi-at-the-moma-film/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 23:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/tatsumi-at-the-moma-film/</guid>
      <description>Tonight I went and see Tatsumiat the MoMA Film (Theater 2), a 2011 animation film from Singapore, directed by Eric Khoo, with the voice of Yoshihiro Tatsumi (who brought innovation to Japanese comics through works of social commentary aimed at an adult audience in postwar Japan in the late 1950s). A Drifting Life, Tatsumi’s epic graphic novel memoir, forms the foundation for the film.
Interesting the unavoidable paralel one can draw between Italys neorealism postwar cinema and Tatsumis works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversation with a Curator and Dawn of Egyptian Art at the MET</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/conversation-with-a-curator-and-dawn-of-egyptian-art-at-the-met/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 22:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/conversation-with-a-curator-and-dawn-of-egyptian-art-at-the-met/</guid>
      <description>This morning I have been at the MET. First I took advantage of the invitation to preview the Dawn of Egyptian Artexhibition which will be on display April 10–August 5, 2012.
While there were many remarkable pieces (for several reasons) in the exhibition, this coyote figure completely captivated me. The legs position denote movement, which is uncommon in animal depictions of the later eras. The reason being that as art evolved, and became &amp;quot;institutionalized&amp;quot; in Ancient Egypt, it adhered more closely to standards and canons, loosing some if the earlier works creativity and freedom, such as this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the MoMA member gallery talk: Cindy Sherman</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-the-moma-member-gallery-talk-cindy-sherman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 17:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-the-moma-member-gallery-talk-cindy-sherman/</guid>
      <description>Today I went to one of MoMA`s members-only gallery talks. This one was about their currentCindy Shermanexhibition(great website, by the way).
Rather than rambling on about Cindy Sherman`s interesting work (an obvious reference to identity, stereotypes, social criticism, art depiction, etc, with her easily recognizable periods and themes), on which there are many articlesthese days, here are some anecdotes:
 Photography is not allowed (I really hate it when museums do not allow photography), so why do they place QRs (particularly when the phone coverage is quite bad)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the Independent Art Spaces Symposium and Art Spaces Directory Launch</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-the-independent-art-spaces-symposium-and-art-spaces-directory-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 14:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-the-independent-art-spaces-symposium-and-art-spaces-directory-launch/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I went to the Independent Art Spaces Symposium and Art Spaces Directory Launchat the New Museum.
I purchased the Art Spaces Directory last week, and I believe it is an excellent work, useful informative, needed. But the symposium was&amp;hellip; sad, to say the least: a bunch of gallery (art-spaces) curators, unable to play a PowerPoint (sic&amp;hellip; makes me sick), and regurgitating exhibit picture after exhibit picture while vomiting names after names of artists, collectives and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the best tea ceremony place in NY: Cha-An</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-the-best-tea-ceremony-place-in-ny-cha-an/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 14:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-the-best-tea-ceremony-place-in-ny-cha-an/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I went to Cha-an. In short: a cute japanese restaurant, good food, excellent desserts, and what seems to be the best Japanese Tea Ceremony in NY (ate there, but will have to do the ceremony some other day). Definitely to the &amp;ldquo;must&amp;rdquo; list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visit to the Madeline Weinrib studio</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/visit-to-the-madeline-weinrib-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 12:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/visit-to-the-madeline-weinrib-studio/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday I visited the studio of Madeline Weinribon 5th Ave., New York.
Located on an impressive loft, her new studio (it used to be located at her apartment above a small museum in SoHo) is, as one would have imagined, full of decorative and inspirational elements, plus lots and lots of fabric samples, books and pictures.
In an informal conversation, Madeline explained her move from painter to fabric designer in 1997 (although she &amp;ldquo;forgot&amp;rdquo; to mention the connexion to her great-grandfather`s company), her world-wide network of artisans and suppliers, and her obvious historical design pattern &amp;ldquo;inspirations&amp;rdquo; (curious how she considers large manufacturers are &amp;ldquo;ripping her off&amp;rdquo; by copying &amp;ldquo;her patterns&amp;rdquo;, when her work is such an obvious &amp;ldquo;appropriation&amp;rdquo; from well known historical-cultural patterns such as the zig-zag or the muslim interlocks, as she describes it in this interview).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madison Square Garden: the LArc~en~Ciel concert</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/madison-square-garden-the-larc~en~ciel-concert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 23:16:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/madison-square-garden-the-larc~en~ciel-concert/</guid>
      <description>The Japan Society invited me to L`Arc~en~Cielconcert at the Madison Square Gardenlast night, so there I went.
L`Arc~en~Cielis a Japanese rock band formed in 1991 in Osaka. The group has sold over 13 million albums, and 16 million singles. Currently on a world tour (obviously last night in NY), their upcoming London and Jakarta concerts are already sold out, and their NY concert was bigger than expected.
Given their JPop-rock sound, no wonder the Madison Square Garden was almost fully packed with Japanese, although there were more than teenagers, like the &amp;ldquo;respectable moms&amp;rdquo; in their 50s, 3 rows ahead of me, who could not stop swinging and laughing and singing, or the guy next to me, there with his wife, who waited patiently for the concert to start while reading manga in his iPad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soba from a master: Soba Totto`s Shuichi Kotani</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/soba-from-a-master-soba-tottos-shuichi-kotani/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 12:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/soba-from-a-master-soba-tottos-shuichi-kotani/</guid>
      <description>Last night, after the MoMA party, I went to have dinner at Soba Totto.
It`s great that NY has so many excellent Japanese restaurants. This was no exception. Kotani sensei is a true master in the ancient art of soba making:More videos here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MoMA members night party and the economy of access as identity</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-moma-members-night-party-and-the-economy-of-access-as-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 11:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-moma-members-night-party-and-the-economy-of-access-as-identity/</guid>
      <description>Last night I attended the members night party at the Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) in New York.
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5723677090335639153]
The &amp;ldquo;party&amp;rdquo; was, as most &amp;ldquo;parties&amp;rdquo; in the USA: drinks, and people. Thats basically it. The music was soft enough that it was barely perceivable (unlike the New Museums party, where DJs try to make it impossible to talk to the person next to you).
So, why all the fuss? Why go to a &amp;ldquo;party&amp;rdquo; that has basically nothing to offer in terms of &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At a WhiteBox NY exhibition closing party</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/at-a-whitebox-ny-exhibition-closing-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 15:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/at-a-whitebox-ny-exhibition-closing-party/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I attended WhiteBox`s exhibition closing party. The invitation said:
 Author and curator Raul Zamudioin conversation with Mookie Tenembaum.
Please join us at White Boxfor the closing reception of DISILLUSIONISM, and to engage in a stimulating conversation between Raul Zamudio and Mookie Tenembaum at 8pm sharp. Mookie will be presenting his new artist book, Paranoia. Malbec wines and truffles will be served.
 Although I am grateful for the invitation, and it sure was an interesting event, some things just beg to be commented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whitney Biennial 2012</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/whitney-biennial-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 23:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/whitney-biennial-2012/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday evening I attended the Whitney Museum of American Contemporary Art`s Biennial 2012exhibition. I had lunchin a hurry, worried that I would not have time to visit the whole exhibition (since I only had a few hours). How wrong I was. Let`s just say it was sooooo disappointing(at least for someone, like me, who knows almost nothing about art), that I was left with a feeling of wonder. Not about the works, but how, who, and why, did they decide to include it in the exhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel discussion about art collecting at Asia Society</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/panel-discussion-about-art-collecting-at-asia-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 22:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/panel-discussion-about-art-collecting-at-asia-society/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday morning I went to the Asia Society for a panel discussiontitled: &amp;ldquo;The Future of the Past – Collecting Ancient Art in the 21st Century&amp;rdquo; presented by the American Committee for Cultural Policyin conjunction with Asia Week. The panelists included:
 Naman Ahuja, Professor of Indian Art and Architecture, Jawaharlal Nehru University, Delhi, India Kate Fitz Gibbon, attorney and author, former member of the Cultural Property Advisory Committee to the President Kurt A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Museum curators talk</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/new-museum-curators-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 18:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/new-museum-curators-talk/</guid>
      <description>Saturday evening I went to the talk_Independent Curators International and the New Museum present The Curators Perspective: Rosina Cazali_. Although there was an interesting &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.sothebys.com/en/auctions/2012/fine-classical-chinese-paintings-n08835/exhibitions.html&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.sothebys.com/en/auctions/2012/fine-classical-chinese-paintings-n08835/exhibitions.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;talk at Sothebystitled &amp;ldquo;_Masters of the Ming and Qing: Chinese Paintings and Calligraphy at Sothebys_&amp;quot; by Arnold Chang, before their Fine Classical Chinese Paintings exhibition and auction. I dont know how the Sotheby`s lecture went, but here is what I saw and heard at the New Museum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards an oversimplification cliff: when green=drunks</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/towards-an-oversimplification-cliff-when-greendrunks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 18:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/towards-an-oversimplification-cliff-when-greendrunks/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday morning, as I was walking towards the gym on Park Avenue, I saw waves of young adults (although acting like teenagers or frat boys) wearing green (some just a t-shirt or sweater, some a full leprechaun costume) on a procession towards their favorite Irish watering hole to &amp;ldquo;celebrate&amp;rdquo; St. Patricks Day in the only way that they seem to believe to be appropriate, besides a 5th Ave. official parade: drink until you pass out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The problem with encyclopedic approach to teaching: lecture at MET</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-problem-with-encyclopedic-approach-to-teaching-lecture-at-met/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-problem-with-encyclopedic-approach-to-teaching-lecture-at-met/</guid>
      <description>Friday I attended the Annual Lecture on the Arts of South and Southeast Asia at the NY Metropolitan Museum of Art (MET), delivered by Crispin Branfoot, School of Oriental and African Studies, University of London. His lecturewas titled: &amp;ldquo;Making Madurai: Temple Arts in Early Modern South India&amp;rdquo;.
Dr. Branfoot is, I am sure, a world renowned expert, and the MET has some wonderful education programs. And this one in particular was filled to capacity, such that I had to watch it from an adjacent &amp;ldquo;study room&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real convergence</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/real-convergence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 05:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/real-convergence/</guid>
      <description>Reading RSS on my smartphone, click on a YouTube video, send it to the computer via Phone2Chrome&amp;hellip;
I read on a newspaper tablet version that TED is now on Netflix, turn on the Google TV Logitech Revue with Able Remote on my phone and start Netflix, adding TED to my Instant Que&amp;hellip;
Remember all that &amp;ldquo;convergence&amp;rdquo; talk?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luch in office cafeteria terrace</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/luch-in-office-cafeteria-terrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 15:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/luch-in-office-cafeteria-terrace/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LES Gallery walk and Volta NY 2012</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/les-gallery-walk-and-volta-ny-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 20:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/les-gallery-walk-and-volta-ny-2012/</guid>
      <description>So, Sunday came and my feet were already trembling scared in anticipation of another art overdose. Let`s go!
I spent the morning walking around some of Manhattans Lower East Side (LES) galleries with artist &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://leewells.org/home/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://leewells.org/home/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Lee Wells&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. We visited &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.roostergallery.com/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.roostergallery.com/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Rooster Gallery&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.anastasia-photo.com/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.anastasia-photo.com/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Anastasia Photo&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://bridgegalleryny.com/home.html&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://bridgegalleryny.com/home.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Bridge Gallery&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.maysongallery.com/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.maysongallery.com/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Mayson Gallery&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://lesleyheller.com/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://lesleyheller.com/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Lesley Heller Workspace&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, and &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.scaramoucheart.com/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armory Art Show 2012 NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/armory-art-show-2012-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 19:28:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/armory-art-show-2012-ny/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday I went to The Armory Show 2012. So many galleries, so little time. While everybody was talking about Marina Abramovic’s _Bed for Human Use _performance, Theaster Gates commissioned Pier 94 café piece, or Michael Riedel’s installation at New York’s David Zwirner’s booth (forget about the Nordic spaces)... I found other works much much more interesting. But thats what makes art`s subjectivity (apparently not so subjective) so appealing.
Although, for the first time I found myself (and was ment to be that way) inside a piece of exhibited art by Michelangelo Pistolettoat Galleria Continua‘s booth (I am not showing it here because it will soon be published in a book).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subway hell on the way to a meeting</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/subway-hell-on-the-way-to-a-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 15:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/subway-hell-on-the-way-to-a-meeting/</guid>
      <description>On Friday morning I had a meeting, so I took the 1 Subway line to 168th St. [mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5718647890686730977]
Given, the station was not the coolest in NY, but what shocked me was that at the other end of the platform, there was a man on the floor, and people just passed by as if nobody was there.
So I crossed to the other side, and asked him if he needed help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art at MAD NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/art-at-mad-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 15:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/art-at-mad-ny/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I went to the New York Museum of Arts and Design (MAD). Honestly, I wasn`t expecting much, but&amp;hellip; on the contrary, what a nice surprise!
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5718498290671972801]
From Japanese exquisite design and art (subtle, delicate, and sensitive beauty that never ceases to soothe your soul) in &amp;ldquo;Beauty in all things&amp;rdquo;, to the awesomely curated &amp;ldquo;Swept Away: Dust, Ashes, and Dirt in Contemporary Art and Design&amp;rdquo;, to the amazing &amp;ldquo;Glasstress New York&amp;rdquo;, the whole museum was a joy to visit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ungovernables party at New Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-ungovernables-party-at-new-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 19:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-ungovernables-party-at-new-museum/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was invited to The UngovernablesTriennial leap year cocktail by-invitation-only party at the New Museum.
After a long line on the street, under the rain and cold wind (no wonder I have a cold now), the party started at 7:30pm in the main lobby: DJ, cocktails, and fluorescent rubber bands for a crowd eager to see and be seen.
Not one to particularly enjoy mingling and parties, I went upstairs to see the exhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At MoMA PS1 for K-HOLE2 Release</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/at-moma-ps1-for-k-hole2-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 01:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/at-moma-ps1-for-k-hole2-release/</guid>
      <description>Today I was invited tothe MoMA PS1 for K-HOLE#2 Release. Young people, &amp;ldquo;Brooklyn artsy&amp;rdquo;, holding beers and beards, with the careless attitude that the PS1 requires: either I dont get it or I do, but in any case, it wont show.
There were many works on display, too many (and too complex or infuriatingly simple) to comment here. What was definitely not worth mentioning, from my ignorant point of view, was the Alterazioni Video &amp;ldquo;The New Cinema Event&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Art in NY: from hairdressing to butoh</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/japanese-art-in-ny-from-hairdressing-to-butoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 01:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/japanese-art-in-ny-from-hairdressing-to-butoh/</guid>
      <description>New York is full of Japanese art, and I am not only referring to the Asia Week NYor the architecture (New Museums SANAA, MoMAs Yoshio Taniguchi, Japan Societys Junzo Yoshimura…), interior design (Megus Yasumichi Morita, Morimotos Tadao Ando, Louis Vuittons Jyun Aoki…), sculpture (Red Cube`s Isamu Noguchi…), art collections (MET, MoMA, Japan Society, Morgan, Rubin…), food (Yasuda, Kajitsu, Minamoto Kichoan…), or shops (Makari, Toy Tokyo, JCC…).
Yesterday I had a chance to see two rare forms of Japanese art in NY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Visa odyssey</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/a-visa-odyssey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 23:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/a-visa-odyssey/</guid>
      <description>This is the story of an L1 Visa. I will try to make it short, although some details have to be explained to be believed&amp;hellip;
In August of 2011 I thought of starting a US subsidiary of my software company in the USA, so I decided to move to New York to start it up and manage it. Since I needed a visa (form I-129) to live and work in the USA, I contacted an immigration lawyer (form G-28 and thousands of dollars) through a friend, and we started the whole process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypocritical and absurd visa questions</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/hypocritical-and-absurd-visa-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 07:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/hypocritical-and-absurd-visa-questions/</guid>
      <description>Some hypocritical and absurd questions found in the DS-160 form, needed to get a US Visa:
 Do you have a mental or physical disorder that poses or is likely to pose a threat to the safety or welfare of yourself or others? Are you or have you ever been a drug abuser or addict? Have you ever violated, or engaged in a conspiracy to violate, any law relating to controlled substances?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The smallest art gallery in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/the-smallest-art-gallery-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 05:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/the-smallest-art-gallery-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>This morning I walked by the smallest art gallery in NY, 125windowgallery, on 47th between 3rd and Lexington Avenue:
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,111219615350942087056,1,64c,center]
The best thing about that gallery is that you do not need to &amp;ldquo;go in&amp;rdquo; 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almodovar and SGAE force cancellation of film screenings at NY Library</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/almodovar-and-sgae-force-cancellation-of-film-screenings-at-ny-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 17:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/almodovar-and-sgae-force-cancellation-of-film-screenings-at-ny-library/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went to the New York Public Library to see Pedro Almodovars &amp;quot;Talk to her&amp;quot;, as part of a &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.nypl.org/blog/2011/12/06/films-pedro-almodovar&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.nypl.org/blog/2011/12/06/films-pedro-almodovar&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;series&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; of Almodovars films screenings in the NYPL. But, to my surprise, the screening (and remainder ones) had been cancelled.
I talked to the person in the information desk, and she told me that the collecting society (that would be the despicable SGAE, which does not even deserve a link in my blog) and Almodovar`s Production company (El Deseo Producciones) had raised what they had previously been asking for as royalties or compensation for the (free) screening of the (not in movie theater) films, and the amount they were now asking was so high, the NYPL could not afford it, so they had to cancel the screenings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disappearing Chrysler and &amp;quot;Spanish&amp;quot; Empire State</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/disappearing-chrysler-and-quotspanishquot-empire-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/disappearing-chrysler-and-quotspanishquot-empire-state/</guid>
      <description>Excuse to try a new photo plug-in for WP:
First photo: the Chrysler building as seen from my living room window.
Second photo: same thing on a foggy day&amp;hellip; Building gone! (no Image Editing here).
Third photo: the Empire State Building, from the living room, decorated with &amp;ldquo;Spanish flags colors&amp;rdquo;
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5703177154854937889]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The parks of the future</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-parks-of-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 22:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-parks-of-the-future/</guid>
      <description>Is this what the parks of the future will look like?“Bird,” by Jacco Olivier, one of six animation installations on display in Madison Square Park, New YorkIt will be, if we do not do something about it now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArtHack Exhibit closing party in Brooklyn</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 22:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday I went to the ArtHack Exhibitclosing party at 319 ScholesSt, Brooklyn (New York).
Located in an industrial complex in Brooklyn, at night, loooong two blocks from the subway, graffiti all over, small door&amp;hellip; that gave way to heaven: young (I was the oldest hacker in that space, but I did not feel that way) energetic happy people tinkering with technology and proudly showing their &amp;ldquo;toys&amp;rdquo; (hacks, mashups, creations, or whatever).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antony and the Johnsons at Radio City Music Hall... indescribable</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/antony-and-the-johnsons-at-radio-city-music-hall...-indescribable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 16:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/antony-and-the-johnsons-at-radio-city-music-hall...-indescribable/</guid>
      <description>Antony and the Johnsonsperformed last Thursday 26th, at the Radio City Music HallSWANLIGHTS, a one-night-only performance commissioned by the Museum of Modern Art (MoMA), NY, the most amazing concert I have ever been to.
One would think that the fact that the performance took place in the world`s largest (and one of the most reputed) theater/music venue, or that the place was chock-full of celebrities (I had Björk right next to me in the line to pick up the reserved tickets), would add to the glamour and grandiose of the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic reactions: Twitter censorship, Google campaign, and magenta trade-marked</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/automatic-reactions-twitter-censorship-google-campaign-and-magenta-trade-marked/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 15:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/automatic-reactions-twitter-censorship-google-campaign-and-magenta-trade-marked/</guid>
      <description>The net was all up in arms this week. After the marvelous uprising against SOPA and PIPA, the new battle ground was Twitter`s announcement of country specific censorship. Never mind that they are open about it (unlike Facebook), never mind that they are talking about their offices and employees in those countries where censorship is the law&amp;hellip; if you hear &amp;ldquo;censorship&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;net&amp;rdquo; get up and scream! Wired has a nice pieceabout it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of context in the interpretation (and enjoyment) of a work of art</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-importance-of-context-in-the-interpretation-and-enjoyment-of-a-work-of-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 01:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-importance-of-context-in-the-interpretation-and-enjoyment-of-a-work-of-art/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went to 3 exhibitions/events that have allowed me to see the importance of context in the interpretation (and enjoyment) of a work of art. Note that I differentiate &amp;ldquo;interpretation&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;enjoyment&amp;rdquo;, although for many of us, those two concepts go hand in hand. But this is just a short post, so the Phenomenological Aesthetics will have to wait (you can read Dewey, Hartmann, Adorno, Ortega y Gasset, Sartre, etc, etc in the meantime 😉 )</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first Kendo class</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/my-first-kendo-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 20:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/my-first-kendo-class/</guid>
      <description>My shoulders and back still hurt, but it was previsible: one hour of Kendo with Ilaria Montagnani (Nike endorsed athlete, and one of the top trainers in NY according to the Wall Street Journal or New York Magazine), and you will not ever wonder how she got all those muscles in her body.
For some odd reason, Kendo feels natural to me. And I say odd, because I am usually lacking the required coordination and flexibility for almost any sport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It`s finally snowing... upwards!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/its-finally-snowing...-upwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 19:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/its-finally-snowing...-upwards/</guid>
      <description>When the wind and cold/warm air currents collide while snowing, you get the funny &amp;ldquo;snowing upwards&amp;rdquo; effect (and sideways also, of course). The 5ºF &amp;ldquo;real feel&amp;rdquo; is not so funny though 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEDxManhattan: Changing the way we eat</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/tedxmanhattan-changing-the-way-we-eat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 16:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/tedxmanhattan-changing-the-way-we-eat/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow, January 21st, 2012, NY</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Zen ad making me sick</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/anti-zen-ad-making-me-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 10:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/anti-zen-ad-making-me-sick/</guid>
      <description>As I walk towards my office, I see an ad that makes me sick (as a matter of fact, I see many, but this one points to something other that the consumerism-sexism-excess that we are so dangerously getting used to).
The ad says &amp;ldquo;Turn now into memories&amp;rdquo;. How wrong is that?!!
Now is now. Now has to be now. Now should be now. Now has to remain now.
When you strive to &amp;ldquo;turn now into memories&amp;rdquo;, you are missing out on the real now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When what the artist intended is distorted by the gallery`s limitations</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/when-what-the-artist-intended-is-distorted-by-the-gallerys-limitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 19:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/when-what-the-artist-intended-is-distorted-by-the-gallerys-limitations/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, along a MeetUp group, we visited several art galleries in Chelsea (NY): Mike Weiss Gallery, Gladstone Gallery, Luhring Augustine Gallery, Metro Pictures Gallery, The Pace Gallery, and Mary Boone Gallery.
Leaving my personal comments on the displayed works aside (as usual, the pleasure of this kind of pilgrimage is to leave your mind and senses open, and let the works and stimuli slowly sink in), one thing surprised me quite a lot: Ai Wei Wei‘s work Sunflower Seeds was supposed to be walked on (at least it did at the Tate Modern in London, for the first 10 days of the exhibit), but at Mary Boone Gallerythere is a security guard that prevents visitors from doing exactly what the artist intended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How &amp;quot;RealFeel&amp;quot; works</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/how-quotrealfeelquot-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 19:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/how-quotrealfeelquot-works/</guid>
      <description>AccuWeatherhas an interesting system called RealFeel. For example, today is 22ºF, but when you step outside, you cant help scream &amp;quot;Shit, its cold!&amp;rdquo;. Accourding to the AccuWeathers RealFeel system (which I assume &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.experts123.com/q/how-does-the-patented-accuweather-realfeel-temperature-work.html&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.experts123.com/q/how-does-the-patented-accuweather-realfeel-temperature-work.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;takes into account more than just humidity&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, like wind), it feels like 10ºF. What it does not take into account is if you forgot your hat, scarf, or gloves (then you are lost, even if you wear UniQlos HeatTech undies) 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A man falls, two walk over him</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/a-man-falls-two-walk-over-him/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 20:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/a-man-falls-two-walk-over-him/</guid>
      <description>Today, at the gym`s lobby/reception area, a man was sitting waiting for his wife to come out of yoga class. When she does, he gets up to greet her, feels dizzy, and passes out, falling to the ground, and hitting his face on the floor.
Two men who were on their way out, walk over this man. They do not bother-care-ask what`s wrong. They do not offer assistance.
Finally, his wife (who witnessed the whole episode, paralyzed in fear) reacts, wakes him up, and makes sure his eye socket bleeding is not too profuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seen in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/seen-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 19:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/seen-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>Random things seen in NY this past week:
A &amp;ldquo;horsehead&amp;rdquo; in the NY subway. What I love (and sometimes hate) about NY: nobody turned, laughed, commented, got scared, pointed a finger&amp;hellip; this is life as usual here.
&amp;ldquo;The Crazy Piano Guy&amp;rdquo; is Colin Huggins, a piano player that takes his piano to Madison Square Park and performs in public for free. Awesome.
Not only the latest Ferrari, Maserati&amp;hellip; once in a while you get to see cool vehicles as well 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bella Gaia concert</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/bella-gaia-concert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 22:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/bella-gaia-concert/</guid>
      <description>Mickey Hart, Dar Williams, Bella Gaia(AWESOME), &amp;amp; The Abrams Brothers(country/folk/rock energetic brothers&amp;hellip; that violin was smoking! loved it) concert at Highline Ballroom.
Cool mix of music, dance and infographic visuals with eco message. Highly recommended (even the veggie burger was good!).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first boxing session with Curtis Summit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/my-first-boxing-session-with-curtis-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 04:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/my-first-boxing-session-with-curtis-summit/</guid>
      <description>Although I like more &amp;ldquo;spiritual&amp;rdquo; martial arts, I had always wanted to try boxing (one of the few martial arts I had not tried yet). So today I had my first boxing session with Curtis Summit. Who is Curtis? This is his official short bio:
 Former professional boxer with 20 years of boxing experience who turned Pro in 1983 after advancing to the 1984 Olympics box off. With 26-9-2 pro records, 14TKOs on the national and international level, ranked No 2 in the world by the World Boxing Council, the World Boxing Association and the International Boxing Federation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culinary curiosities in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/culinary-curiosities-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 05:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/culinary-curiosities-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>In Dean &amp;amp; Delucayou can find the most exquisite culinary treats (most from Europe, of course). And while there are so many to choose from a foodie like me could not make his mind up in a hundred years, I must admit the cuteness of this snowman-cake won me over:
On the other hand, even when one sticks to very healthy vegetarian (mostly vegan, sometimes macrobiotic, but always with the exception of sushi) diet, it seems impossible to scape the &amp;ldquo;over-spiced&amp;rdquo; cooking in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Years Eve party at Iridium and Times Square</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/new-years-eve-party-at-iridium-and-times-square/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 02:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/new-years-eve-party-at-iridium-and-times-square/</guid>
      <description>Of course, the first year living in NY, new year`s eve party HAD to include a peregrination to Times Square. And since we had tickets to the Iridium concert(the Mike Stern Band featuring Randy Brecker, John Patitucci &amp;amp; Dave Weckl), we figured we would get a taste of it taking the subway to 42nd/Times Square (since police closed the nearer 50th st station)&amp;hellip; and did we indeed!!
The Broadway/42nd intersection was incredibly packed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geek gifts</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/geek-gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 19:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/geek-gifts/</guid>
      <description>I hate to give in on the Xmas-Santa-Market craze. That`s why I have waited until after the 25th to offer you these hints:
 Giftmeister(interactive suggestions) Uncrate(random ideas) Mugs(it does not take so much to make a geek happy, does it?) Online stores (ThinkGeek, XtremeGeek, IWantOneOfThose, MakerSHED&amp;hellip;) BrickAndMortar stores (Robot Village, the Wired Store&amp;hellip; right across the street from the office!)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond work: first days in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/beyond-work-first-days-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2011 01:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/beyond-work-first-days-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>To go to my officein Times Square by subway is an adventure in itself, not due to the intense exercise of avoiding waves of pedestrians, but from the very fascinating tunnels (there is a world down there of abandoned stations, marginal dwellers, and those things nobody talks about)
to what one can find in the stations themselves: music(from the saw lady, to YouBredRaptors), promotions (from an armored vehicle at the Army recruiting station at 42nd, to the Sesame Street characters wishing you happy holidays)&amp;hellip;anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga Guru uses copyright to sue competitor</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 19:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</guid>
      <description>Ego, money, power, abuse, restriction&amp;hellip; shame on those who stain the &amp;ldquo;holy&amp;rdquo; teachings.
Source: NYT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art gallery inaugurations</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/art-gallery-inaugurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 23:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/art-gallery-inaugurations/</guid>
      <description>Tonight we went to the MaysonGallery inaugural inauguration &amp;ldquo;Launch&amp;rdquo; featuring works by Doug Henders, Scott Hewett, Michael Oatman, Jeff Quinn, Bastienne Schmidt, and Rodger Stevens. It was way too crowded to see the works, but it was fun. Particularly because we enjoyed dinner at almost next door JinJapanese restaurant.
But we wish we were at another art inauguration: IVAM`s Claudio Zirotti.
My dear friend and mentor presents &amp;ldquo;Without Time&amp;rdquo; (PDF), an excellent exhibit of his wonderful art at Valencia`s IVAM Modern Art Institute, until February 19th 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International teahouse office</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/international-teahouse-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 18:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/international-teahouse-office/</guid>
      <description>Pretty amazing: I am putting out fires with a customer in Colombia, with the help of an engineer in Japan, coordinated with the headquarters in Spain&amp;hellip; while sipping on a coconut white bubble tea at ArgoUnion Square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying to Rio with a character</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/flying-to-rio-with-a-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 10:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/flying-to-rio-with-a-character/</guid>
      <description>After arriving in JFK in the most predictable way (rain, snow, traffic or whatever) which is the combo E line + AirTrain, and boarding on a &amp;ldquo;last call&amp;rdquo; although I arrived early enough (due to the never-ending security lines, and the abnormal amount of passengers with special needs such as many small children in strollers, large hand-luggage, senior citizens, etc) I finally arrive at my seat on the flight New York – Rio de Janeiro, and I see it is occupied by… Rolls Royce car keys, with a Rolls Royce keyring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you see here...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-do-you-see-here.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 12:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-do-you-see-here.../</guid>
      <description>A green PacMan The market size you want to conquer Your shrinking market size Food to eat Food eaten A green tea – coconut – ginger vegan cake A memory A moment Enjoyment  &amp;hellip;
Does this post start to sound like an HSBC ad? I spend too much time in airports!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Thanksgiving where no being suffers</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/a-thanksgiving-where-no-being-suffers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 04:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/a-thanksgiving-where-no-being-suffers/</guid>
      <description>Vegan Korean teahouse and restaurant Franchia. And leave turkeys alone.

PS: This morning I missed Macy`s Thanksgiving Paradebecause I miscalculated the angle. From my living room, the Empire State Building blocks the view, and from the sun deck (50th floor), being 2 streets to the East and 5 to the South made the viewing impossible. Next year, better to go to Central Park in the morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NY healthy restaurants</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/ny-healthy-restaurants/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 22:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/ny-healthy-restaurants/</guid>
      <description>Breakfast: Au Bon Pain, Le Pain Quotidien, and Europa Cafe.
October 9th
 Greek restaurant Molyvos  October 10th
 PeaceBar Candle Cafe  October 11th
 Indian restaurant Sapphire Gobo  October 12th
 Caravan of Dreams Souen Organic Macrobiotic(Union Square)  October 13th
 Angelica`s Kitchen Trattoria dell`Arte  October 14th
 Zen Palate Baltazar  October 15th
 Villagenatural Mana  October 16th
 Bonobo Back to Souen Organic Macrobiotic(this time 28 East 13th St)  October 17th</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The odyssey of renting an apartment and offices in NY: mission accomplished</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/the-odyssey-of-renting-an-apartment-and-offices-in-ny-mission-accomplished/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 14:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/the-odyssey-of-renting-an-apartment-and-offices-in-ny-mission-accomplished/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday October 9th we went to NY. Travel went smoothly and without anecdotes. We arrived, left things in the hotel(with its spectacular penthouse lounge that we had no time to visit) and we went for dinner (all the restaurants visited, here). Without exaggeration, from Monday 10 to Tuesday 18, virtually the entire time we were looking for apartments, visiting flats with and without agent, meeting with real estate agents, collecting information for signing the lease &amp;hellip; and the first thing we noticed is that without a local phone, it was all much more difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>