<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psychology on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psychology on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 16:08:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Very interesting insights from the UBS Forum 2017</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/very-interesting-insights-from-the-ubs-forum-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 16:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/very-interesting-insights-from-the-ubs-forum-2017/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Giles and Magda invited me to attend the annual UBS Forum at the beautiful Rosewood Hotel, one of those hotels in a renovated palace in the heart of London, with a resident dog.
Held in major financial cities across Europe, the UBS Forum is presented under the banner &amp;ldquo;sharper opinions – smarter decisions”, where UBS specialists and external experts provide insights on key topics. This years` speakers and topics were:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Revolution needs a Revolution</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 17:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went with my wife and son to visit the Victoria &amp;amp; Albert`s Museum exhibition You Say You Want a Revolution? Records and Rebels 1966-1970. The aim of the exhibition was quite clear:
 How have the finished and unfinished revolutions of the late 1960s changed the way we live today and think about the future?
 I was very much looking forward to visiting the exhibition. It is SO timely, and SO needed, I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My artwork “God bless Amurika”, on display at the Ludwig Museum (Cologne), explained</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-artwork-god-bless-amurika-on-display-at-the-ludwig-museum-cologne-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 09:26:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-artwork-god-bless-amurika-on-display-at-the-ludwig-museum-cologne-explained/</guid>
      <description>I have often criticized artists who hide behind “my work speaks for itself” or “it’s up to the viewer to interpret my work”. Nice try, but that’s bullshit.
Of course, anyone can interpret anything when exposed to an artwork! But the artist should at least make an attempt to explain the meaning behind a piece. No matter how self-explanatory (or obscure) it might be. It’s not “restricting the viewer”, it’s guiding; suggesting is not imposing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last day in San Francisco: ART</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/last-day-in-san-francisco-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 22:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/last-day-in-san-francisco-art/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, September 17, was my last day in San Francisco, and the only one I had with some spare time.
After breakfast, I went to but some gifts from Japan Town and then headed to Union Square, for the Korean Day (Chuseok) culture festival.
Then I went to the Yerba Buena Center for the Arts to check out Tom Sachs _Space Program: Europa_. As I feared, after the failure of _Sony Outsider,_ Tom Sachs obsession with demonstrating his hand-made &amp;ldquo;bricolage style&amp;rdquo; continues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s pretend none of this ever happened</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 10:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</guid>
      <description>Walking towards my London Shoreditch office
to meet the Swiss investor and his impeccable suit,
leaving the City bankers’s coffee-holding fast pace behind,
I notice the absence nobody seems to
Where did he go?
His sleeping sack and pillow still on the sidewalk
as annoyingly positioned in the corner as always
But he’s gone
.
I wonder and I worry
his failing body, almost as absent as his lost gaze</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I stood up against a terrorist in a German train</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/i-stood-up-against-a-terrorist-in-a-german-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 12:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/i-stood-up-against-a-terrorist-in-a-german-train/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, after spending the day at a tradeshow in Düsseldorf, on my way by train to the hotel in Mülheim, I stopped in the town of Duisburg, which was on my way, because I heard they were setting up a Christmas market. The market was indeed being set up, but it was still closed, so I decided to go back to the station. To avoid the sprinkling rain I took the 901 tram at König-Heinrich Platz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attending the presentation of a new videogame as investment opportunity</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/attending-the-presentation-of-a-new-videogame-as-investment-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 20:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/attending-the-presentation-of-a-new-videogame-as-investment-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>On Monday I attended the presentation of Project M, a new video-game as investment opportunity, in Google Campus, London.

First of all, let me congratulate the savvy business and marketing team behind it. They put together a well though-out package, their idea is unique and very interesting: a videogame that will reward players by sending them real gold + investors buying &amp;ldquo;mines&amp;rdquo; in the game and participating in the profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the IBM Federal Summit, Washington DC</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/at-the-ibm-federal-summit-washington-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 13:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/at-the-ibm-federal-summit-washington-dc/</guid>
      <description>Last Wednesday I participated in IBM’s Federal Summit at the Ronald Reagan Federal Building in Washington DC.
Business aside, it was one scary meeting. There were control systems all over. From the IRS to airports, to National Security, the demos were much more advanced and comprehensive than anything you may have seen in a movie. Big Brother to the Nth degree. They know it all about you. In a second. You either get paranoid-serious about security, encryption and privacy, or you might as well forget completely about your privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold men destroy women</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/cold-men-destroy-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 16:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/cold-men-destroy-women/</guid>
      <description>Cold men destroy women,” my mother wrote me years later. “They woo them with something personable that they bring out for show, something annexed to their souls like a fake greenhouse, lead you in, and you think you see life and vitality and sun and greenness, and then when you love them, they lead you out into their real soul, a drafty, cavernous, empty ballroom, inexorably arched and vaulted and mocking you with its echoes— you hear all you have sacrificed, all you have given, landing with a loud clunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look at the data, just look at it!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/look-at-the-data-just-look-at-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 14:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/look-at-the-data-just-look-at-it/</guid>
      <description>Carna botnet offers us this amazing 24 hour visualization of relative IPv4 utilization observed using ICMP Ping requests.
Look at the data, just look at it! Dont you see peoples sleeping patterns, internet usage patterns, eating schedule habit, cultural differences, urban influence, regional inequalities&amp;hellip;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology in Phoenix, autopsy in Albuquerque</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/technology-in-phoenix-autopsy-in-albuquerque/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 16:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/technology-in-phoenix-autopsy-in-albuquerque/</guid>
      <description>4 flights and 40 hours later (after having missed Japan Week), I am back in New York in the modern and technological Delta terminal (C, not D) at Laguardia Airport, with its tablets and card readers on all tables and bars at all bars and restaurants.What a difference from the Delta Terminal 4 at JFK! Luckily the new one will be finished in May, because the old one is falling apart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool corp.?</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/cool-corp./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 11:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/cool-corp./</guid>
      <description>Read Quote of Balaji Viswanathans answer to Microsoft: Why isnt Microsoft ‘cool`?on Quora</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compliment</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/compliment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 19:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/compliment/</guid>
      <description>Today Juan gave me a great compliment, for which I am grateful:
 You embody the saying &amp;ldquo;Fall down 7 times, get up 8&amp;rdquo;
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trees rise, leafs leave</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/trees-rise-leafs-leave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 16:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/trees-rise-leafs-leave/</guid>
      <description>Astonished I witness the trees rise
tall from their base,
not even rooted.
Leafs leave,
group,
organize,
and shifting shapes,
take to the sky
only to dive down.
A red dragon,
a viking vessel,
coming straight at me.
The memory of holding your hand,
and blinking,
gets me through.
But how far could even a never fading memory take me?
I shall hold your hand again, or be taken by the leafs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>007 Skyfall at MoMA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/007-skyfall-at-moma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 21:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/007-skyfall-at-moma/</guid>
      <description>Although it may not be too obvious, I have been going through a few very hard weeks for several reasons. So someone who knows me well told me I should not be stupid, and should have fun. Let`s be it, then!
As part of their James Bond 50 years celebration, MoMA has been showing some of 007 movies in their collection (the largest by any museum in the world). So yesterday I was invited, and I of course invited Stephanie to be my guest, to the screening of the latest James Bond movie: &amp;ldquo;007 Skyfall&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After hurricane Sandy in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 20:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>From tilted posts to trees completely gone, after hurricane Sandy there were many signs of destruction around New York.
I had to stay at Stepahnie`s apartment (thank you again!) until Monday, because my building remained without power. And even after the power returned, the telephone and internet took two more days.
Some people were not so lucky, with all hotels fully booked, and had to stay at home for days without power or water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slavoj Žižek lecture &amp;quot;Conditions of Possibility&amp;quot; with M. Hägglund and A. Johnston</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/slavoj-%C5%BEi%C5%BEek-lecture-quotconditions-of-possibilityquot-with-m.-h%C3%A4gglund-and-a.-johnston/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 13:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/slavoj-%C5%BEi%C5%BEek-lecture-quotconditions-of-possibilityquot-with-m.-h%C3%A4gglund-and-a.-johnston/</guid>
      <description>Note: Start video on 33:33 (absolutely nothing happening before that, but just people waiting for the panelist to go on stage).On Friday I was invited to attend Slavoj Žižeks lecture &amp;quot;Conditions of Possibility&amp;quot; with M. Hägglund &amp;amp; A. Johnston at City University of New Yorks Graduate Center.
Martin Hägglund (associate professor of comparative literature and humanities at Yale University) and Adrian Johnston (professor in the department of philosophy at the University of New Mexico at Albuquerque and a faculty member at the Emory Psychoanalytic Institute in Atlanta) both read legthy and endogamic discourses about Heidegger, classic philosophical concepts, and stubbornly narrow minded &amp;ldquo;canons&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>319 Scholes art opening of &amp;quot;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 12:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I went to 319 Scholes to attend the art opening of &amp;ldquo;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;rdquo;.
Beyond the anecdotal post/pre hispter crowd, the exhibition itself is a sad celebration of noise. Which, in itself is as valid, or invalid, as any other starting point in the endless debate about art (more so in regards with contemporary, electronic, net, etc).
But it is its legitimization attempt, with research project, curator, catalogue, and international tour, which brings the debate to a whole different level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections from NY Comic Con</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 09:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I went to NY Comic Con, like everyone else, I guess, with the idea of having fun, of experiencing first hand one of the &amp;ldquo;major events&amp;rdquo; that a true nerdy geek can attend. I also wanted to meet Cory Doctorow (although we actually ended up not meeting). It has been years since I last met him, and it was the perfect &amp;ldquo;excuse&amp;rdquo; to attend the conference.
When I arrived, I was really surprised to see the size of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>white skin</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/white-skin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/white-skin/</guid>
      <description>Autumn.
My skin falls and yours is not there.
I turn to the canvas, but its not color I want to smear your whiteness with. I face the white screen, but its not light that I seek.
I confront the blank page, but words will not bring solace.
Then my skin falls on the piano ivory.
Fingers sliding down each key.
Caresses that the air won`t keep.
The music was already playing in my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Norse vs Inuit approach</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-norse-vs-inuit-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-norse-vs-inuit-approach/</guid>
      <description>The Norse vs Inuit approach
There are many seemingly &amp;ldquo;small events&amp;rdquo; in history to which we do not pay much attention, when actually they provide very important lessons. I always talk about historical examples of perfectly successful cooperatives and anarchist self government. But this time I want to comment on a very different historical event: the Norse attempt to colonize Greenland.
When the Norse tried to colonize Greenland, the Inuit already lived there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High culture might will numb you, how stay true? On &amp;quot;Graffiti&amp;quot; screening and panel at New Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 15:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I was invited to the New Musuem for the screening of &amp;ldquo;Graffiti – PostGraffiti&amp;rdquo; documentary and panel discussion.Your usual suspects were there. Besides the panelist (Pattie Astor, Fab Five Freddy, Lady Pink, and Lee Quinones), there were many old glories and a couple of aspiring bomber kids in the audience that I am sure were tagging walls late that night.
What started as a celebration, a remembrance, and a comunion, as the liturgy advanced ended up becoming a hurtful vindication and even a flat out purist attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I`m the man and the boy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/im-the-man-and-the-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 22:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/im-the-man-and-the-boy/</guid>
      <description>I`m the man that fears rejection
Im the man that cant sleep because of problems
I`m the man that will fight and defend the castle</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It`s October and all I want is you</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 22:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</guid>
      <description>Lying on the carpet, poetry book and pencil in hand, U2 in the background.
October
 October
And the trees are stripped bare
Of all they wear
What do I care
October
And kingdoms rise
And kingdoms fall
But you go on&amp;hellip;and on&amp;hellip;
 So many literal meanings: the fear of wearing-out (The Edge was considering leaving the band like his brother did before they were even called U2), the false sense of security arising from self-defeat (&amp;ldquo;What do I care&amp;rdquo;), moving on after a loss (both Bono and Larry had just lost their mothers), the high hopes and expectations arising from new democracies in Eastern Europe only to become despair and dissapointment, and eventually resilience, surviving, going on&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multidimensional matrix of epistemology</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/a-multidimensional-matrix-of-epistemology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 09:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/a-multidimensional-matrix-of-epistemology/</guid>
      <description>I have no clue about physics or philosophy. But just like, when thinking theoretical physics, I cant help but reach the conclusion that time is a form of energy, when I think of epistemology, I cant help but to think of it in a multidimensional matrix, of which we can usually only grasp part, because the interconnexions we trace are linear an unidirectional.
It`s a well known fact that our brain is not built to comprehend reality, but &amp;ldquo;to make sense&amp;rdquo; of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting videos</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/interesting-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 22:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/interesting-videos/</guid>
      <description>Let me share some odd videos I have watched recently, thanks to Leaitrice and Patricia:
The famous &amp;quot;Sunscreen&amp;rdquo; music video(the text comes from an essaywritten in 1997 by Mary Schmich, a columnist at the Chicago Tribune, as a graduation speech for the class of `97) which gives some amazing advice for life. There is even a StarWars Version.
Drunk History: get some history students drunk, have them narrate historical events, while reenacting them&amp;hellip; more fun than it seems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poem: &amp;quot;Accompanied by your absence&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/poem-quotaccompanied-by-your-absencequot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 16:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/poem-quotaccompanied-by-your-absencequot/</guid>
      <description> Accompanied by your absence
I hear your skin calling.
Silently, still, I answer.
In the solitude of your presence
I remember sliding down your gaze
fearlessly falling into your void,
your being`s foyer.
Next to you, finally, I rest
dreaming and longing,
with the peace and tranquility that comes from
knowing me you.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay for Nebula`s new photobook</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/essay-for-nebulas-new-photobook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 13:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/essay-for-nebulas-new-photobook/</guid>
      <description>I have contributed an essay to the book (PDF soon available for free online, and for purchase in book format -a few sample images shown here-) of an exhibition I am curating. 3 years in the making, &amp;ldquo;Gaze, Reflexion, Fusion&amp;rdquo; is the highly poetical but politically charged work of one of the most interesting new photographers in the New York art scene: NEBULA.
From Tokyo to San Francisco, Madrid to Seoul, the Spanish photographer Nebula has traveled to 10 cities in 4 countries in order to find inspiration and the right images (somethimes a fleeting reflexion of it) to bring to life what she feels about art, identity, apropriationism, feminism, and psychoanalysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I beat Watson at Jeopardy (more or less)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 18:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in my previous post, at IBM Innovation Center in Chicago they have a Watson(more info here) interactive kiosk with which to play an interactive game of Jeopardy. In case you have been living in a cave for the past few months, Watson beatJeopardy human champions on live TV, the significanceof which can not be overstated.
Now, remember: this is a &amp;ldquo;small version&amp;rdquo; of Watson, and a &amp;ldquo;self-contained&amp;rdquo; version of Jeopardy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critics and artists</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/critics-and-artists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 17:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/critics-and-artists/</guid>
      <description>When art critics get together they talk about Form and Structure and Meaning. When artists get together they talk about where you can buy cheap turpentine.
 Picasso</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts about the 15M</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/thoughts-about-the-15m/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 13:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/thoughts-about-the-15m/</guid>
      <description>May 15th I went to the #15M demosntration in Malaga (Spain). As I was by myself, and to document and support &amp;ldquo;the cause&amp;rdquo;, I took my camerca and zig-zagged thourgh the crowd, in a kind of amateur sociological analysis of the most interesting social movement in these turbulent times. Here are some not-so-random thoughts:
 While no particular spacial organization can be detected in the demonstration, the group dynamics and power hierarchy (even if perceived representation power) applied their invisible forces once more to take the radicals (or most outspoken at least) to march in the front line, families in the middle, and party goers and curious at the back Most &amp;ldquo;organizers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;speakers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;banner-holders and support van drivers&amp;rdquo; were foreign (mainly Argentinians) Although supposedly devoid of political affiliation, the only ones showing political signs were those without direct political representation in the form of &amp;ldquo;their own party&amp;rdquo; (anarchist, republicans, etc) While there was no &amp;ldquo;organized plan of action&amp;rdquo; (I wonder if the &amp;ldquo;assemblies&amp;rdquo; could get to one without some sort of non-hierarchical order and/or structure), the #cazerolada and #lacaixaesmordor seem to channel the discontempt towards the direct real cause (superficial, first and most apparent, but not necessarily the most important) of the dire social tensions of today: banks and the financial system&amp;hellip; although how about the political system that allowed that to happen (from corruption to &amp;ldquo;democratic&amp;rdquo; representation)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A conversation with Spanish Philosopher Fernando Sabater at Instituto Cervantes NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/a-conversation-with-spanish-philosopher-fernando-sabater-at-instituto-cervantes-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 13:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/a-conversation-with-spanish-philosopher-fernando-sabater-at-instituto-cervantes-ny/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday May 2nd, I had the pleasure to meet Fernando Sabaterat Instituto Cervantes, NY.
The conversation was lighthearted and included many anecdotes and trvia, but also a good dose of Philosophy and Psychology wisdom and aphorisms (like those by Andrés Newman). Here are some delicious quotes by him:
  Dont attack, dont comply Childhood is always bad: wether because it was bad and left you a trauma, or because it was good and it frustrates you to leave it behind Happyness is also hard to bear Skepticism grows, and thats why when I am about to make a statement (particularly if it is a grand one) I end up laughing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business advice for startups: do not collect underpants</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/business-advice-for-startups-do-not-collect-underpants/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 11:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/business-advice-for-startups-do-not-collect-underpants/</guid>
      <description>First read this post.
Then watch this South Park episode.
Now, if you are not going to cook something, get out of the kitchen (and at least start selling 😉 )</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The danger of graphs and cold data</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</guid>
      <description>After posting graphs and cold data (quite ilustrative, I believe), and the discussion it has generated (people, why don`t you use the &amp;ldquo;comment&amp;rdquo; instead all the other unstructured methods you are using?), please let me write a caveat about graphs and cold data.
In my high-tech gym, you have the option to have a lot of data collected, for your own, private and personal use. It seems like a great idea at first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC anarchist book fair</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/nyc-anarchist-book-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 13:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/nyc-anarchist-book-fair/</guid>
      <description>Since I could not get a hold of tickts for New Museum`s Seven on Seven, I decided to make the most out of my day yesterday (defying my cold), so I even had time to visit the NYC anarchist book fair, at Judson Church (Washington Square).
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5731668030633382577]
I wish I had had more time to devote to exploring all the literature (great and aweful) on display. But at least I had time to notice:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with face.com face recognition technology</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/playing-with-face.com-face-recognition-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 17:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/playing-with-face.com-face-recognition-technology/</guid>
      <description>While I am preparing a loooooong post about technology and privacy (with a provocative twist, for a change 😈 ), I have decided to play with face.com‘s face recognition technology.
What do you think? On target (hint: no, not on target, I am not THAT old, and definitely I AM a male)? Scary (hint: only if we are unaware of these technologies and their uses)?&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autism news</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/autism-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 17:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/autism-news/</guid>
      <description>While generalizations are usually absurd and damaging (asking &amp;ldquo;What is it like to be in a relationship with someone who has Asperger`s?&amp;rdquo; is almost as ridiculous a generalization as asking &amp;ldquo;What is it like to be in a relationship with a blonde?&amp;quot;) it is true that in general, working with an autistic person may be hard, living with one could be unbearable, and being one is&amp;hellip;
Some, let`s seek relief and help in knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards an oversimplification cliff: when green=drunks</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/towards-an-oversimplification-cliff-when-greendrunks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 18:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/towards-an-oversimplification-cliff-when-greendrunks/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday morning, as I was walking towards the gym on Park Avenue, I saw waves of young adults (although acting like teenagers or frat boys) wearing green (some just a t-shirt or sweater, some a full leprechaun costume) on a procession towards their favorite Irish watering hole to &amp;ldquo;celebrate&amp;rdquo; St. Patricks Day in the only way that they seem to believe to be appropriate, besides a 5th Ave. official parade: drink until you pass out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You may pretend, but remember...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/you-may-pretend-but-remember.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 04:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/you-may-pretend-but-remember.../</guid>
      <description> When you go around jumping like you are on the moon, and then you trip and fall, you are going to smash your face against the floor with full Earth gravity.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context in Art as Political Discussion: Amalia Pica`s Venn Diagrams</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/context-in-art-as-political-discussion-amalia-picas-venn-diagrams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 19:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/context-in-art-as-political-discussion-amalia-picas-venn-diagrams/</guid>
      <description>One of the multiple interesting pieces currently being exhibited at the New Museums &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://cortell.net/blog/2012/03/the-ungovernables-party-at-new-museum/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://cortell.net/blog/2012/03/the-ungovernables-party-at-new-museum/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;The Ungovernables&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; is Amalia Picas Venn Diagrams. The text under this piece says:
 During the period of dictatorship in Argentina in the 1970s, gatherings of citizens were closely monitored as they were considered a threat to the government. At the same time group theory and venn diagrams were banned from primary school programs as they could provide a model for subversive thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic reactions: Twitter censorship, Google campaign, and magenta trade-marked</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/automatic-reactions-twitter-censorship-google-campaign-and-magenta-trade-marked/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 15:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/automatic-reactions-twitter-censorship-google-campaign-and-magenta-trade-marked/</guid>
      <description>The net was all up in arms this week. After the marvelous uprising against SOPA and PIPA, the new battle ground was Twitter`s announcement of country specific censorship. Never mind that they are open about it (unlike Facebook), never mind that they are talking about their offices and employees in those countries where censorship is the law&amp;hellip; if you hear &amp;ldquo;censorship&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;net&amp;rdquo; get up and scream! Wired has a nice pieceabout it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of context in the interpretation (and enjoyment) of a work of art</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-importance-of-context-in-the-interpretation-and-enjoyment-of-a-work-of-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 01:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-importance-of-context-in-the-interpretation-and-enjoyment-of-a-work-of-art/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went to 3 exhibitions/events that have allowed me to see the importance of context in the interpretation (and enjoyment) of a work of art. Note that I differentiate &amp;ldquo;interpretation&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;enjoyment&amp;rdquo;, although for many of us, those two concepts go hand in hand. But this is just a short post, so the Phenomenological Aesthetics will have to wait (you can read Dewey, Hartmann, Adorno, Ortega y Gasset, Sartre, etc, etc in the meantime 😉 )</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture in today`s world in a state of polarized anomie</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/culture-in-todays-world-in-a-state-of-polarized-anomie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 17:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/culture-in-todays-world-in-a-state-of-polarized-anomie/</guid>
      <description>When Émile Durkheim wrote on the concept of anomie (expanding on Jean-Marie Guyau`s work) in his 1897 book Suicide, he spoke of one end of anomie: a society with too much rigidity and little individual discretion causing a destructive mismatch (moral deregulation and an absence of legitimate aspirations).
This is happening in the XXI century world, in many countries: those totalitarian (military or religious) societies where the social rule, expectations, and repression conform a cage around individuals, deposessing them of their individuality, their aspirations, subtly (or otherwise) imposing a social corset where the individual can not be itself, concentrating only on breathing, surviving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Zen ad making me sick</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/anti-zen-ad-making-me-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 10:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/anti-zen-ad-making-me-sick/</guid>
      <description>As I walk towards my office, I see an ad that makes me sick (as a matter of fact, I see many, but this one points to something other that the consumerism-sexism-excess that we are so dangerously getting used to).
The ad says &amp;ldquo;Turn now into memories&amp;rdquo;. How wrong is that?!!
Now is now. Now has to be now. Now should be now. Now has to remain now.
When you strive to &amp;ldquo;turn now into memories&amp;rdquo;, you are missing out on the real now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate MLK day with RX2008 mix</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/celebrate-mlk-day-with-rx2008-mix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 09:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/celebrate-mlk-day-with-rx2008-mix/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A man falls, two walk over him</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/a-man-falls-two-walk-over-him/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 20:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/a-man-falls-two-walk-over-him/</guid>
      <description>Today, at the gym`s lobby/reception area, a man was sitting waiting for his wife to come out of yoga class. When she does, he gets up to greet her, feels dizzy, and passes out, falling to the ground, and hitting his face on the floor.
Two men who were on their way out, walk over this man. They do not bother-care-ask what`s wrong. They do not offer assistance.
Finally, his wife (who witnessed the whole episode, paralyzed in fear) reacts, wakes him up, and makes sure his eye socket bleeding is not too profuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color associations: red and yellow</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/color-associations-red-and-yellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 05:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/color-associations-red-and-yellow/</guid>
      <description>Seeing certain color combinations, associations are sure to fly into anybody`s minds.
Usually, red and yellow will bring to mind things like flags (of Spain, Catalonia-Valencia, R, Security, and adding some shapes you could even think of Macedonia or China).
Beyond flags, Axomil, sunset, fire, peppers,tullips, ballons, ketchup and mustard, Flash, soccer referee cards, Superman&amp;hellip; there are SO many options.
But when you consider the hue, tone, context, memory, and further additional information, then those options start to get reduced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you like Science, you will like...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/if-you-like-science-you-will-like.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 18:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/if-you-like-science-you-will-like.../</guid>
      <description>Source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ode to the pen</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/ode-to-the-pen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 18:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/ode-to-the-pen/</guid>
      <description>See in Scientific American:
 &amp;ldquo;I could not survive without a ballpoint pen in my back pocket. It`s invaluable for scribbling notes on the front of my hand (my version of the PalmPilot&amp;hellip;) to remind me to do things I used to be able to remember unaided before my age converged with my IQ while traveling in opposite directions.&amp;rdquo;
 _John P. MooreProfessor of Microbiology and Immunology
Weill Medical College of Cornell University, New York City_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook: couple breaker for drunks</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/facebook-couple-breaker-for-drunks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 05:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/facebook-couple-breaker-for-drunks/</guid>
      <description>Interesting couple of trivia about Facebook in UK:
 Facebook blamed for one-third marriage breakdowns British Facebook users intoxicated in 76% of their photos  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun interpreting signs</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/fun-interpreting-signs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 17:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/fun-interpreting-signs/</guid>
      <description>The world around us is full of signs. I wont go on dabble about _signifiers_, _meanings_, and the psychoanalitycal importance of the _word_. But sometimes I just cant help myself, when I see a sign begging for a creative interpretation:
Cmon, dont tell me you don`t see something like:
 If you press this button, your mouth will become a hotspot
 or
 A giant asteroid is heading towards your SpaceInvaders spacecraft, push the button to destroy the asteroid with a Dune-sque voice-blast</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Uncanny Valley as an approach to the pseudo-empathy of Aperger Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/the-uncanny-valley-as-an-approach-to-the-pseudo-empathy-of-aperger-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 18:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/the-uncanny-valley-as-an-approach-to-the-pseudo-empathy-of-aperger-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>According to Wikipedia:
 The uncanny valley is a hypothesis in the field of robotics and 3D computer animation, which holds that when human replicas look and act almost, but not perfectly, like actual human beings, it causes a response of revulsion among human observers. The &amp;ldquo;valley&amp;rdquo; in question is a dip in a proposed graph of the positivity of human reaction as a function of a robot`s human likeness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do I feel better when...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/why-do-i-feel-better-when.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 07:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/why-do-i-feel-better-when.../</guid>
      <description>I am referred to (not addressed to, of course) in third person?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anxiety quantifiers</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/anxiety-quantifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2011 02:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/anxiety-quantifiers/</guid>
      <description>We all know them, c`mon, add to the list. Here are some examples to get you going:
 Number of tabs opened in browser Number of virtualized OSs in a single box Number of unread emails per hour Number of unread RSSs (or number of feeds) Number of saved sites on Delicious, Pulse, whatever Number of post drafts Number of beta-invites to be accepted  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga Guru uses copyright to sue competitor</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 19:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</guid>
      <description>Ego, money, power, abuse, restriction&amp;hellip; shame on those who stain the &amp;ldquo;holy&amp;rdquo; teachings.
Source: NYT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complex</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/complex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 18:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/complex/</guid>
      <description>Somebody told me yesterday:
 You are not complex, you just make everybody else`s life complicated
 [irony on] Nice, thanks [irony off]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying to Rio with a character</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/flying-to-rio-with-a-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 10:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/flying-to-rio-with-a-character/</guid>
      <description>After arriving in JFK in the most predictable way (rain, snow, traffic or whatever) which is the combo E line + AirTrain, and boarding on a &amp;ldquo;last call&amp;rdquo; although I arrived early enough (due to the never-ending security lines, and the abnormal amount of passengers with special needs such as many small children in strollers, large hand-luggage, senior citizens, etc) I finally arrive at my seat on the flight New York – Rio de Janeiro, and I see it is occupied by… Rolls Royce car keys, with a Rolls Royce keyring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you see here...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-do-you-see-here.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 12:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-do-you-see-here.../</guid>
      <description>A green PacMan The market size you want to conquer Your shrinking market size Food to eat Food eaten A green tea – coconut – ginger vegan cake A memory A moment Enjoyment  &amp;hellip;
Does this post start to sound like an HSBC ad? I spend too much time in airports!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To be a CEO...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/to-be-a-ceo.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 22:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/to-be-a-ceo.../</guid>
      <description>means resisting the urge to kill yourself or kill others, and find a solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We the people... divorce = bankruptcy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/we-the-people...-divorce-bankruptcy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 17:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/we-the-people...-divorce-bankruptcy/</guid>
      <description>Walking on 8th Ave., I find this amazing signs on a lawyer`s office window (NO COMMENT):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tragedy of probability ignorance</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-tragedy-of-probability-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 13:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-tragedy-of-probability-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>When a M. Phil. from Cambridge, A.B. from Harvard, and M.D. from UCal writes an articleinsisting on a probabilistic fallacy, a trap where, in one way or another, many have fallen (from Eccles to Nagel), and this article is echoed in many sites (such as BoingBoing) and an infographicis made and becomes staff pick at visual.ly&amp;hellip; then you know ignorance is everywhere and very dangerous.
Read the article, then read Roy Weatherford`s &amp;ldquo;Philosophical foundations of probability theory&amp;rdquo; (or maybe something simpler), and once you grasp the concept of &amp;ldquo;a priori theories of probability&amp;rdquo;, laugh at those who think each one of us is a miracle&amp;hellip; we all are, but not because the probability of us being born is extremely small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to &amp;quot;What more than sorry&amp;quot; by Ben Harper</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/listening-to-quotwhat-more-than-sorryquot-by-ben-harper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 17:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/listening-to-quotwhat-more-than-sorryquot-by-ben-harper/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bad thing about being good at seeming &amp;quot;normal&amp;quot;...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-bad-thing-about-being-good-at-seeming-quotnormalquot.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 10:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-bad-thing-about-being-good-at-seeming-quotnormalquot.../</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; is that people forget you are not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of a cycle counter</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-importance-of-a-cycle-counter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 14:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-importance-of-a-cycle-counter/</guid>
      <description>Curious coincidence (or maybe not), two days after realising &amp;ldquo;something&amp;rdquo; was missing in one of my frequent logic diagrams, I saw an episodeof The Big Bang Theory in which Wollowitz discovers a flaw in Sheldon`s friendship algorithm.
Dr. Sheldon Cooper`s lack of a cycle counter in his friendship algorithmis not a trivial issue. The cycle counter is the &amp;ldquo;real life&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;context&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;awareness&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;empathy&amp;rdquo;, aspect of a logic interpretation of a social engagement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why am I dropping out of Stanford`s AI course</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/why-am-i-dropping-out-of-stanfords-ai-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 10:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/why-am-i-dropping-out-of-stanfords-ai-course/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps all those people telling me &amp;ldquo;you`re trying to do too much at the same time&amp;rdquo; (thanks Ana, Remei, Juan&amp;hellip;) were right. Perhaps moving to NY and trying to make my company grow, not to mention &amp;ldquo;personal life&amp;rdquo;, is already time-consuming enough. Or perhaps there are other reasons&amp;hellip; but the truth is, I am dropping out of the fun and interesting AI course at Stanford University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not so difficult (is it?)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/not-so-difficult-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 09:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/not-so-difficult-is-it/</guid>
      <description>In this cute decorative vinyl from chispum.com, the message says: &amp;ldquo;I want a boyfriend who only wants to sleep with me (and nobody else)&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approaching 1984</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/approaching-1984/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 12:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/approaching-1984/</guid>
      <description>Governments that use stats to lie, that shamelessly change political stands, that pocket millionaires paychecks and retirements in even in times of crisis&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, that &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.ij.org/about/4058&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.ij.org/about/4058&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;steal from citizens with any excuse&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, that &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://boingboing.net/2011/09/25/rejected-designs-for-the-federal-housing-finance-agency-seal.html?utm_source=pulsenews&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+boingboing%2FiBag+%28Boing+Boing%29&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://boingboing.net/2011/09/25/rejected-designs-for-the-federal-housing-finance-agency-seal.html?utm_source=pulsenews&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+boingboing%2FiBag+%28Boing+Boing%29&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;do not care to spend 400$ or 600,000€ in a logo&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, that allow an &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://youtu.be/6zZ_JfROhOE&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://youtu.be/6zZ_JfROhOE&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;out of control financial system&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (and force lower interest to finance a war driven by personal economic interests in a time that required higher interests) which places us at the edge of the cliff and dares to &amp;quot;rescue them&amp;quot; with everybodys money, with a cost higher than which would be needed to end poverty in the world, and not making any changes so it does not happen again in the financial or food markets&amp;hellip; all this and more, with complete impunity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>