<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geek Fun on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/geek-fun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geek Fun on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 08:45:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/geek-fun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool online presentations with free software</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/05/cool-online-presentations-with-free-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 08:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/05/cool-online-presentations-with-free-software/</guid>
      <description>It has been a while since I wrote a tutorial to Share The Wealth, so it’s about time I shared some practical (if basic) knowledge beyond reposting a link.
For years I have had a pet project in the backburner: I wanted to create presentations without the need of dedicated software, commercial (like PowerPoint or Keynote), or free (like LibreOffice or OpenOffice). That way I could avoid bringing my computer to a lecture, and not worry about what computer system would be available in the auditorium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the UK-China Hi! Technology event in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/invited-to-the-uk-china-hi-technology-event-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 16:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/invited-to-the-uk-china-hi-technology-event-in-london/</guid>
      <description>For reasons beyond the scope of this post I was invited to participate in the UK-China Hi! Technology event in London.
The event was well attended by a large number of entrepreneurs, funds and investors from the UK and China.
The highlight of the event, for me, other than a couple of really interesting contacts, was to see all these suited-up people lining up to try the VR sets (HTC, Oculus, Hololens, etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spare time fun: protein structure analysis of mutations causing inheritable diseases</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/spare-time-fun-protein-structure-analysis-of-mutations-causing-inheritable-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 08:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/spare-time-fun-protein-structure-analysis-of-mutations-causing-inheritable-diseases/</guid>
      <description>Most people I know would not consider protein structure analysis of mutations causing inheritable diseases &amp;ldquo;spare time fun&amp;rdquo;. Then again, most people I know don`t think I am like most people they know.
This week I`m a &amp;ldquo;single-dad&amp;rdquo;, since my wife is traveling. So my spare time right now is almost non existent. Nevertheless, the thought of mutating a Proline into a Glycine at position 22 intrigued me, so I spent a few minutes simulating it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting the London Design Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/visiting-the-london-design-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 08:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/visiting-the-london-design-museum/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I visited the Design Museum(&amp;ldquo;The world`s leading museum devoted to contemporary design in every form from architecture and fashion to graphics, product and industrial design&amp;rdquo;) in its spectacular new location on High Street Kensington (London), with my son.
The #newdesignmuseum opened its doors in its new location only 5 days ago. The building and renovation are great, and in a nice location: on the edge of Holland Park, with the added bonus of being near the Kyoto Garden, Muji, and not far from the Serpentine Gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valencia (Spain) VC flows</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/valencia-spain-vc-flows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 14:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/valencia-spain-vc-flows/</guid>
      <description>Adam Gilfix, Brian de Luna, and Luke Heine, with the help of Dealroom.co, have created a very interesting data visualization tool for Venture Capital (VC) flows.
I know for a fact and from experience that VC activity in places like Silicon Valley, NY, Boston, or London is big. But even when I go back home (Valencia – Spain) for the holidays, there are all kinds of &amp;ldquo;VC&amp;rdquo; events, news, meetings, spaces&amp;hellip; which, given the conservative and provincial nature of the &amp;ldquo;Valencian Investors&amp;rdquo; I have met, surprises me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My company has been named “Top Scaleup in the UK”</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-company-has-been-named-top-scaleup-in-the-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 07:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-company-has-been-named-top-scaleup-in-the-uk/</guid>
      <description>For second consecutive year, my company has been named “Top Scaleup in the UK”. This means that we are growing fast, and also that I get invited to cool events. One of those events was a reception and a ‘Ten Years From Now’ series of keynotes at the Royal Institution of Great Britain, another one a mentoring session at London’s City Hall, and another one a series of talks at Google Campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Future Decoded 2016</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/microsoft-future-decoded-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 20:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/microsoft-future-decoded-2016/</guid>
      <description>November 1 I attended Future Decoded, the annual event where Microsoft and Partners present their forward looking products and concepts.
Besides some cool “event attractions” (like the Back To The Future Delorean, seeing how data is not completely deleted even if you deep freeze a hard drive, the Bloodhound record-breaking car, or seeing the inside of a Rolls Royce plane turbine), the key for me was to be able to demonstrate my company’s software running on an amazing 84” Microsoft Surface Hub, and attending the invitation-only Microsoft Executive Party at the Sunborn Yacht Hotel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego day 4</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 16:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-4/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, October 11th, was day four, and last, at the Exponential Medicine Conference in San Diego.
Some of the talks I enjoyed the most:
Exponential Thinking &amp;amp; Future Predictions: Ray Kurzweil Co-founder &amp;amp; Chancellor, Singularity University
Exponential Entrepreneurship:
 Zayna Khayat, PhD Lead, MaRS Health and Director, MaRS EXCITE Stephanie Marrus, MBA Entrepreneurship Center Director, UCSF  Investing In The Future: Vinod Khosla Founder, Khosla Ventures
Visualizing the Future of Medical Education, from VR to the OR:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tea with Peter Diamandis and dinner with Vinod Khosla</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/tea-with-peter-diamandis-and-dinner-with-vinod-khosla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 15:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/tea-with-peter-diamandis-and-dinner-with-vinod-khosla/</guid>
      <description>Monday, October 10th, I had the pleasure to have a chat with Peter Diamandis at a coffee (tea for me, thank you) break.
He was very interested in talking about my company (Kanteron Systems), as we have developed technology that can really help some of his investments in Precision Medicine and Longevity.
Even more interesting than talking about investments, it was to know a little bit the man behind the legend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego day 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 14:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-3/</guid>
      <description>Monday, October 10th was day 3 at the Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego.
For me the highlights were:
Bold Innovation: Peter Diamandis, MD Co-Founder, Singularity University and Founder &amp;amp; Chair, XPRIZE
Redesigning Care: Tony Young, PhD FRCS National Clinical Director for Innovation, NHS England
Bakul Patel, MBA Associate Director of Digital Health, Food and Drug Administration/Center for Devices and Radiological Health
Getting the xMED Scrubs Photo on the Beach, with an awesome drone:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Award and Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego day 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/award-and-exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 14:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/award-and-exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-2/</guid>
      <description>Sunday, October 9th, was day two at Exponential Medicine Conference in San Diego.
Some of the highlights were:
From ‘Omics to Action
 Moira Gunn, PhD Host, NPR’s Biotech Nation Larry Smarr, PhD Professor, UCSD and Director, Calit2 George Poste, DVM PhD FRS Chief Scientist, Complex Adaptive Systems Initiative- Arizona State University  Mobile, Connected, Digital Health
 David Albert, MD Founder, AliveCor Stanley Shaw, MD PhD Co-Director, MGH Center for Assessment Technology &amp;amp; Continuous Health Bakul Patel, MBA Associate Director of Digital Health, Food and Drug Administration/Center for Devices and Radiological Health Ulrik Wisløff Professor: Faculty of Medicine, Norwegian University of Science and Technology  Innovating at Scale: John Mattison, MD CMIO and Assistant Medical Director, Kaiser Permanente</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Medicine Conference San Diego day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 09:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/exponential-medicine-conference-san-diego-day-1/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, October 8th, I attended day 1 of the Singularity University Exponential Medicine Conference in San Diegoat the amazing Hotel Del Coronado.
The event was organized mainly by Will Weisman and the incomparable Daniel Kraft, MD (whom I met last year at the London Stock Exchange), both from Singularity University.
The Conference was fully packed with activities. Morning activities started at 7am and included Yoga, Meditation, Art, and Beach Run. Evening activities changed every day, and included things like Team Collaboration &amp;amp; Innovation Games, Gadget &amp;amp; S’mores Bar, Music &amp;amp; Magic at the Bar, UnConference, or Silent Disco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Silicon Valley for bilateral meetings with Uber, Berkeley and General Electric</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/in-silicon-valley-for-bilateral-meetings-with-uber-berkeley-and-general-electric/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 21:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/in-silicon-valley-for-bilateral-meetings-with-uber-berkeley-and-general-electric/</guid>
      <description>Friday, September 16, I attended 3 &amp;ldquo;bilateral meetings&amp;rdquo;.The first one took place in downtown San Francisco, in Uber HQ.
The first one took place in downtown San Francisco, in Uber, which is in the same building as Square and across the street from Twitter.
That same morning there was a big story about how much money Uber is losing, and how artificially high their valuation is, but of course, nobody wanted to talk about that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Silicon Valley for meetings with Microsoft, Google Ventures, LinkedIn, and party at Idean</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/in-silicon-valley-for-meetings-with-microsoft-google-ventures-linkedin-and-party-at-idean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 03:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/in-silicon-valley-for-meetings-with-microsoft-google-ventures-linkedin-and-party-at-idean/</guid>
      <description>Thursday, September 15 I had several meetings in Silicon Valley.
The first one was with the Director of Strategic Investments at the Microsoft Technology Center in Mountain View. Since it is business related, I won`t comment anything about that very interesting meeting.
The second one was with a Partner at Google Ventures. The discussion was to the point and provocative. It is interesting to note that Google and Google Ventures are NOT the same company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I won the Anti-Patents Policy Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/i-won-the-anti-patents-policy-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 02:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/i-won-the-anti-patents-policy-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>On September 13, Mind the Bridge hosted a policy hackathon sponsored by Dell at the MTB Innovation Center in San Francisco. The Dell PolicyHack™ brought together entrepreneurs and U.S./EU policy experts to solve policy challenges. The goal is to productively brainstorm and to provide top-line thinking that can inspire and serve as basis to develop and implement full policies.
My team was formed by:
 Sara R. Klucking (Section Chief, Innovation &amp;amp; Programs, Office of Science and Technology Cooperation, US Department of State) Bogdan Ceobanu (Policy Officer, Startups &amp;amp; Innovation, European Commission) David Hodgson (CEO, Hummingbird Labs) me  The five teams had 75 minutes to come up with a policy solution to issue areas that impact entrepreneurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco, day 4</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/san-francisco-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 02:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/san-francisco-day-4/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday September 13 was a day devoted to workshops, a policy hackathon, and a visit to Pinterest HQ.
As I have mentioned before, we have been fortunate to have a great group of mentors. In this case we enjoyed the following sessions in small groups:
 Market growth with: the CEO of CorkBIC, a former Microsoft BizDev VP, and the co-Founder &amp;amp; Director of Blippar Funding with: the Chair of Global Venture Forum, a Director at Woodside Capital, and a Partner at Delta Partners Group M&amp;amp;A/IPO with: the Principal M&amp;amp;A Integration at Google, a Managing Partner at Woodside Capital, and a Partner at Penningtons Manches Communication/PR with: the President of ActiveMedia, and the Associate Director at Oxygen PR  After that we had a policy hackathon competition (more about that in the next blog post).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EID at Computer History Museum in Mountain View</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/eid-at-computer-history-museum-in-mountain-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 01:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/eid-at-computer-history-museum-in-mountain-view/</guid>
      <description>Monday, September 12, was the European Innovation Day (EID)at the Computer History Museumin Mountain View, CA.
Although the museum is not open on Mondays, we had access to a few of the exhibits, like the one about the IBM 1401, the awesome PDP-1 (Creating the Hacker Culture), and autonomous vehicles (and yes, of course, I go into a Google driverless car, and took a selfie).
But the reason why we went there was not (only) to see the museum but to participate in the EID event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco, day 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/san-francisco-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/san-francisco-day-2/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that strikes me the most in this trip is how many homeless there are in SF. The income inequality is so obvious and insulting, it hurts. I know this is not a “SF-only” problem, but here it is a lot more visible than in many other cities.
As I walk from Union Sq. to Tender Nob through Geary or O’Farrell streets, or as I go to work in SOMA, I see homeless and people in need all over the sidewalk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kanteron Workshop in Valencia</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/kanteron-workshop-in-valencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 14:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/kanteron-workshop-in-valencia/</guid>
      <description>For a couple of days at the end of July, we held a workshop in Kanteron Systems Headquarters, where most of the team came together to share, discuss, work, and have fun:
We had standup meetings, teamwork&amp;hellip; all &amp;ldquo;Kanteron Style&amp;rdquo; 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to speak at Microsoft Healthcare event</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/08/invited-to-speak-at-microsoft-healthcare-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 15:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/08/invited-to-speak-at-microsoft-healthcare-event/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday August 9th, I was invited to talk about Personalised Medicine at Microsoft’s event “Empowering Health in a mobile first and cloud first world”, at Microsoft’s UK headquarters in Reading (UK).
There were very interesting sessions on Intelligent Cloud, Microsoft Research (with whom we are collaborating) work on radiology and genomics, Introduction to productivity in health, Revolutionising infection control, National Technology Officer’s Cloud Update, Transdermal Sensors in Paediatric Care, Introduction to personalised computing in health, Virtual care clinics in Sweden, Digital wellbeing, The venture programme for health, NHS…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyperJapan 2016 London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/hyperjapan-2016-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 15:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/hyperjapan-2016-london/</guid>
      <description>Today we went with my sister and brother-in-law, who are visiting for a few days, to HyperJapanin London Olympia.
Silly and fun, full of cosplay and otakus. Kawaii!
^.^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-designing a NASA interface</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/re-designing-a-nasa-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 14:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/re-designing-a-nasa-interface/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in many things. One of the main ones is technology. And within technology, software development to view telemetry data in different ways, within the same application.
Answering NASA’s call to help contribute to the exploration of the solar system, I got access to their next-generation mission control framework being developed at the NASA Ames Research Center in Silicon Valley being used for mission planning and operations in the lead up to the Resource Prospector mission, and at NASA`s Jet Propulsion Laboratory to view data from the Curiosity Rover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A week of meetings in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/a-week-of-meetings-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 09:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/a-week-of-meetings-in-london/</guid>
      <description>After the trip to Boston I came down with the flu, of course on a weekend as usual. So Monday I had zero energy, but a week ahead with an usual large number of meetings around London, so I had to do “magic calendar tricks” to be able to make all of them and to also attend several events. The main “trick” is to concentrate meetings geographically, adding into the calendar the time it takes to go from point A to point B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Society and Forbidden Planet London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/japan-society-and-forbidden-planet-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 08:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/japan-society-and-forbidden-planet-london/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday , on my way from an event to a meeting, I made two stops. The first one in Forbidden Planet.
Forbidden Planet is a comic store that I enjoyed tremendously while living in New York. While not exactly Tokyo’s Mandarake, Forbidden Planet had enough variety to make it interesting. What I did not know is that they had such a large store in London! It is a fun place full of comic (and non-comic) books, manga, merchandise, figures, posters…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the Amazon Web Services Summit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/invited-to-the-amazon-web-services-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 07:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/invited-to-the-amazon-web-services-summit/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday and Thursday, I was invited to attend the Amazon Web Services Summit in London’s Excel center.
Besides an exhibition area with many vendors (some of them already suppliers to my company) like NewRelic, DataDog, GitHub, Chef, Alscient, Teradici, DataPipe, Ruxit, CloudCheckr, Amazon Activate, Elastic, Redis, etc, all with their great swag (mostly t-shirts and stickers, but lots of giveaways, from drones to iWatches), the highlight was the conference sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking to Prof. Church about machine learning applied to genomic research</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/talking-to-prof.-church-about-machine-learning-applied-to-genomic-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 12:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/talking-to-prof.-church-about-machine-learning-applied-to-genomic-research/</guid>
      <description>During my flight to Boston I read “Regenesis”, the interesting genomic science book by Professor George Church, which was a gift from my friend Dr. Raminderpal Singh.
On Wednesday evening I had a very interesting conversation in Boston with both of them. Neither of them needs an introduction in the genomics world, but for those of you outside the field:
 Raminder is Vice-president at Eagle Genomics and Advisor at Kanteron Systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Festival of Genomics Boston</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/festival-of-genomics-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 15:43:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/festival-of-genomics-boston/</guid>
      <description>June 28 and 29 I attended, along with my friend John Memarian, President &amp;amp; CCO of my company Kanteron Systems, the Festival of Genomics Boston, as a Microsoft Genomics Group partner.
Although the show was small, it was a great opportunity to network with industry and academic experts (from Harvard Professors to Illumina executives) and learn.
From scientific posters to the latest sequencing technologies, from robotic arms to genomics experiments in space, it was great #geekfun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Father’s Day gift: building a Picade with my son</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/ultimate-fathers-day-gift-building-a-picade-with-my-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 13:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/ultimate-fathers-day-gift-building-a-picade-with-my-son/</guid>
      <description>For Father’s Day (we live in London, so we celebrate it today, unlike in Spain which is March 19) my wife gave me the “Ultimate Father`s Day” gift, from TechCamp UK. [Thank you, love!]
It consisted of a workshop with other father-son / father-daughter “teams”, held at the Iron Yard (The Leathermarket – London), where we built a desktop arcade machine in 5 hours (including lunch break), following the directions from Tom and Tom, using the Picadeset, setting up and using the Raspberry Pi, custom OS, emulators, ROMs, loudspeakers, power supply, LCD screen, etc:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to InfoSecurity Europe</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-infosecurity-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 15:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-infosecurity-europe/</guid>
      <description>Today I was invited to attend InfoSecurity Europe, Europe`s largest Information Security industry event.
As always, it was interesting to have a chance to catch up with this rapidly moving field, and a great opportunity to chat with old friends.
Apart from gimmicks (VR everywhere, car racing and helicopter simulators, giant robots, etc), swag (all kinds of Star Wars and other Sci-Fi related giveaways, from toys to t-shirts) and junk food (from candy to icecream to chips, the booths did not have healthy alternatives, although the food vendors did), the most interesting part of these events is always the talks, specifically the hands-on demos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited with my son to Intel Buzz videogame developer workshop</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-with-my-son-to-intel-buzz-videogame-developer-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 17:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-with-my-son-to-intel-buzz-videogame-developer-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Today I was invited, along with my son, who at 14 has been a videogame developer for years, to attend the Intel Buzz videogame developer workshop. It was not only a lot of fun, but WONDERFUL to attend with him!
Although a small event, it ended up being extremely interesting, with an area to try indie games and new technologies, and a long list of talks and panels, including one-on-ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to Microsoft Research Cambridge workshop: Computing in Cancer</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-microsoft-research-cambridge-workshop-computing-in-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 06:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-microsoft-research-cambridge-workshop-computing-in-cancer/</guid>
      <description>May 27 I was invited to participate in the “Computing in Cancer Workshop” organized by Microsoft Research in Cambridge.
It was a great opportunity to network, meet with colleagues and other researchers, and especially to learn a lot.
The fascinating lectures were:
 Antonio Criminisi (Principal Researcher, Microsoft Research): Machine Learning for Medical Image Analysis Jasmin Fisher (Senior Researcher, Microsoft Research): Virtual Models of Cancer Giles Maskell (President, Royal College of Radiologists): Current problems in diagnostic radiology Fiona Gilbert (Head of the Department of Radiology, University of Cambridge) Dennis Wang (Senior Bioinformatics Scientist, AstraZeneca): Predicting drug combinations and biomarkers of response: a crowd-sourced solution Florian Markowetz (University of Cambridge, CRUK Cambridge Institute): Quantifying patterns of tumour evolution Francesca Buffa (Associate Professor, Department of Oncology, University of Oxford): In-silico systems biology and functional genomics approaches to accelerate biomarker discovery Hoifung Poon (Researcher, Microsoft Research): Machine Reading for Cancer Panomics Raj Jena (Academic Consultant Clinical Oncologist, Cambridge University Hospitals): Computing for Radiation Oncology – from cell culture to the clinic Bertie Gottgens (Professor of Molecular Haematology, University of Cambridge): Defining Cell States and Regulatory Networks using Single Cell Genomics  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up my first art exhibit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/setting-up-my-first-art-exhibit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 14:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/setting-up-my-first-art-exhibit/</guid>
      <description>The weekend of February 27 and 28 I set up my first art exhibition as Independent International Art Curator.
In collaboration with the Internet Freedom Festival, held in Las Naves (Valencia) from 2 to 6 March, Net Freedom Art Showis an international, itinerant, collective and multidisciplinary contemporary art show. After its debut in Valencia, it will be exhibited in galleries around the world (New York, London, Santiago de Chile, and Kaunas).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft comes to Valencia to meet with my team, collaborate on medical technology research, and discuss a Term Sheet</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/microsoft-comes-to-valencia-to-meet-with-my-team-collaborate-on-medical-technology-research-and-discuss-a-term-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 08:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/microsoft-comes-to-valencia-to-meet-with-my-team-collaborate-on-medical-technology-research-and-discuss-a-term-sheet/</guid>
      <description>On February 25 a group of medical imaging researchers from Microsoft came to our company’s headquarters in Valencia (Spain) for a day-long workshop on bleeding edge medical image software.
I must admit that just a few years ago I would have laughed at the idea of such an occurrence for many reasons. But things change, and now Microsoft is much more open (and convinced) about Open Source software, their researchers have demonstrated exceptional ability in advanced medical imaging analysis algorithms (unlike their failed business strategy around Amalga), and my company has grown and innovated to the point where it captures the interest and even enthusiasm of some of the largest technology companies in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Big Bang Data” and “Tintin” exhibitions at Somerset House, London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/01/big-bang-data-and-tintin-exhibitions-at-somerset-house-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 18:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/01/big-bang-data-and-tintin-exhibitions-at-somerset-house-london/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we went to see a couple exhibitions at Somerset House, in London.
The first exhibition we saw was “TINTIN: Hergé`s Masterpiece”. Basic but obviously appealing, it was too crowded to be enjoyable.
The second one was “Big Bang Data”.
While undoubtedly interesting, especially for someone who works in, teaches, and loves bid data and technology like myself, to me the most interesting aspect of this exhibition is that everyone who was there had already experienced the subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A couple days in Zürich</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/a-couple-days-in-z%C3%BCrich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 10:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/a-couple-days-in-z%C3%BCrich/</guid>
      <description>I spent Wednesday evening and most of Thursday in Zürich.
On Wednesday I had dinner with some business partners; “business as usual”.
But on Thursday, after my business presentation to potential customers, I had the very rare and exclusive opportunity to visit one of the main data centers in Switzerland. Here are some impressive facts about them:
 they host 1/3 of Swiss banks data internet traffic = 40% of Switzerland’s internet traffic energy bill = 2 million Swiss Franks per annum 2 different energy suppliers from 2 different access points, with preferential oil supply in case of a failure (full reserves for 5 days for the generators) almost 50 telecoms suppliers, from many different countries, providing direct access for their customers worldwide RFIDs paired with 3D fingerprint scanners which measure the fingerprint but also the morphology, pulse and temperature separate isolated room to open packages, to minimize the risk of fire single person magnetic doors temperature, movement, and sound sensors double-gated entrance even to the parking lot!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing in London… even with Microsoft!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/playing-in-london-even-with-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 09:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/playing-in-london-even-with-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>These past few days have been quite “playful”.
On the one hand, I have just discovered, right around the corner from our apartment by London Bridge, a free and public playground that has an artificial grass hockey field, half a basketball court, 3 pingpong tables and even a beach volleyball court with sand and all! So obviously, the next day I went with my son to a sports equipment store and bought a soccer ball, a pingpong set, a basketball, a volleyball and a badminton set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the TechHubIs5 Party in Shoreditch</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/invited-to-the-techhubis5-party-in-shoreditch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 16:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/invited-to-the-techhubis5-party-in-shoreditch/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday we (Carlos and Victoria from Kanteron, my wife and I) were invited, since we are members, to the TechHub 5th birthday party at an abandoned textile warehouse in London.
The party was expertly organized by the TechHub crew, and had everything you need to ensure a great party: two DJs, karaoke, photo-booth, grilled cheese sandwiches, ice-cream, cupcakes, booze, and cool tech (this time it was the HP Sprout).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Next Event: NY vs London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/google-next-event-ny-vs-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 14:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/google-next-event-ny-vs-london/</guid>
      <description>On June 23 I was invited to attend the Google Next Event, as a customer of Google and a potential partner.
It was quite a shock comparing the overall tone and spirit to the same event in New York, last year.
In New York everything was oriented toward networking, and you had the feeling that anyone could be anyone, and it didn`t matter if they represented a large company or a &amp;ldquo;start-up wannabe&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working at Google Campus London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/working-at-google-campus-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 11:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/working-at-google-campus-london/</guid>
      <description>I have been working at the Google-TechHub Campus in Shoreditch (the “Silicon Roundabout”) London for a few weeks. It is really cool. In no particular order, here are some things I love about this place:
 A cafeteria (open to anyone) with terrace, foosball table, bitcoin machine, device bar (to test your developments in many different devices) and even a spacesuit! A small but well stocked library of tech books Very nice team, from security to reception, to admin, to social media… all of them Two levels of office space, one of them (supposedly) “quiet zone” Unlimited supplies of toast and tea, great wifi, and good scanners/printers A ton of areas to sit down and have a meeting, not just the “meeting rooms” Most importantly: the events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My talk at the Circumvention Tech Festival, March 4th</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/my-talk-at-the-circumvention-tech-festival-march-4th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 23:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/my-talk-at-the-circumvention-tech-festival-march-4th/</guid>
      <description>This past winter I met Sandy and James from Open ITP in New York, and Pepe from Valencia. They were organizing the Circumvention Tech Festivalto be held in Las Naves, Valencia (Spain) March 1-6.
They invited me to give a talk, which was eventually scheduled for March 4th at 3pm. I titled the talk “When privacy does not mean the same to you and me”. It was meant to generate debate, to expose other people’s points of view, rather than to be a unidirectional speech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin and block chain event in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/02/bitcoin-and-block-chain-event-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/02/bitcoin-and-block-chain-event-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>On Monday, February 9, I attended a Bitcoin – Blockchain eventwith my wife at law firm Latham &amp;amp; Watkins in New York, organized by Hedgeable.

Over 100 bitcoin enthusiasts, investors, journalists, lawyers, and entrepreneurs networking over food and beverages, with demos from:
and a round table of Bitcoin innovation experts:
Since I have already started researching the application of the block chain technology for healthcare, it was quite a useful event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have invites for OnePlus and Ello</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/i-have-invites-for-oneplus-and-ello/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 13:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/i-have-invites-for-oneplus-and-ello/</guid>
      <description>If anyone wants an invite to buy a OnePlus, the best phone in the market, or to join Ello, the social network that does not sell your data, send me a message.
STW</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick family visit in Valencia</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/quick-family-visit-in-valencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 09:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/quick-family-visit-in-valencia/</guid>
      <description>Of course, everytime I go to Europe I make sure I stop in Valencia and see my kids. It makes me SO tremendously happy to see them! I can’t wait until we can all live in the same city again. Some day, soon.
We had fun meeting the family (although my parents were on a cruise), projecting movies at night on the “large screen” over the living room windows, and playing all kinds of games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Circumvention Tech Festival</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/the-circumvention-tech-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 15:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/the-circumvention-tech-festival/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wearable review: Withings Pulse Ox, WS-30 WiFi scale, and Blood Pressure Monitor</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/wearable-review-withings-pulse-ox-ws-30-wifi-scale-and-blood-pressure-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 20:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/wearable-review-withings-pulse-ox-ws-30-wifi-scale-and-blood-pressure-monitor/</guid>
      <description>Due to the launch of the biosensors module for my company`s medical imaging and data solution a few days ago, the Withings company sent me a biosensor (wearable) Withings Pulse Ox, manometer BPM and WiFi WS-30 scale for testing and integration tests ahead of some national projects we are about to sign in London and Santiago de Chile.
All three came in luxury packaging, and were relatively easy to connect and set up, at least for a &amp;ldquo;tinkerer&amp;rdquo; (there are people who gets annoyed if I use &amp;ldquo;hacker&amp;rdquo; as a synonym, although it is) like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My new OnePlus One phone is amazing</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/my-new-oneplus-one-phone-is-amazing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 22:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/my-new-oneplus-one-phone-is-amazing/</guid>
      <description>I have just bought a OnePlusOne phone, and have been using it for a couple of days. Let me tell you: it`s AMAZING.
If you have never heard of the company, dont worry, youre not alone. But you should definitely check it out, because their phones are incredibly high quality, high specs, and low price (mine was $349). No catch:
 Qualcomm© Snapdragon™ 801 processor with 2.5GHz Quad-core CPUs Adreno 330 GPU, 578MHz 64 GB eMMC 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I was forced to hack into Schiphol Airport wifi</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/i-was-forced-to-hack-into-schiphol-airport-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 12:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/i-was-forced-to-hack-into-schiphol-airport-wifi/</guid>
      <description>A couple weeks ago I was at Schiphol Airport in Amsterdam. Of course, when I arrive in an airport with enough time ahead of my boarding, I look for a plug and wifi. Luckily Schiphol is an excellent airport, offering both. The only problem is that every time I clicked on the &amp;ldquo;Enjoy unlimited free wifi – Connect&amp;rdquo; button, I got an &amp;ldquo;Unknown error 0&amp;rdquo; message back.
 Don`t tell me &amp;ldquo;Enjoy unlimited free wifi&amp;rdquo; and then try to prevent me from accessing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In The Netherlands: Utrecht and Amsterdam</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/in-the-netherlands-utrecht-and-amsterdam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 11:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/in-the-netherlands-utrecht-and-amsterdam/</guid>
      <description>As soon as I arrived in Utrecht, Diederik took me to a lunch at a very nice restaurant, inside an industrial complex: Zuiver. Both him and the waiter suggested the smoked eel salad, and I must agree, it was delicious.
Then, after a couple of very interesting meetings, he took me to dinner to another very nice restaurant, this time in the colorful and very touristy Red Light District: ANNA, where we had pre-appetizer, appetizer, main course, pre-dessert, and dessert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Lego cable management solution</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/08/my-lego-cable-management-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 21:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/08/my-lego-cable-management-solution/</guid>
      <description>After a month traveling throughout Europe (posts and pictures soon), I returned to New York and I needed to catch up with work. In order to be more productive I had to tackle the &amp;ldquo;cable jungle&amp;rdquo; challenge. Quick and easy (and cool) solution? LEGO!
Just attach some velcro to the back of a Lego, attach it to the edge of your desk, get some of your favorite figures, have them &amp;ldquo;hold their arms up&amp;rdquo;, and let them hold the USB and charger cables for you 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the IBM Federal Summit, Washington DC</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/at-the-ibm-federal-summit-washington-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 13:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/at-the-ibm-federal-summit-washington-dc/</guid>
      <description>Last Wednesday I participated in IBM’s Federal Summit at the Ronald Reagan Federal Building in Washington DC.
Business aside, it was one scary meeting. There were control systems all over. From the IRS to airports, to National Security, the demos were much more advanced and comprehensive than anything you may have seen in a movie. Big Brother to the Nth degree. They know it all about you. In a second. You either get paranoid-serious about security, encryption and privacy, or you might as well forget completely about your privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reset the net</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning quantum computer programming</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/learning-quantum-computer-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 11:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/learning-quantum-computer-programming/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I started learning and experimenting with quantum computing programming. Its not easy to express the fun and excitement that experience brought me, but Ill try:
Programming a quantum computer is different than programming a binary (0 and 1) &amp;ldquo;digital&amp;rdquo; computer. To program a quantum system, you have to map a problem into a search for the “lowest point&amp;rdquo; in a very large pool of options, which corresponds to the best possible outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking at the CUNY President`s office</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/networking-at-the-cuny-presidents-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 19:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/networking-at-the-cuny-presidents-office/</guid>
      <description>On May 6th, having just returned from quick trips to Cleveland and Atlanta, I attended with my wife the round table debate &amp;ldquo;Curiosity, Understanding, and Utility: Science and the Creative Economy&amp;rdquo; held at the City University of New York Graduate Center`s Proshansky Auditorium.
William Bialek, director of the Graduate Center`s Initiative for the Theoretical Sciences, moderated a discussion with Jennifer Tour Chayes, distinguished scientist and managing director of Microsoft Research New England and Microsoft Research New York City; Fernando Pereira, research at Google; and Chris Wiggins, chief data scientist at the New York Times and faculty member in the Department of Applied Mathematics and Applied Physics at Columbia University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited by Google to the Google Cloud Platform presentation</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-by-google-to-the-google-cloud-platform-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-by-google-to-the-google-cloud-platform-presentation/</guid>
      <description>March 25 Google NY invited me to their Google Cloud Platformpresentation in their Chelsea offices, 8 blocks away from my apartment.
Besides the interesting new features (here are the videos), and the delicious and healthy lunch buffet, I networked quite a lot, and had a few laughs about the highest concentration of Google Glasses per person I have seen so far. One thing is clear: genomics, which is one of the main things my two companies deal with, and the cloud, are closely related, and they will be even more in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromecast &#43; Hola = Multimedia freedom</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/02/chromecast-hola-multimedia-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 18:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/02/chromecast-hola-multimedia-freedom/</guid>
      <description>How many times have you tried to access online media that was not available in your country? How many times have you gotten frustrated with proxy services?
How many times have you wished there was an easy way to wirelessly display online content on your TV without paying for expensive privative boxes?
Enter Hola.org+ ChromecastHola is a free browser extension used by 14 million people to access geographically restricted online media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the introduction of IBM Watson at WTC NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/invited-to-the-introduction-of-ibm-watson-at-wtc-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 13:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/invited-to-the-introduction-of-ibm-watson-at-wtc-ny/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday January 8th I was asked to hold a meeting regarding the potential involvement of my company (Kanteron Systems) in IBM’s Watson. It was a late night meeting, on the 54th floor of the still under construction World Trade Center. The reason why the meeting took place there is because the IBM team was finishing the set up of the next day’s Watson presentation.
What is Watson, you may ask?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a simple hack</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/testing-a-simple-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 14:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/testing-a-simple-hack/</guid>
      <description>I use qtranslate as a multi-language plugin for my blog. It`s an excellent solution, but the problem is that everytime Word Press is updated, it takes days, and sometimes weeeks, for the plugin author to update it.
So, tired of waiting, I have found a quick and simple hack to make it work with the latests WP 3.8 update: edit qtranslate.php to
 define(‘QT_SUPPORTED_WP_VERSION, ‘3.8);
 You`re welcome 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NY ComicCon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/ny-comiccon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 23:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/ny-comiccon/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5934418147899482241]
After going the other day with Maker Fairewith my parents, yesterday we went backto ComicCon. The usual: cosplay, crowds, swag&amp;hellip; FUN!!
UPDATE: here is a list of interesting links (artists, publishing houses, software, etc) we collected there.
Artists/Comics:
 Bill Plympton (studio, blog, store, tumblr), whom I have admired for many years, was there in person. Cool! Dylan (UpsideDownGrin) Rich Miller (FilthWorks) Selina Briggs (The Jelly Empire) The Gate Crashers  Studios/Stores:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with the robot (Roomba)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/08/playing-with-the-robot-roomba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 15:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/08/playing-with-the-robot-roomba/</guid>
      <description>We got great gifts for our wedding, but hands down, the best (ever!) is A ROBOT.
My mother-in-law got us a robot. Got that? How cool is that!?
And it is not to make her daughter’s life easier, because I am the one who vacuums at home. She did it because it is cool. Heck yeah it is!
So the Roombais nothing new. It has been around for a decade already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to abide to the law while rejecting threats</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/how-to-abide-to-the-law-while-rejecting-threats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 14:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/how-to-abide-to-the-law-while-rejecting-threats/</guid>
      <description>According to Spanish law
web(emphasis mine):
 Information intermediary suppliers:
    Do not have an obligation to supervise the contents they host, transmit, or classify in a link directory, but must collaborate with public authorities when required to interrupt an IT service or take a content down.
    They are not, in principle, responsible for alien content they host, transmit, or give access to, but could incur in responsibility if they take an active participation in its ellaboration or, if knowing of a particular material being being illegal, do not act swiftly to take it down or prevent access to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am requested to take a link down and... Streisand effect!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 01:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</guid>
      <description>Today I received this email (it was in Spanish, I have translated it into English because that is the main language of this blog, and in order to give this issue the international coverage that it deserves – sorry for any translation mistake since I am not a lawyer and he writes like an old-fashioned one trying to sound intimidating; here is the original):
 Mr. Cortell:
Currently I am suing Greg Prévôt in the Courts of Barcelona, author of a defamatory site which infringes upon my honor, whose link appears in which you administer, at the following address:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VII Japan Society CUTS Contemporary Japanese Film Festival</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/vii-japan-society-cuts-contemporary-japanese-film-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 15:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/vii-japan-society-cuts-contemporary-japanese-film-festival/</guid>
      <description>The Japan Society CUTS Contemporary Japanese Film Festivalis one of my favorites.
This year we saw four very different but delightful (in their own way) fims, all of them USA premieres and Co-presented with the New York Asian Film Festival:
The Festival Opening Film, with Introduction and Q&amp;amp;A with Director Toshiaki Toyoda, and after film party. Interesting story about death, life, cults&amp;hellip;
Of course, while we were in the area, with so many Japanese restaurants in 47th, we tried:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting NY tech companies</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/meeting-ny-tech-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 17:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/meeting-ny-tech-companies/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5879766487788118305]
Friday May 17th I took the day to meet some of the interesting tech companies present in New York. There are over 1,200 tech companies in NY(including CodeAcademy, KickStarter, Foursquare, MakerBot, ZocDoc, Guilt, AppNexus, Tumblr, Etsy, KickStarter, Automatic&amp;hellip; and mine!), most between the Flat Iron and SoHo areas of Manhattan (Silicon ALley). So I chose a few that, for one reason or another, I was interested in meeting and talk to their founders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working distractions</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/working-distractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 13:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/working-distractions/</guid>
      <description>If I go to the office, I complain that there are too many distractions: whether it is the boom-boom music form the downstairs SoHo store, my coworkers playing ping-pong, street art that requires my attention, or the temptation of a Japanese bento box or mochi with tea&amp;hellip;
But if I stay at home, Calvin makes sure I am not as productive as I could be.
OK, I admit it, this was a very silly excuse to try a new slider plugin with Pinterest non-official API&amp;hellip; and trying those things is not a diversion or distraction, is part of my job, I swear!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look at the data, just look at it!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/look-at-the-data-just-look-at-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 14:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/look-at-the-data-just-look-at-it/</guid>
      <description>Carna botnet offers us this amazing 24 hour visualization of relative IPv4 utilization observed using ICMP Ping requests.
Look at the data, just look at it! Dont you see peoples sleeping patterns, internet usage patterns, eating schedule habit, cultural differences, urban influence, regional inequalities&amp;hellip;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in NY: Wired Magazine and IBM Smart Camp</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/back-in-ny-wired-magazine-and-ibm-smart-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 17:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/back-in-ny-wired-magazine-and-ibm-smart-camp/</guid>
      <description>After MIT`s crazy week, back in NY I needed a couple of days of sleep and relax to get back into the normal rhythm. Luckily it was SuperBowl weekend, so the streets (and Chelsea Market) were fairly empty!
So on Tuesday I was ready to get going full speed ahead. First, after meeting with P. Oberton in the NYPL, then I went to Condé Nast publications` building, into Wired Magazine, to discuss a PR campaign/project along with Valencia Regional Minister of Industry (&amp;amp; etc) Max Buch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT final day (6)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/mit-final-day-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 17:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/mit-final-day-6/</guid>
      <description>The final day was an interesting one.
My team (team senZa) choose me to do the presentation of the teams project. We all thought we did an excellent job, and everybody in the room (372) congratulated us. One of the judges even said &amp;quot;it is the best one I have ever seen&amp;quot;. But... lo and behold, we were not selected to the final round. And whats even worst, we received almost no feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT day 5</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/mit-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 16:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/mit-day-5/</guid>
      <description>Day 5 started with a presentation of MIT`s eMBA and the REAP program.
After that, lectures by William Aulet, Scott Keating, Paul Maeder, and Antoinette Schoar.
And then&amp;hellip; an all-nighter preparing the group project. Tension, stress, frustration, but in the end a great feeling of accomplishment, and pride in a job well done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT day 4</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/mit-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 16:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/mit-day-4/</guid>
      <description>Day 4 started with a corporate presentation (we got to choose, and I attended the one by Pfizer) at 7:30am, in which Pfizer`s Senior Vice President of Research and Development talked about the rapidly shifting way in which big pharma is working, and mentioned an unacceptable fact that should make us all reflect on how much the patent system is broken:
 Pfizer has 98,000 employees&amp;hellip; and 31,000 lawyers!
 The rest of the day I attended classes by Catherine Tucker, Brian Halligan, and a speech by Dean David Schmittlein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT day 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/mit-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 16:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/mit-day-3/</guid>
      <description>Day 3 started with my winning the Twitter competition with this tweet:
Then we had classes by Matt Marx,William Aulet, Elaine Chen, and John McEleney.
Even during lunch (at room E52, 6th floor of the Martin Trust Center for MIT Entrepreneurship – Tang Building) we are lectured. In this case by Scott Stern. Non stop from 7am until 8pm (or later, depending on how hard working your team is).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT day 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/mit-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 00:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/mit-day-2/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5838741007492762897]
Snowing, cold, snow, cold&amp;hellip;
Day 2 of the MIT-EDP program has been crazy. Breakfast at 7:00am, classes from 9:00am until 7:00pm, with a lunch break that was actually a lecture too, and two 15 minute breaks in which we were suppose to sign up for company visits, pick up material, etc&amp;hellip;
But it was worth it: William Aulet, and Fiona Murray are excellent lecturers with obviously a lot of experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/mit-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/mit-day-1/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5838342469980149841]
Today is my first day as a student of &amp;quot;the most important university in the world&amp;rdquo; (according to this article): MIT.
I am here to take the MIT Sloan Executive EducationEDP (Entrepreneurship Development Program).
Getting up at 4 am and braving the fluoutbreakin Boston and the cold weather including a frozen Charles River (not like it is less cold in NY anyway), I arrived from NY this morning in an early flight, and after checking in at the Marriot, I went to a luncheon at the Towne Stove and Spiritsrestaurant sponsored by Ken Morse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instead of Halloween party</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/instead-of-halloween-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 15:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/instead-of-halloween-party/</guid>
      <description>I`m still stuck in Baltimore, but it seems I will be able to return to NY late tonight, arrivingtomorrow morningafternoon, the day after Halloween (which reaches amazing levels, like Barbie special edition dolls).
So, instead of going to the Village Halloween parade(which has been cancelled for the first time in 39 years), or anyof the Halloween parties I was invited to (the New Museum and Cara`s parties have also been cancelled), and wear the cool and simple MineCraft Creeper costume Cory Doctorow twitted(from Comic Con NY):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections from NY Comic Con</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 09:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I went to NY Comic Con, like everyone else, I guess, with the idea of having fun, of experiencing first hand one of the &amp;ldquo;major events&amp;rdquo; that a true nerdy geek can attend. I also wanted to meet Cory Doctorow (although we actually ended up not meeting). It has been years since I last met him, and it was the perfect &amp;ldquo;excuse&amp;rdquo; to attend the conference.
When I arrived, I was really surprised to see the size of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft, derivative works, parodies...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 10:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</guid>
      <description>Hugo sends me thisamazing song/video made in Minecraft. Of course, that leads to 10more, 14more&amp;hellip; there are so many!
When you make the tools available to the people, and allow them to create (in this case under the safe harbor of &amp;ldquo;parody&amp;rdquo;) wonderful things happen. Its NOT all about the money, profit, control... Its about imagination, art, creativity, culture. Thats how it happens: copying, re-using, mixing, adjusting, modifying... thats what creativity is really about (or did you think it was about &amp;ldquo;inventing&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;making unheard of things out of thin air&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun at Hackers On Planet Earth 9 – New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/fun-at-hackers-on-planet-earth-9-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 17:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/fun-at-hackers-on-planet-earth-9-new-york/</guid>
      <description>July 13th-15th Alvaro and I attended Hope9(Hackers On Planet Earth number 9) conference in New York`s Hotel Pennsylvania.
It was a lot of fun, as usual. Besides the many and informative talks(we gave one on &amp;ldquo;Digital Security in Health Care Institutions&amp;rdquo;, the first day), there was music, booths (FSF, EFFwith a girl that wanted to come to Spain to help the #indignados, Free Manning, No Starch PressBooks and more), arduino and lock-picking classes, a pro-ponies and against-zombies USA Presidential Candidate wearing a boot on his head, MakerBot3D printers, the IMMI, Hackers For Charity, AlphaOneHackerSpace (will be visiting it next Thursday with Audrey), StartUpHire, SparkleLabs(awesome presents for kids and n00bies!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two biggest Lytro pitfalls</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/two-biggest-lytro-pitfalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 11:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/two-biggest-lytro-pitfalls/</guid>
      <description>After playing with it for a while, beyond it limitations (light, format, movement&amp;hellip;) here are the two biggest pitfalls with the Lytro camera:
  It is still for Mac OSX only. They NEED to come out with Open Source / Free Software (both their software AND platform support for GNU/Linux).
  Picture library size and location. BIG unresolved issue.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I beat Watson at Jeopardy (more or less)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 18:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in my previous post, at IBM Innovation Center in Chicago they have a Watson(more info here) interactive kiosk with which to play an interactive game of Jeopardy. In case you have been living in a cave for the past few months, Watson beatJeopardy human champions on live TV, the significanceof which can not be overstated.
Now, remember: this is a &amp;ldquo;small version&amp;rdquo; of Watson, and a &amp;ldquo;self-contained&amp;rdquo; version of Jeopardy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry Elephants</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/angry-elephants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 21:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/angry-elephants/</guid>
      <description>via APM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech is a tool, people are stupid</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/tech-is-a-tool-people-are-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 13:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/tech-is-a-tool-people-are-stupid/</guid>
      <description>Technology is getting easier to use everyday. Take GNU/Linux distributions as an example: anyone can make their own. Does that mean everyone should make their own? Why not? But then, again, we end up with things like Ubuntu Satanic(and their Ubuntu SE 666.10 “Necrophiliac Neuromancer”), Hannah Montana Linux(how far would you go to attract kids to free software?), or Red Star OS(free software for North Korea and non-free browsing? WTF?).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A conversation with Walt Mossberg and Kara Swisher at NYU</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/a-conversation-with-walt-mossberg-and-kara-swisher-at-nyu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 11:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/a-conversation-with-walt-mossberg-and-kara-swisher-at-nyu/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday I went to New York University for a nice conversation in the Inside the Internet Garageseries, with journalists Walt Mossberg and Kara Swisher (AllThingsDigital, Wall Street Journal, etc).
Besides the very interesting bio/background overview of them that the interviewer did, here are some quotes that caught my attention.
Walt Mossberg:
 IT departments are the most regressive force in tech, blocking new tech adoption
The story goes that Larry Page asked Steve Jobs for advice, he said &amp;ldquo;Find the 5 things you do best, and focus on it&amp;rdquo;, which its what hes doing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geekest prom date</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/geekest-prom-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 10:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/geekest-prom-date/</guid>
      <description>And you thought I was talking about Princess Leia?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The danger of graphs and cold data</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</guid>
      <description>After posting graphs and cold data (quite ilustrative, I believe), and the discussion it has generated (people, why don`t you use the &amp;ldquo;comment&amp;rdquo; instead all the other unstructured methods you are using?), please let me write a caveat about graphs and cold data.
In my high-tech gym, you have the option to have a lot of data collected, for your own, private and personal use. It seems like a great idea at first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newspaper map (with translations)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/newspaper-map-with-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 12:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/newspaper-map-with-translations/</guid>
      <description>Map + Newspapers + Translations = Simple and AWESOME!!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In 3D with Firefox`s new TILT inspector</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/in-3d-with-firefoxs-new-tilt-inspector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 12:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/in-3d-with-firefoxs-new-tilt-inspector/</guid>
      <description>Lego web design, anyone? 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social-media inspired cocktails at Mandarin Oriental NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/social-media-inspired-cocktails-at-mandarin-oriental-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 11:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/social-media-inspired-cocktails-at-mandarin-oriental-ny/</guid>
      <description>seen in Tumblr (user: hragv)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marvel Marathon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/marvel-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 23:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/marvel-marathon/</guid>
      <description>From the #thisIsHowItsDone (not the movie adaptations, but special events to make people go more to the movie theaters) department, here is an awesome initiative from AMC movie theaters:
Get ready to watch the greatest Marvel movie event ever held at your local AMC Theatre on May 3rd! Experience THE ULTIMATE MARVEL MARATHON with six movies on one epic day. Watch the heroes’ stories unfold as they assemble for the midnight premiere of The Avengers 3D!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with face.com face recognition technology</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/playing-with-face.com-face-recognition-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 17:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/playing-with-face.com-face-recognition-technology/</guid>
      <description>While I am preparing a loooooong post about technology and privacy (with a provocative twist, for a change 😈 ), I have decided to play with face.com‘s face recognition technology.
What do you think? On target (hint: no, not on target, I am not THAT old, and definitely I AM a male)? Scary (hint: only if we are unaware of these technologies and their uses)?&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is your Mac infected? Find out (and fix it if it is)!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/is-your-mac-infected-find-out-and-fix-it-if-it-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 17:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/is-your-mac-infected-find-out-and-fix-it-if-it-is/</guid>
      <description>Over 600,000 Macs are infected with the FlashBack Trojan. Is yours one of those? Let`s find out.
Open the Terminal (c`mon, be a hacker, not a slacker) and type:
if it says:
 The domain/default pair of (/Applications/Safari.app/Contents/Info, LSEnvironment) does not exist
 that means your Mac is ok so far (otherwise, go here). Then type:
if it says:
 The domain/default pair of (/Users/[your user name here]/.MacOSX/environment, DYLD_INSERT_LIBRARIES) does not exist</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real convergence</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/real-convergence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 05:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/real-convergence/</guid>
      <description>Reading RSS on my smartphone, click on a YouTube video, send it to the computer via Phone2Chrome&amp;hellip;
I read on a newspaper tablet version that TED is now on Netflix, turn on the Google TV Logitech Revue with Able Remote on my phone and start Netflix, adding TED to my Instant Que&amp;hellip;
Remember all that &amp;ldquo;convergence&amp;rdquo; talk?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArtHack Exhibit closing party in Brooklyn</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 22:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday I went to the ArtHack Exhibitclosing party at 319 ScholesSt, Brooklyn (New York).
Located in an industrial complex in Brooklyn, at night, loooong two blocks from the subway, graffiti all over, small door&amp;hellip; that gave way to heaven: young (I was the oldest hacker in that space, but I did not feel that way) energetic happy people tinkering with technology and proudly showing their &amp;ldquo;toys&amp;rdquo; (hacks, mashups, creations, or whatever).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RePress: fight online censorship with a WP Plug-In</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/repress-fight-online-censorship-with-a-wp-plug-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 17:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/repress-fight-online-censorship-with-a-wp-plug-in/</guid>
      <description>I just installed RePress: This plug-in enables you to magically uncensor any website on the internet from your own WordPress installation. Why and How.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data visualization of twitter activity with embedded game</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/data-visualization-of-twitter-activity-with-embedded-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2012 15:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/data-visualization-of-twitter-activity-with-embedded-game/</guid>
      <description>That`s what I call a fun mix (hint: throw the bird against the columns): httpss://vizify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color associations: red and yellow</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/color-associations-red-and-yellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 05:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/color-associations-red-and-yellow/</guid>
      <description>Seeing certain color combinations, associations are sure to fly into anybody`s minds.
Usually, red and yellow will bring to mind things like flags (of Spain, Catalonia-Valencia, R, Security, and adding some shapes you could even think of Macedonia or China).
Beyond flags, Axomil, sunset, fire, peppers,tullips, ballons, ketchup and mustard, Flash, soccer referee cards, Superman&amp;hellip; there are SO many options.
But when you consider the hue, tone, context, memory, and further additional information, then those options start to get reduced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you like Science, you will like...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/if-you-like-science-you-will-like.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 18:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/if-you-like-science-you-will-like.../</guid>
      <description>Source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ode to the pen</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/ode-to-the-pen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 18:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/ode-to-the-pen/</guid>
      <description>See in Scientific American:
 &amp;ldquo;I could not survive without a ballpoint pen in my back pocket. It`s invaluable for scribbling notes on the front of my hand (my version of the PalmPilot&amp;hellip;) to remind me to do things I used to be able to remember unaided before my age converged with my IQ while traveling in opposite directions.&amp;rdquo;
 _John P. MooreProfessor of Microbiology and Immunology
Weill Medical College of Cornell University, New York City_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook: couple breaker for drunks</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/facebook-couple-breaker-for-drunks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 05:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/facebook-couple-breaker-for-drunks/</guid>
      <description>Interesting couple of trivia about Facebook in UK:
 Facebook blamed for one-third marriage breakdowns British Facebook users intoxicated in 76% of their photos  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun interpreting signs</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/fun-interpreting-signs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 17:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/fun-interpreting-signs/</guid>
      <description>The world around us is full of signs. I wont go on dabble about _signifiers_, _meanings_, and the psychoanalitycal importance of the _word_. But sometimes I just cant help myself, when I see a sign begging for a creative interpretation:
Cmon, dont tell me you don`t see something like:
 If you press this button, your mouth will become a hotspot
 or
 A giant asteroid is heading towards your SpaceInvaders spacecraft, push the button to destroy the asteroid with a Dune-sque voice-blast</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anxiety quantifiers</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/anxiety-quantifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2011 02:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/anxiety-quantifiers/</guid>
      <description>We all know them, c`mon, add to the list. Here are some examples to get you going:
 Number of tabs opened in browser Number of virtualized OSs in a single box Number of unread emails per hour Number of unread RSSs (or number of feeds) Number of saved sites on Delicious, Pulse, whatever Number of post drafts Number of beta-invites to be accepted  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Below zero... even on Google</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/below-zero...-even-on-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 19:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/below-zero...-even-on-google/</guid>
      <description>To celebrate the falling temperatures in NY, try typing &amp;ldquo;let it snow&amp;rdquo; on Google`s search box (you can even wipe the screen with your mouse) 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI?</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 11:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/ai/</guid>
      <description>😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of a cycle counter</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-importance-of-a-cycle-counter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 14:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-importance-of-a-cycle-counter/</guid>
      <description>Curious coincidence (or maybe not), two days after realising &amp;ldquo;something&amp;rdquo; was missing in one of my frequent logic diagrams, I saw an episodeof The Big Bang Theory in which Wollowitz discovers a flaw in Sheldon`s friendship algorithm.
Dr. Sheldon Cooper`s lack of a cycle counter in his friendship algorithmis not a trivial issue. The cycle counter is the &amp;ldquo;real life&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;context&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;awareness&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;empathy&amp;rdquo;, aspect of a logic interpretation of a social engagement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>