<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Short prose on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/short-prose/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Short prose on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 10:25:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/short-prose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s pretend none of this ever happened</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 10:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</guid>
      <description>Walking towards my London Shoreditch office
to meet the Swiss investor and his impeccable suit,
leaving the City bankers’s coffee-holding fast pace behind,
I notice the absence nobody seems to
Where did he go?
His sleeping sack and pillow still on the sidewalk
as annoyingly positioned in the corner as always
But he’s gone
.
I wonder and I worry
his failing body, almost as absent as his lost gaze</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold men destroy women</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/cold-men-destroy-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 16:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/cold-men-destroy-women/</guid>
      <description>Cold men destroy women,” my mother wrote me years later. “They woo them with something personable that they bring out for show, something annexed to their souls like a fake greenhouse, lead you in, and you think you see life and vitality and sun and greenness, and then when you love them, they lead you out into their real soul, a drafty, cavernous, empty ballroom, inexorably arched and vaulted and mocking you with its echoes— you hear all you have sacrificed, all you have given, landing with a loud clunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My gift, goodbye or new beginning</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/my-gift-goodbye-or-new-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 19:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/my-gift-goodbye-or-new-beginning/</guid>
      <description>If the world ends today, this is my goodbye soundtrack gift to you.
If it doesn`t, tomorrow it will be the soundtrack of a waterfall, my new beginning gift to you.
In any case, the first composition that I ever share with the world (&amp;ldquo;Waterfall in the winter&amp;rdquo;). Straight from my open heart. Enjoy. Peace. Love. Happiness.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red curtain</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/red-curtain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 20:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/red-curtain/</guid>
      <description>Red dyes sky and &amp;ldquo;sea&amp;rdquo;, as they call it, as the sun sets over the Rio de la Plata.
The promenade fills up with Montevideans with their mates. They smile, oblivious to, or despite of, life`s drama.
This intense red bursts, invades, dyes and covers like a curtain. I must share it with you.
It`s ephemeral, I know it will pass, but now it feels as if nothing can escape its spillover, which drags along my attention, my sensibility, my pain, my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trees rise, leafs leave</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/trees-rise-leafs-leave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 16:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/trees-rise-leafs-leave/</guid>
      <description>Astonished I witness the trees rise
tall from their base,
not even rooted.
Leafs leave,
group,
organize,
and shifting shapes,
take to the sky
only to dive down.
A red dragon,
a viking vessel,
coming straight at me.
The memory of holding your hand,
and blinking,
gets me through.
But how far could even a never fading memory take me?
I shall hold your hand again, or be taken by the leafs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>319 Scholes art opening of &amp;quot;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 12:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I went to 319 Scholes to attend the art opening of &amp;ldquo;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;rdquo;.
Beyond the anecdotal post/pre hispter crowd, the exhibition itself is a sad celebration of noise. Which, in itself is as valid, or invalid, as any other starting point in the endless debate about art (more so in regards with contemporary, electronic, net, etc).
But it is its legitimization attempt, with research project, curator, catalogue, and international tour, which brings the debate to a whole different level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>white skin</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/white-skin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/white-skin/</guid>
      <description>Autumn.
My skin falls and yours is not there.
I turn to the canvas, but its not color I want to smear your whiteness with. I face the white screen, but its not light that I seek.
I confront the blank page, but words will not bring solace.
Then my skin falls on the piano ivory.
Fingers sliding down each key.
Caresses that the air won`t keep.
The music was already playing in my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High culture might will numb you, how stay true? On &amp;quot;Graffiti&amp;quot; screening and panel at New Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 15:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I was invited to the New Musuem for the screening of &amp;ldquo;Graffiti – PostGraffiti&amp;rdquo; documentary and panel discussion.Your usual suspects were there. Besides the panelist (Pattie Astor, Fab Five Freddy, Lady Pink, and Lee Quinones), there were many old glories and a couple of aspiring bomber kids in the audience that I am sure were tagging walls late that night.
What started as a celebration, a remembrance, and a comunion, as the liturgy advanced ended up becoming a hurtful vindication and even a flat out purist attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I`m the man and the boy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/im-the-man-and-the-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 22:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/im-the-man-and-the-boy/</guid>
      <description>I`m the man that fears rejection
Im the man that cant sleep because of problems
I`m the man that will fight and defend the castle</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It`s October and all I want is you</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 22:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</guid>
      <description>Lying on the carpet, poetry book and pencil in hand, U2 in the background.
October
 October
And the trees are stripped bare
Of all they wear
What do I care
October
And kingdoms rise
And kingdoms fall
But you go on&amp;hellip;and on&amp;hellip;
 So many literal meanings: the fear of wearing-out (The Edge was considering leaving the band like his brother did before they were even called U2), the false sense of security arising from self-defeat (&amp;ldquo;What do I care&amp;rdquo;), moving on after a loss (both Bono and Larry had just lost their mothers), the high hopes and expectations arising from new democracies in Eastern Europe only to become despair and dissapointment, and eventually resilience, surviving, going on&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the messages kept coming in</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/and-the-messages-kept-coming-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 09:25:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/and-the-messages-kept-coming-in/</guid>
      <description>One after another. Light, quick, nonchalant.
Poured, as a quick one-sided conversation, the messages kept coming in.
On the background, music by an unknown artist. Unknown even to himself. Adding a reggae-folk soundtrack that sounded unintendedly tragic. The guitar riffs camouflaging the &amp;ldquo;new-message&amp;rdquo; tones. But the desperation kept building up. With every superficial message, a poignant indication that the truth was, still, being concealed. Or worse: never revealed. Each new line, a ticker tape reminder of how little he matter, how opaque and transparent he had become at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comment on &amp;quot;Debunking Putin`s Newest Myth&amp;quot; by Alexander Yanov</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/comment-on-quotdebunking-putins-newest-mythquot-by-alexander-yanov/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 22:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/comment-on-quotdebunking-putins-newest-mythquot-by-alexander-yanov/</guid>
      <description>After reading &amp;ldquo;Debunking Putin`s Newest Myth&amp;rdquo; by Alexander Yanov, PhD, and with all my respect and admiration for this very well known historian of Russian nationalisms:
Although quite brilliant and eloquent, I believe it is not incisive and daring enough in debunking Putin`s newest myth. It takes a very conservative approach, perhaps letting a Western traditional philosophy baggage and inclination take the part of pure reason and belief, which is usually needed, in equal parts, to fight a political/philosophical quarrel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poem: &amp;quot;Accompanied by your absence&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/poem-quotaccompanied-by-your-absencequot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 16:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/poem-quotaccompanied-by-your-absencequot/</guid>
      <description> Accompanied by your absence
I hear your skin calling.
Silently, still, I answer.
In the solitude of your presence
I remember sliding down your gaze
fearlessly falling into your void,
your being`s foyer.
Next to you, finally, I rest
dreaming and longing,
with the peace and tranquility that comes from
knowing me you.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay for Nebula`s new photobook</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/essay-for-nebulas-new-photobook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 13:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/essay-for-nebulas-new-photobook/</guid>
      <description>I have contributed an essay to the book (PDF soon available for free online, and for purchase in book format -a few sample images shown here-) of an exhibition I am curating. 3 years in the making, &amp;ldquo;Gaze, Reflexion, Fusion&amp;rdquo; is the highly poetical but politically charged work of one of the most interesting new photographers in the New York art scene: NEBULA.
From Tokyo to San Francisco, Madrid to Seoul, the Spanish photographer Nebula has traveled to 10 cities in 4 countries in order to find inspiration and the right images (somethimes a fleeting reflexion of it) to bring to life what she feels about art, identity, apropriationism, feminism, and psychoanalysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A definition of art</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/a-definition-of-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 10:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/a-definition-of-art/</guid>
      <description>Seeking the definition of Art for a while, I can not find one that satisfies me, nor I seem to be able to reach one by myself. Here is as far as I have been able to get so far:
 Art is giving the opportunity of being to something that would never be
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You may pretend, but remember...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/you-may-pretend-but-remember.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 04:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/you-may-pretend-but-remember.../</guid>
      <description> When you go around jumping like you are on the moon, and then you trip and fall, you are going to smash your face against the floor with full Earth gravity.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligence and heart quote</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/intelligence-and-heart-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 05:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/intelligence-and-heart-quote/</guid>
      <description>Intelligence could not represent for a long time the part of the heart.
 François de la Rochefoucauld</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ode to the pen</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/ode-to-the-pen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 18:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/ode-to-the-pen/</guid>
      <description>See in Scientific American:
 &amp;ldquo;I could not survive without a ballpoint pen in my back pocket. It`s invaluable for scribbling notes on the front of my hand (my version of the PalmPilot&amp;hellip;) to remind me to do things I used to be able to remember unaided before my age converged with my IQ while traveling in opposite directions.&amp;rdquo;
 _John P. MooreProfessor of Microbiology and Immunology
Weill Medical College of Cornell University, New York City_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finishing is not ending</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/finishing-is-not-ending/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 08:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/finishing-is-not-ending/</guid>
      <description>October knew, of course, that the action of turning a page, of ending a chapter or of shutting a book, did not end a tale.
 &amp;ldquo;The man who was October&amp;rdquo;, G. K. Chesterton</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>