<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Humor and curiosities on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/humor-and-curiosities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Humor and curiosities on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 14:17:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/humor-and-curiosities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Valencia (Spain) VC flows</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/valencia-spain-vc-flows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 14:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/valencia-spain-vc-flows/</guid>
      <description>Adam Gilfix, Brian de Luna, and Luke Heine, with the help of Dealroom.co, have created a very interesting data visualization tool for Venture Capital (VC) flows.
I know for a fact and from experience that VC activity in places like Silicon Valley, NY, Boston, or London is big. But even when I go back home (Valencia – Spain) for the holidays, there are all kinds of &amp;ldquo;VC&amp;rdquo; events, news, meetings, spaces&amp;hellip; which, given the conservative and provincial nature of the &amp;ldquo;Valencian Investors&amp;rdquo; I have met, surprises me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My artwork “God bless Amurika”, on display at the Ludwig Museum (Cologne), explained</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-artwork-god-bless-amurika-on-display-at-the-ludwig-museum-cologne-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 09:26:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-artwork-god-bless-amurika-on-display-at-the-ludwig-museum-cologne-explained/</guid>
      <description>I have often criticized artists who hide behind “my work speaks for itself” or “it’s up to the viewer to interpret my work”. Nice try, but that’s bullshit.
Of course, anyone can interpret anything when exposed to an artwork! But the artist should at least make an attempt to explain the meaning behind a piece. No matter how self-explanatory (or obscure) it might be. It’s not “restricting the viewer”, it’s guiding; suggesting is not imposing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited by the Duque of York to have dinner at Windsor Castle November 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/invited-by-the-duque-of-york-to-have-dinner-at-windsor-castle-november-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 20:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/invited-by-the-duque-of-york-to-have-dinner-at-windsor-castle-november-3/</guid>
      <description>The other day I received a letter from Buckingham Palace, inviting me to have dinner with the Duke of York (Prince Andrew) on Thursday at Windsor Castle.
I was curious to see the castle from the inside: it is a medieval style fortress, filled with military memorabilia (guns, swords, lances, armors…), banners and crests. It was more Game of Thrones than Harry Potter.
The reception was held at the Grand Reception Room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween in Wimbledon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/halloween-in-wimbledon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 07:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/halloween-in-wimbledon/</guid>
      <description>Halloween has arrived in Wimbledon. The multicolored leaves paint their annual natural mosaic, one of the many subjective manifestations where we can observe our mind at work, interpreting events. Do you get taken away by the beauty of the color range? Does it make you wonder why everybody finds beautiful a cyclical natural event that occurs because tree leaves die, fall and rot? Do you associate it with annoyingly unpredictable weather and uncomfortably falling temperatures?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyperJapan 2016 London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/hyperjapan-2016-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 15:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/hyperjapan-2016-london/</guid>
      <description>Today we went with my sister and brother-in-law, who are visiting for a few days, to HyperJapanin London Olympia.
Silly and fun, full of cosplay and otakus. Kawaii!
^.^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-designing a NASA interface</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/re-designing-a-nasa-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 14:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/re-designing-a-nasa-interface/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in many things. One of the main ones is technology. And within technology, software development to view telemetry data in different ways, within the same application.
Answering NASA’s call to help contribute to the exploration of the solar system, I got access to their next-generation mission control framework being developed at the NASA Ames Research Center in Silicon Valley being used for mission planning and operations in the lead up to the Resource Prospector mission, and at NASA`s Jet Propulsion Laboratory to view data from the Curiosity Rover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wimbledon tennis madness</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/wimbledon-tennis-madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 14:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/wimbledon-tennis-madness/</guid>
      <description>I live in Wimbledon. We moved here from London Bridge because this area is much more relaxed and has great parks within walking distance. But for two weeks a year, this town becomes the tennis capital of the world.
I can post this collection of photos showing how crazy the town gets for two weeks now that the Wimbledon Tennis Championships 2016 are over, and I can tell because I could hear the players moan, the umpire call the score… let alone the crowd roaring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating the non-comissioned art piece “Diangle” for the Tate Modern Gallery</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/creating-the-non-comissioned-art-piece-diangle-for-the-tate-modern-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 11:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/creating-the-non-comissioned-art-piece-diangle-for-the-tate-modern-gallery/</guid>
      <description>Thursday June 23 I was given the opportunity to create a non-comissioned art piece at the Tate Gallery new extension Switch House.
Within Meschac Gaba (1961, Benin) “Architecture Room” installation part of the “Museum of Contemporary African Art” exhibit, the artist invitation was to build my own imaginary museum… and what better place to do that than in the recently inaugurated Switch House extension of the Tate Gallery by Herzog &amp;amp; de Meuron?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to InfoSecurity Europe</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-infosecurity-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 15:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-infosecurity-europe/</guid>
      <description>Today I was invited to attend InfoSecurity Europe, Europe`s largest Information Security industry event.
As always, it was interesting to have a chance to catch up with this rapidly moving field, and a great opportunity to chat with old friends.
Apart from gimmicks (VR everywhere, car racing and helicopter simulators, giant robots, etc), swag (all kinds of Star Wars and other Sci-Fi related giveaways, from toys to t-shirts) and junk food (from candy to icecream to chips, the booths did not have healthy alternatives, although the food vendors did), the most interesting part of these events is always the talks, specifically the hands-on demos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flight data as business intelligence</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/01/flight-data-as-business-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 08:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/01/flight-data-as-business-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>As an international &amp;ldquo;solo-preneur&amp;rdquo; you have to be careful about how to invest your time and resources, and what metrics are really key.
My main company (Kanteron Systems) is in the Enterprise Healthcare Software world. Blog posts and books talking about apps, user adoption, and monetization mean nothing to me. Yet most companies in the Enterprise B2B space are big listed multinationals, so their metrics do not exactly apply to me either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cup Noodles Museum Yokohama</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/cup-noodles-museum-yokohama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 11:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/cup-noodles-museum-yokohama/</guid>
      <description>On my way back from the amazing Sankeien Garden, after attending (but honestly not paying much attention to) a Japanese-only BioInformatics lecture (seriously, I enjoy those things), I went for something fun and quirky: the Cup Noodles Museum.
Founded by revered Momofuku Sando-san, Instant Noodles (Cup Noodles) has a very interesting story behind its world wide wild success. I learned that Sando-san spent two years in jail for tax evasion. That he invented the instant noodles in his 60’s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast in London, lunch in Reykjavík and dinner in Boston</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/breakfast-in-london-lunch-in-reykjav%C3%ADk-and-dinner-in-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 10:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/breakfast-in-london-lunch-in-reykjav%C3%ADk-and-dinner-in-boston/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing in London… even with Microsoft!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/playing-in-london-even-with-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 09:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/playing-in-london-even-with-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>These past few days have been quite “playful”.
On the one hand, I have just discovered, right around the corner from our apartment by London Bridge, a free and public playground that has an artificial grass hockey field, half a basketball court, 3 pingpong tables and even a beach volleyball court with sand and all! So obviously, the next day I went with my son to a sports equipment store and bought a soccer ball, a pingpong set, a basketball, a volleyball and a badminton set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the MoMA member reception “The Tomorrow Now…”</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/invited-to-the-moma-member-reception-the-tomorrow-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 16:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/invited-to-the-moma-member-reception-the-tomorrow-now/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday my wife and I were invited to the MoMA member reception “The Forever Now: Contemporary Painting in an Atemporal World”, which opens officially tomorrow for the general public.
Obviously the rain did not prevent hordes of socialites to flock to MoMA and gather around one of the three open bars. But that was great because it gave us, and quite a few other &amp;ldquo;they must be on a How About We date&amp;rdquo; couples to visit some of the galleries without having to use our elbows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick family visit in Valencia</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/quick-family-visit-in-valencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 09:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/quick-family-visit-in-valencia/</guid>
      <description>Of course, everytime I go to Europe I make sure I stop in Valencia and see my kids. It makes me SO tremendously happy to see them! I can’t wait until we can all live in the same city again. Some day, soon.
We had fun meeting the family (although my parents were on a cruise), projecting movies at night on the “large screen” over the living room windows, and playing all kinds of games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I was forced to hack into Schiphol Airport wifi</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/i-was-forced-to-hack-into-schiphol-airport-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 12:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/i-was-forced-to-hack-into-schiphol-airport-wifi/</guid>
      <description>A couple weeks ago I was at Schiphol Airport in Amsterdam. Of course, when I arrive in an airport with enough time ahead of my boarding, I look for a plug and wifi. Luckily Schiphol is an excellent airport, offering both. The only problem is that every time I clicked on the &amp;ldquo;Enjoy unlimited free wifi – Connect&amp;rdquo; button, I got an &amp;ldquo;Unknown error 0&amp;rdquo; message back.
 Don`t tell me &amp;ldquo;Enjoy unlimited free wifi&amp;rdquo; and then try to prevent me from accessing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singapore wacky laws</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/singapore-wacky-laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 05:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/singapore-wacky-laws/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Lego cable management solution</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/08/my-lego-cable-management-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 21:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/08/my-lego-cable-management-solution/</guid>
      <description>After a month traveling throughout Europe (posts and pictures soon), I returned to New York and I needed to catch up with work. In order to be more productive I had to tackle the &amp;ldquo;cable jungle&amp;rdquo; challenge. Quick and easy (and cool) solution? LEGO!
Just attach some velcro to the back of a Lego, attach it to the edge of your desk, get some of your favorite figures, have them &amp;ldquo;hold their arms up&amp;rdquo;, and let them hold the USB and charger cables for you 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to the beach... Canadian style</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/02/going-to-the-beach...-canadian-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 17:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/02/going-to-the-beach...-canadian-style/</guid>
      <description>This has been a hard winter in North America. Snow, ice, flurries, sleet&amp;hellip; But today I got to enjoy the beach (Waverly beach – Lake Erie, Canada) in a way I had never experienced before: walking over water&amp;hellip;. frozen water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It was so cold, it was funny</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/it-was-so-cold-it-was-funny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 19:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/it-was-so-cold-it-was-funny/</guid>
      <description>The other day my wife and I had to put on several layers of warm clothes to leave our apartment.
Then, when we got back home, we saw this online and we could not stop laughing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This IS cold -23ºF in New York right now with ice inside the window</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/this-is-cold-23%C2%BAf-in-new-york-right-now-with-ice-inside-the-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 16:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/01/this-is-cold-23%C2%BAf-in-new-york-right-now-with-ice-inside-the-window/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A most pleasant celebration of your planet’s Winter Solstice</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/12/a-most-pleasant-celebration-of-your-planets-winter-solstice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 11:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/12/a-most-pleasant-celebration-of-your-planets-winter-solstice/</guid>
      <description>“Hope you experience a most pleasant celebration of your planet’s Winter Solstice and a most logical New Year.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barack and Michelle Obama congratulate us on our wedding</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/11/barack-and-michelle-obama-congratulate-us-on-our-wedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 10:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/11/barack-and-michelle-obama-congratulate-us-on-our-wedding/</guid>
      <description>A couple days ago, when we returned home from the SVA Theatre at the School of Visual Arts, where we were invited to attend the screeningof selected videosby winners and finalists from the 2013 Los Angeles Music Video Festival(and an interesting panel discussion with Bob Giraldi, Christopher Walters, Steven Gottlieb, Scott Reich, August Schram, and others), we found this in our mailbox:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precolumbian Einstein</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/precolumbian-einstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 00:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/precolumbian-einstein/</guid>
      <description>Seen at the MET Museum in NY.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NY ComicCon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/ny-comiccon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 23:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/ny-comiccon/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5934418147899482241]
After going the other day with Maker Fairewith my parents, yesterday we went backto ComicCon. The usual: cosplay, crowds, swag&amp;hellip; FUN!!
UPDATE: here is a list of interesting links (artists, publishing houses, software, etc) we collected there.
Artists/Comics:
 Bill Plympton (studio, blog, store, tumblr), whom I have admired for many years, was there in person. Cool! Dylan (UpsideDownGrin) Rich Miller (FilthWorks) Selina Briggs (The Jelly Empire) The Gate Crashers  Studios/Stores:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with the robot (Roomba)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/08/playing-with-the-robot-roomba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 15:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/08/playing-with-the-robot-roomba/</guid>
      <description>We got great gifts for our wedding, but hands down, the best (ever!) is A ROBOT.
My mother-in-law got us a robot. Got that? How cool is that!?
And it is not to make her daughter’s life easier, because I am the one who vacuums at home. She did it because it is cool. Heck yeah it is!
So the Roombais nothing new. It has been around for a decade already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am requested to take a link down and... Streisand effect!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 01:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</guid>
      <description>Today I received this email (it was in Spanish, I have translated it into English because that is the main language of this blog, and in order to give this issue the international coverage that it deserves – sorry for any translation mistake since I am not a lawyer and he writes like an old-fashioned one trying to sound intimidating; here is the original):
 Mr. Cortell:
Currently I am suing Greg Prévôt in the Courts of Barcelona, author of a defamatory site which infringes upon my honor, whose link appears in which you administer, at the following address:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VII Japan Society CUTS Contemporary Japanese Film Festival</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/vii-japan-society-cuts-contemporary-japanese-film-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 15:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/vii-japan-society-cuts-contemporary-japanese-film-festival/</guid>
      <description>The Japan Society CUTS Contemporary Japanese Film Festivalis one of my favorites.
This year we saw four very different but delightful (in their own way) fims, all of them USA premieres and Co-presented with the New York Asian Film Festival:
The Festival Opening Film, with Introduction and Q&amp;amp;A with Director Toshiaki Toyoda, and after film party. Interesting story about death, life, cults&amp;hellip;
Of course, while we were in the area, with so many Japanese restaurants in 47th, we tried:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese fun</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/japanese-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 15:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/japanese-fun/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, on my way to a financial presentation, I stopped at Kinokuniya Bookstoreto browse books and to enjoy the origami they had on display as part of the OrigamiAsArtexhibition.
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5896481691678261089]
To round the Japanese-themed day up, I went in the New York Public Libraryand got two films:
 Densha Otoko (Train_Man) Fish Story  ^_^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoHo surprises</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/soho-surprises/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 15:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/soho-surprises/</guid>
      <description>Lately I have been going to the office more than usual. The FDA inspection, then the PILOT health tech NY day (which was held in the coworking space where my office is), and a few other things have made me walk around SoHo quite a lot these days. Here are a few of the surprises I have encountered in the always colorful neighborhood:  The Pearl River Market store, right next door to my offices entrance, is &amp;quot;SoHos best kept secret&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy of an FDA inspection</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/anatomy-of-an-fda-inspection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 15:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/anatomy-of-an-fda-inspection/</guid>
      <description>On April 25th I attended my first FDA (U.S. Food and Drug Administration) Medical Device Establishment Inspection. Agent (Investigator) Kimberley A. Ricketts called me a couple days before to let me know that as a registered medical device manufacturing company, Kanteron Systems (the company I founded in 2005) had been selected for an Establishment Inspection. It was the &amp;ldquo;Notice of Inspection pursuant to Section 704(a)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetics Act [21 U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am featured in an IBM ad</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/i-am-featured-in-an-ibm-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 15:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/i-am-featured-in-an-ibm-ad/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norwegian Breakaway inaugural cruise day 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/norwegian-breakaway-inaugural-cruise-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 19:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/norwegian-breakaway-inaugural-cruise-day-2/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5877235646228621073]
Day 2 of our cruise started waking up to the sound of the waves and with a buffet breakfast at Garden Café, which we took in an outside table.
The day was fully packed of activities, and given my terrible memory, I`m sure I would have forgotten some of them by now. But thanks to the fact that the cruise line gave us access to the net (although only for Twitter, Facebook and Instagram), I was able to tweet my activities, and then use the TL to remember them easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video interview (IBM Beacon Award)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/video-interview-ibm-beacon-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 17:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/video-interview-ibm-beacon-award/</guid>
      <description>Right after I accepted the IBM Beacon Award for Healthcare and Life Sciences given to my company (Kanteron Systems), I was video interviewed in the corridor. Here is the result:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working distractions</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/working-distractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 13:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/working-distractions/</guid>
      <description>If I go to the office, I complain that there are too many distractions: whether it is the boom-boom music form the downstairs SoHo store, my coworkers playing ping-pong, street art that requires my attention, or the temptation of a Japanese bento box or mochi with tea&amp;hellip;
But if I stay at home, Calvin makes sure I am not as productive as I could be.
OK, I admit it, this was a very silly excuse to try a new slider plugin with Pinterest non-official API&amp;hellip; and trying those things is not a diversion or distraction, is part of my job, I swear!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seen in the streets of NY until april 2013</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/seen-in-the-streets-of-ny-until-april-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 19:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/seen-in-the-streets-of-ny-until-april-2013/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5867858717493854113]
Now that the good weather seems to have arrived to NY, I will be walking more (more than my two hours daily that I already walk), and will be more willing to stop and take photographs of the crazy stuff one sees on the streets every day. Here are some images before April 2013.
(Note: the fun Einstein and Freud images were taken at Chelsea Market, from an exhibition by FunnyFoodArt).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sculpture drafts</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/sculpture-drafts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 19:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/sculpture-drafts/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5873034546116971265]
Here are some of my sculpture drafts that I hope some day will become real sculptures: &amp;ldquo;homeless snail: you and me&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;the lovers&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool corp.?</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/cool-corp./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 11:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/cool-corp./</guid>
      <description>Read Quote of Balaji Viswanathans answer to Microsoft: Why isnt Microsoft ‘cool`?on Quora</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Montevideo in December</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/montevideo-in-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 20:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/montevideo-in-december/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5821499441712215169]
December 2nd I flew to Montevideo. I stayed at the Radisson Hotel, Plaza de la Independencia. Very conveniently located with some impressive views from the top floor. Good thing it had a pool, because it is not easy to keep my exercise regime when traveling so much.
Besides very productive meetings with IBM (very nice, professional, and friendly executives, by the way) and presentation to several hospital groups (one of the meetings at the Presidential Building, another one at the country`s largest hospital, and a presentation at the Solis Theater), I enjoyed the promenade by the river which seems like a sea, the old town, and a weird Ice Bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instead of Halloween party</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/instead-of-halloween-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 15:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/instead-of-halloween-party/</guid>
      <description>I`m still stuck in Baltimore, but it seems I will be able to return to NY late tonight, arrivingtomorrow morningafternoon, the day after Halloween (which reaches amazing levels, like Barbie special edition dolls).
So, instead of going to the Village Halloween parade(which has been cancelled for the first time in 39 years), or anyof the Halloween parties I was invited to (the New Museum and Cara`s parties have also been cancelled), and wear the cool and simple MineCraft Creeper costume Cory Doctorow twitted(from Comic Con NY):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seen in NY: skaters, cheese and a record selling truck</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/seen-in-ny-skaters-cheese-and-a-record-selling-truck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 12:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/seen-in-ny-skaters-cheese-and-a-record-selling-truck/</guid>
      <description>A big band of skaters (I only captured a few in my photograph becuase they were left behind in a stoplight, but there were many many more) rolling down south on Broadway. As they passed, people on the side walk greeted and cheered them. More play and less politics, or the return of the playful society, please. [Update.- there is a big story behind it: the Broadway Bomb] Beecher`s Handmade Cheese, where you can sample and purchase artisanal cheese, have some wine and small apetizers in the cellar downstairs, but even more fun to just sit and watch them make cheese live, through a big glass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections from NY Comic Con</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 09:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I went to NY Comic Con, like everyone else, I guess, with the idea of having fun, of experiencing first hand one of the &amp;ldquo;major events&amp;rdquo; that a true nerdy geek can attend. I also wanted to meet Cory Doctorow (although we actually ended up not meeting). It has been years since I last met him, and it was the perfect &amp;ldquo;excuse&amp;rdquo; to attend the conference.
When I arrived, I was really surprised to see the size of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick trip to Panama</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/quick-trip-to-panama/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 13:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/quick-trip-to-panama/</guid>
      <description>I have just returned from Panama. It has been a quick business trip in which I have tried to make the most of my time. Here are some notes from the trip:
– United Airlines choice of dinner was &amp;quot;beef or chicken&amp;quot;. Whatever happened to the broadly accepted vegetarian-friendly classic pasta choice? Besides, the chicken was breaded, in a white bun, and the &amp;quot;beef&amp;quot;, lets just say it did not look too good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft, derivative works, parodies...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 10:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</guid>
      <description>Hugo sends me thisamazing song/video made in Minecraft. Of course, that leads to 10more, 14more&amp;hellip; there are so many!
When you make the tools available to the people, and allow them to create (in this case under the safe harbor of &amp;ldquo;parody&amp;rdquo;) wonderful things happen. Its NOT all about the money, profit, control... Its about imagination, art, creativity, culture. Thats how it happens: copying, re-using, mixing, adjusting, modifying... thats what creativity is really about (or did you think it was about &amp;ldquo;inventing&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;making unheard of things out of thin air&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No unions admitted at the Intrepid Museum, NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/no-unions-admitted-at-the-intrepid-museum-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2012 13:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/no-unions-admitted-at-the-intrepid-museum-ny/</guid>
      <description>New York`s Intrepid Museum, new home of the Space Shuttle Enterprise, does not allow unions. You can see it (point number 13) in their &amp;ldquo;code of conduct&amp;rdquo;. WTF!!??
via Alvaro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&amp;quot;All White Party&amp;quot; at the New Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/quotall-white-partyquot-at-the-new-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 10:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/quotall-white-partyquot-at-the-new-museum/</guid>
      <description>Five days ago, the New Museum invited me to the &amp;ldquo;All White Party&amp;rdquo;. It`s one of those events I would not normally go by myself, but Jane told me about the rooftop bar that only opens on weekends and during parties, so I decided to go and check it out. Plus, I was told it was the only chance I would have to see new yorkers dressed in white.
As it was to be expected, lot of people, quite a few &amp;ldquo;celebrities&amp;rdquo;, and 95% wearing white (with your typical &amp;ldquo;I am wearing black, to signal I am bad, or odd, or fun, or whatever&amp;rdquo;, two or three &amp;ldquo;ooops, I thought they were joking about the white – or I don`t have white clothes – and I am wearing my grey/orange shirt&amp;rdquo; and a petite blonde wearing black skirt and white top).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun at Hackers On Planet Earth 9 – New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/fun-at-hackers-on-planet-earth-9-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 17:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/fun-at-hackers-on-planet-earth-9-new-york/</guid>
      <description>July 13th-15th Alvaro and I attended Hope9(Hackers On Planet Earth number 9) conference in New York`s Hotel Pennsylvania.
It was a lot of fun, as usual. Besides the many and informative talks(we gave one on &amp;ldquo;Digital Security in Health Care Institutions&amp;rdquo;, the first day), there was music, booths (FSF, EFFwith a girl that wanted to come to Spain to help the #indignados, Free Manning, No Starch PressBooks and more), arduino and lock-picking classes, a pro-ponies and against-zombies USA Presidential Candidate wearing a boot on his head, MakerBot3D printers, the IMMI, Hackers For Charity, AlphaOneHackerSpace (will be visiting it next Thursday with Audrey), StartUpHire, SparkleLabs(awesome presents for kids and n00bies!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting videos</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/interesting-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 22:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/interesting-videos/</guid>
      <description>Let me share some odd videos I have watched recently, thanks to Leaitrice and Patricia:
The famous &amp;quot;Sunscreen&amp;rdquo; music video(the text comes from an essaywritten in 1997 by Mary Schmich, a columnist at the Chicago Tribune, as a graduation speech for the class of `97) which gives some amazing advice for life. There is even a StarWars Version.
Drunk History: get some history students drunk, have them narrate historical events, while reenacting them&amp;hellip; more fun than it seems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I beat Watson at Jeopardy (more or less)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 18:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in my previous post, at IBM Innovation Center in Chicago they have a Watson(more info here) interactive kiosk with which to play an interactive game of Jeopardy. In case you have been living in a cave for the past few months, Watson beatJeopardy human champions on live TV, the significanceof which can not be overstated.
Now, remember: this is a &amp;ldquo;small version&amp;rdquo; of Watson, and a &amp;ldquo;self-contained&amp;rdquo; version of Jeopardy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critics and artists</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/critics-and-artists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 17:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/critics-and-artists/</guid>
      <description>When art critics get together they talk about Form and Structure and Meaning. When artists get together they talk about where you can buy cheap turpentine.
 Picasso</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun days, June 1st and 2nd</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/fun-days-june-1st-and-2nd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 12:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/fun-days-june-1st-and-2nd/</guid>
      <description>Trying to catch up with fun days, here is what June 1st looked like: first some crêpes for lunch at Vive La CrepeUnion Square (delicious crêpes and funny chair backs embedded in concrete).
Then, after browsing around at Beacons Closet&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, and going to &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.tibethouse.us/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.tibethouse.us/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Tibet House&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; to gather info (Tuesdays meditation classes, here I go), it was finally time to visit Rubin Museum of Art. While Modernist Art from India, Illuminated, and Casting the Divine were very interesting and delightful, I must admit the nerdy geek in me enjoyed Hero, Villain, Yeti like a real kid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering snow today at near 100ºF in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/remembering-snow-today-at-near-100%C2%BAf-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 12:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/remembering-snow-today-at-near-100%C2%BAf-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>Today, #HelloSummer, at almost 100ºF in NY, is a good day to remember the snow. I took this picture of a promo stunt May 31st at Times Square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry Elephants</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/angry-elephants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 21:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/angry-elephants/</guid>
      <description>via APM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Kagemu video</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/awesome-kagemu-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 21:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/awesome-kagemu-video/</guid>
      <description>Although I can not embed it (the author has disabled the option) this videoby Japanese performer and CGI artist Kagemu is really worth looking at. Enjoy. (Via Nebula).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with my new Lytro</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/playing-with-my-new-lytro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 18:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/playing-with-my-new-lytro/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I received my new Lytrocamera. Although it is an incredible technology, and allows things that were unthinkable until now, so far I am mixed.
Pros:
 Compact and discreet Extremely easy to use New ways of taking pictures Novelty Supercool &amp;ldquo;focus later&amp;rdquo;  Cons:
 You have to get used to a different way of thinking and framing a shot (square! and distance) Low performance under low light (although better than my crappy Samsung Galaxy IIS camera)  Check out this online gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom of religion, freedom of expression, and public spaces</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/freedom-of-religion-freedom-of-expression-and-public-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 17:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/freedom-of-religion-freedom-of-expression-and-public-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Picture.
Question: why do I have to cross the street on my way home?
Debate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journalists covering FB IPO</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/journalists-covering-fb-ipo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 13:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/journalists-covering-fb-ipo/</guid>
      <description>May 18th, on my way to the subway, outside my office.
Look at the pictures. The making of the circus. Draw your own conclusions (and yes, the third one is a journalist on top of a wooden box to make her look taller).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech is a tool, people are stupid</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/tech-is-a-tool-people-are-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 13:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/tech-is-a-tool-people-are-stupid/</guid>
      <description>Technology is getting easier to use everyday. Take GNU/Linux distributions as an example: anyone can make their own. Does that mean everyone should make their own? Why not? But then, again, we end up with things like Ubuntu Satanic(and their Ubuntu SE 666.10 “Necrophiliac Neuromancer”), Hannah Montana Linux(how far would you go to attract kids to free software?), or Red Star OS(free software for North Korea and non-free browsing? WTF?).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Queens Museum of Art</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/queens-museum-of-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 13:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/queens-museum-of-art/</guid>
      <description>Last Thursday I went to Queens Museum of Art for a talk about NYFA Immigrant Art Project.
Besides interesting art, and an interesting (although basic) talk, here are some things that caught my attention (and yes, that IS a model of the park inside the elevator!): </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business advice for startups: do not collect underpants</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/business-advice-for-startups-do-not-collect-underpants/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 11:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/business-advice-for-startups-do-not-collect-underpants/</guid>
      <description>First read this post.
Then watch this South Park episode.
Now, if you are not going to cook something, get out of the kitchen (and at least start selling 😉 )</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geekest prom date</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/geekest-prom-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 10:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/geekest-prom-date/</guid>
      <description>And you thought I was talking about Princess Leia?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I admire these criminals</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-admire-these-criminals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 15:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-admire-these-criminals/</guid>
      <description>In Spain, the conservative PP government is planning to make &amp;ldquo;passive resistance&amp;rdquo; a crime(as well as organizing demonstrations using internet technologies).
I have these 4 criminals` magnetic puppets on my fridge. 2 were outlawed (and had to flee) by German Nazis. 1 had to flee Spanish dictatorship because he was a Communist. And the other one was thrown in jail by British occupation forces for &amp;ldquo;passive resistance&amp;rdquo;.
 I will not let anyone walk through my mind with their dirty feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Person of Interest filming around the corner</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/person-of-interest-filming-around-the-corner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 13:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/person-of-interest-filming-around-the-corner/</guid>
      <description>Today, as I headed to work, I exit my apartment, turn the corner onto 5th Ave. and see the film crew of Person of Interest. It doesn`t surprise me any more. Am I getting used to living in Manhattan?
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5730569373684857169]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In 3D with Firefox`s new TILT inspector</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/in-3d-with-firefoxs-new-tilt-inspector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 12:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/in-3d-with-firefoxs-new-tilt-inspector/</guid>
      <description>Lego web design, anyone? 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social-media inspired cocktails at Mandarin Oriental NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/social-media-inspired-cocktails-at-mandarin-oriental-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 11:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/social-media-inspired-cocktails-at-mandarin-oriental-ny/</guid>
      <description>seen in Tumblr (user: hragv)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marvel Marathon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/marvel-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 23:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/marvel-marathon/</guid>
      <description>From the #thisIsHowItsDone (not the movie adaptations, but special events to make people go more to the movie theaters) department, here is an awesome initiative from AMC movie theaters:
Get ready to watch the greatest Marvel movie event ever held at your local AMC Theatre on May 3rd! Experience THE ULTIMATE MARVEL MARATHON with six movies on one epic day. Watch the heroes’ stories unfold as they assemble for the midnight premiere of The Avengers 3D!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am such an ignorant</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-am-such-an-ignorant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 21:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-am-such-an-ignorant/</guid>
      <description>No wise man ever wished to be younger
Live everyday of your life
 Jonathan Swift</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At a WhiteBox NY exhibition closing party</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/at-a-whitebox-ny-exhibition-closing-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 15:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/at-a-whitebox-ny-exhibition-closing-party/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I attended WhiteBox`s exhibition closing party. The invitation said:
 Author and curator Raul Zamudioin conversation with Mookie Tenembaum.
Please join us at White Boxfor the closing reception of DISILLUSIONISM, and to engage in a stimulating conversation between Raul Zamudio and Mookie Tenembaum at 8pm sharp. Mookie will be presenting his new artist book, Paranoia. Malbec wines and truffles will be served.
 Although I am grateful for the invitation, and it sure was an interesting event, some things just beg to be commented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards an oversimplification cliff: when green=drunks</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/towards-an-oversimplification-cliff-when-greendrunks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 18:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/towards-an-oversimplification-cliff-when-greendrunks/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday morning, as I was walking towards the gym on Park Avenue, I saw waves of young adults (although acting like teenagers or frat boys) wearing green (some just a t-shirt or sweater, some a full leprechaun costume) on a procession towards their favorite Irish watering hole to &amp;ldquo;celebrate&amp;rdquo; St. Patricks Day in the only way that they seem to believe to be appropriate, besides a 5th Ave. official parade: drink until you pass out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At MoMA PS1 for K-HOLE2 Release</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/at-moma-ps1-for-k-hole2-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 01:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/at-moma-ps1-for-k-hole2-release/</guid>
      <description>Today I was invited tothe MoMA PS1 for K-HOLE#2 Release. Young people, &amp;ldquo;Brooklyn artsy&amp;rdquo;, holding beers and beards, with the careless attitude that the PS1 requires: either I dont get it or I do, but in any case, it wont show.
There were many works on display, too many (and too complex or infuriatingly simple) to comment here. What was definitely not worth mentioning, from my ignorant point of view, was the Alterazioni Video &amp;ldquo;The New Cinema Event&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypocritical and absurd visa questions</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/hypocritical-and-absurd-visa-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 07:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/hypocritical-and-absurd-visa-questions/</guid>
      <description>Some hypocritical and absurd questions found in the DS-160 form, needed to get a US Visa:
 Do you have a mental or physical disorder that poses or is likely to pose a threat to the safety or welfare of yourself or others? Are you or have you ever been a drug abuser or addict? Have you ever violated, or engaged in a conspiracy to violate, any law relating to controlled substances?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spain – US business = Pride Vs Arrogance</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/spain-us-business-pride-vs-arrogance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 20:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/spain-us-business-pride-vs-arrogance/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, in a meeting at the Setai Hotel in NY, Michael (with over 3 decades of experience working with US and Spanish corporations) perfectly described what is like to do business between the USA and Spain:
 A struggle between American arrogance and Spanish pride
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The smallest art gallery in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/the-smallest-art-gallery-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 05:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/the-smallest-art-gallery-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>This morning I walked by the smallest art gallery in NY, 125windowgallery, on 47th between 3rd and Lexington Avenue:
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,111219615350942087056,1,64c,center]
The best thing about that gallery is that you do not need to &amp;ldquo;go in&amp;rdquo; 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disappearing Chrysler and &amp;quot;Spanish&amp;quot; Empire State</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/disappearing-chrysler-and-quotspanishquot-empire-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/disappearing-chrysler-and-quotspanishquot-empire-state/</guid>
      <description>Excuse to try a new photo plug-in for WP:
First photo: the Chrysler building as seen from my living room window.
Second photo: same thing on a foggy day&amp;hellip; Building gone! (no Image Editing here).
Third photo: the Empire State Building, from the living room, decorated with &amp;ldquo;Spanish flags colors&amp;rdquo;
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5703177154854937889]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The parks of the future</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-parks-of-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 22:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-parks-of-the-future/</guid>
      <description>Is this what the parks of the future will look like?“Bird,” by Jacco Olivier, one of six animation installations on display in Madison Square Park, New YorkIt will be, if we do not do something about it now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArtHack Exhibit closing party in Brooklyn</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 22:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday I went to the ArtHack Exhibitclosing party at 319 ScholesSt, Brooklyn (New York).
Located in an industrial complex in Brooklyn, at night, loooong two blocks from the subway, graffiti all over, small door&amp;hellip; that gave way to heaven: young (I was the oldest hacker in that space, but I did not feel that way) energetic happy people tinkering with technology and proudly showing their &amp;ldquo;toys&amp;rdquo; (hacks, mashups, creations, or whatever).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It`s finally snowing... upwards!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/its-finally-snowing...-upwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 19:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/its-finally-snowing...-upwards/</guid>
      <description>When the wind and cold/warm air currents collide while snowing, you get the funny &amp;ldquo;snowing upwards&amp;rdquo; effect (and sideways also, of course). The 5ºF &amp;ldquo;real feel&amp;rdquo; is not so funny though 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When what the artist intended is distorted by the gallery`s limitations</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/when-what-the-artist-intended-is-distorted-by-the-gallerys-limitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 19:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/when-what-the-artist-intended-is-distorted-by-the-gallerys-limitations/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, along a MeetUp group, we visited several art galleries in Chelsea (NY): Mike Weiss Gallery, Gladstone Gallery, Luhring Augustine Gallery, Metro Pictures Gallery, The Pace Gallery, and Mary Boone Gallery.
Leaving my personal comments on the displayed works aside (as usual, the pleasure of this kind of pilgrimage is to leave your mind and senses open, and let the works and stimuli slowly sink in), one thing surprised me quite a lot: Ai Wei Wei‘s work Sunflower Seeds was supposed to be walked on (at least it did at the Tate Modern in London, for the first 10 days of the exhibit), but at Mary Boone Gallerythere is a security guard that prevents visitors from doing exactly what the artist intended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How &amp;quot;RealFeel&amp;quot; works</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/how-quotrealfeelquot-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 19:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/how-quotrealfeelquot-works/</guid>
      <description>AccuWeatherhas an interesting system called RealFeel. For example, today is 22ºF, but when you step outside, you cant help scream &amp;quot;Shit, its cold!&amp;rdquo;. Accourding to the AccuWeathers RealFeel system (which I assume &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.experts123.com/q/how-does-the-patented-accuweather-realfeel-temperature-work.html&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.experts123.com/q/how-does-the-patented-accuweather-realfeel-temperature-work.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;takes into account more than just humidity&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, like wind), it feels like 10ºF. What it does not take into account is if you forgot your hat, scarf, or gloves (then you are lost, even if you wear UniQlos HeatTech undies) 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data visualization of twitter activity with embedded game</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/data-visualization-of-twitter-activity-with-embedded-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2012 15:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/data-visualization-of-twitter-activity-with-embedded-game/</guid>
      <description>That`s what I call a fun mix (hint: throw the bird against the columns): https://vizify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seen in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/seen-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 19:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/seen-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>Random things seen in NY this past week:
A &amp;ldquo;horsehead&amp;rdquo; in the NY subway. What I love (and sometimes hate) about NY: nobody turned, laughed, commented, got scared, pointed a finger&amp;hellip; this is life as usual here.
&amp;ldquo;The Crazy Piano Guy&amp;rdquo; is Colin Huggins, a piano player that takes his piano to Madison Square Park and performs in public for free. Awesome.
Not only the latest Ferrari, Maserati&amp;hellip; once in a while you get to see cool vehicles as well 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color associations: red and yellow</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/color-associations-red-and-yellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 05:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/color-associations-red-and-yellow/</guid>
      <description>Seeing certain color combinations, associations are sure to fly into anybody`s minds.
Usually, red and yellow will bring to mind things like flags (of Spain, Catalonia-Valencia, R, Security, and adding some shapes you could even think of Macedonia or China).
Beyond flags, Axomil, sunset, fire, peppers,tullips, ballons, ketchup and mustard, Flash, soccer referee cards, Superman&amp;hellip; there are SO many options.
But when you consider the hue, tone, context, memory, and further additional information, then those options start to get reduced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ode to the pen</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/ode-to-the-pen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 18:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/ode-to-the-pen/</guid>
      <description>See in Scientific American:
 &amp;ldquo;I could not survive without a ballpoint pen in my back pocket. It`s invaluable for scribbling notes on the front of my hand (my version of the PalmPilot&amp;hellip;) to remind me to do things I used to be able to remember unaided before my age converged with my IQ while traveling in opposite directions.&amp;rdquo;
 _John P. MooreProfessor of Microbiology and Immunology
Weill Medical College of Cornell University, New York City_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook: couple breaker for drunks</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/facebook-couple-breaker-for-drunks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 05:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/facebook-couple-breaker-for-drunks/</guid>
      <description>Interesting couple of trivia about Facebook in UK:
 Facebook blamed for one-third marriage breakdowns British Facebook users intoxicated in 76% of their photos  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun interpreting signs</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/fun-interpreting-signs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 17:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/fun-interpreting-signs/</guid>
      <description>The world around us is full of signs. I wont go on dabble about _signifiers_, _meanings_, and the psychoanalitycal importance of the _word_. But sometimes I just cant help myself, when I see a sign begging for a creative interpretation:
Cmon, dont tell me you don`t see something like:
 If you press this button, your mouth will become a hotspot
 or
 A giant asteroid is heading towards your SpaceInvaders spacecraft, push the button to destroy the asteroid with a Dune-sque voice-blast</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geeky XMas</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/geeky-xmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 16:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/geeky-xmas/</guid>
      <description>My friend Juangui sends me a great collection of geeky xmas cards. I would definitely choose this one:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geek gifts</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/geek-gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 19:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/geek-gifts/</guid>
      <description>I hate to give in on the Xmas-Santa-Market craze. That`s why I have waited until after the 25th to offer you these hints:
 Giftmeister(interactive suggestions) Uncrate(random ideas) Mugs(it does not take so much to make a geek happy, does it?) Online stores (ThinkGeek, XtremeGeek, IWantOneOfThose, MakerSHED&amp;hellip;) BrickAndMortar stores (Robot Village, the Wired Store&amp;hellip; right across the street from the office!)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anxiety quantifiers</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/anxiety-quantifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2011 02:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/anxiety-quantifiers/</guid>
      <description>We all know them, c`mon, add to the list. Here are some examples to get you going:
 Number of tabs opened in browser Number of virtualized OSs in a single box Number of unread emails per hour Number of unread RSSs (or number of feeds) Number of saved sites on Delicious, Pulse, whatever Number of post drafts Number of beta-invites to be accepted  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga Guru uses copyright to sue competitor</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 19:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</guid>
      <description>Ego, money, power, abuse, restriction&amp;hellip; shame on those who stain the &amp;ldquo;holy&amp;rdquo; teachings.
Source: NYT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Below zero... even on Google</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/below-zero...-even-on-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 19:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/below-zero...-even-on-google/</guid>
      <description>To celebrate the falling temperatures in NY, try typing &amp;ldquo;let it snow&amp;rdquo; on Google`s search box (you can even wipe the screen with your mouse) 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complex</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/complex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 18:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/complex/</guid>
      <description>Somebody told me yesterday:
 You are not complex, you just make everybody else`s life complicated
 [irony on] Nice, thanks [irony off]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International teahouse office</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/international-teahouse-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 18:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/international-teahouse-office/</guid>
      <description>Pretty amazing: I am putting out fires with a customer in Colombia, with the help of an engineer in Japan, coordinated with the headquarters in Spain&amp;hellip; while sipping on a coconut white bubble tea at ArgoUnion Square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying to Rio with a character</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/flying-to-rio-with-a-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 10:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/flying-to-rio-with-a-character/</guid>
      <description>After arriving in JFK in the most predictable way (rain, snow, traffic or whatever) which is the combo E line + AirTrain, and boarding on a &amp;ldquo;last call&amp;rdquo; although I arrived early enough (due to the never-ending security lines, and the abnormal amount of passengers with special needs such as many small children in strollers, large hand-luggage, senior citizens, etc) I finally arrive at my seat on the flight New York – Rio de Janeiro, and I see it is occupied by… Rolls Royce car keys, with a Rolls Royce keyring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you see here...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-do-you-see-here.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 12:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-do-you-see-here.../</guid>
      <description>A green PacMan The market size you want to conquer Your shrinking market size Food to eat Food eaten A green tea – coconut – ginger vegan cake A memory A moment Enjoyment  &amp;hellip;
Does this post start to sound like an HSBC ad? I spend too much time in airports!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To be a CEO...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/to-be-a-ceo.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 22:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/to-be-a-ceo.../</guid>
      <description>means resisting the urge to kill yourself or kill others, and find a solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We the people... divorce = bankruptcy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/we-the-people...-divorce-bankruptcy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 17:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/we-the-people...-divorce-bankruptcy/</guid>
      <description>Walking on 8th Ave., I find this amazing signs on a lawyer`s office window (NO COMMENT):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In NY, puddles are dangerous</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/in-ny-puddles-are-dangerous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 16:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/in-ny-puddles-are-dangerous/</guid>
      <description>In Spain, kids are told not to step on a puddle because they can get dirty.
In NY kids do not need to be told to avoid puddles: from a very early age, they learn when puddles are frozen in the winter, they are a deadly slippery trap. Freezing time approaching. Welcome to NY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are charitable dinners and then charitable dinners</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/there-are-charitable-dinners-and-then-charitable-dinners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 10:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/there-are-charitable-dinners-and-then-charitable-dinners/</guid>
      <description>I hate charitable dinners where most (or almost all) of the money goes to caviar, tuxedos, valet parking and other hoopla.
Fortunately there are other charitable dinners, where you wont see any &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.escolar.net/MT/archives/2011/11/la-nueva-politica-de-igualdad.html&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.escolar.net/MT/archives/2011/11/la-nueva-politica-de-igualdad.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;PP mothers&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, like yesterdays organized by Didi, where people sit on the floor, eat off plastic plates, and enjoy Didis deliciously vegan cooking and sincere love, so just about all money collected goes to Calcuttas orphans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI?</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 11:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/ai/</guid>
      <description>😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tragedy of probability ignorance</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-tragedy-of-probability-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 13:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-tragedy-of-probability-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>When a M. Phil. from Cambridge, A.B. from Harvard, and M.D. from UCal writes an articleinsisting on a probabilistic fallacy, a trap where, in one way or another, many have fallen (from Eccles to Nagel), and this article is echoed in many sites (such as BoingBoing) and an infographicis made and becomes staff pick at visual.ly&amp;hellip; then you know ignorance is everywhere and very dangerous.
Read the article, then read Roy Weatherford`s &amp;ldquo;Philosophical foundations of probability theory&amp;rdquo; (or maybe something simpler), and once you grasp the concept of &amp;ldquo;a priori theories of probability&amp;rdquo;, laugh at those who think each one of us is a miracle&amp;hellip; we all are, but not because the probability of us being born is extremely small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/life-is.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 17:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/life-is.../</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; a deadly STD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of a cycle counter</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-importance-of-a-cycle-counter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 14:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/the-importance-of-a-cycle-counter/</guid>
      <description>Curious coincidence (or maybe not), two days after realising &amp;ldquo;something&amp;rdquo; was missing in one of my frequent logic diagrams, I saw an episodeof The Big Bang Theory in which Wollowitz discovers a flaw in Sheldon`s friendship algorithm.
Dr. Sheldon Cooper`s lack of a cycle counter in his friendship algorithmis not a trivial issue. The cycle counter is the &amp;ldquo;real life&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;context&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;awareness&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;empathy&amp;rdquo;, aspect of a logic interpretation of a social engagement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not so difficult (is it?)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/not-so-difficult-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 09:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/not-so-difficult-is-it/</guid>
      <description>In this cute decorative vinyl from chispum.com, the message says: &amp;ldquo;I want a boyfriend who only wants to sleep with me (and nobody else)&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>