<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CyberRights on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/cyberrights/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CyberRights on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 10:19:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/cyberrights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My EU policy recommendation published: &#34;Hacking Policy. Exploring Innovative Ways to Advance Policy Reform&#34;</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/my-eu-policy-recommendation-published-hacking-policy.-exploring-innovative-ways-to-advance-policy-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 10:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/my-eu-policy-recommendation-published-hacking-policy.-exploring-innovative-ways-to-advance-policy-reform/</guid>
      <description>Under the title &amp;ldquo;Hacking Policy. Exploring Innovative Ways to Advance Policy Reform&amp;rdquo; StartupEurope has published a report listing the Policy Recommendations that came out of the Policy Hackathon in San Francisco, where my team won the competition.
Download it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview for the art exhibition that I have curated and is currently being shown in Kaunas, Lithuania</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/interview-for-the-art-exhibition-that-i-have-curated-and-is-currently-being-shown-in-kaunas-lithuania/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/interview-for-the-art-exhibition-that-i-have-curated-and-is-currently-being-shown-in-kaunas-lithuania/</guid>
      <description>INTERVIEW with JORGE CORTELL, curator
By Airida Rekštytė – November 4, 2016
According to your profound theoretical education (sic) it will not be difficult to present us in short your intentions for organizing this event.
When did the idea of making this exhibition occur and what inspired it?
I have spent years as activist defending free software and online privacy, and opposing censorship.
During a dinner with the director of an event that focuses on those themes (the Internet Freedom Festival, also known as Circumvention Festival), I told him how it would be a nice challenge to try to convey the main messages of the Festivals themes into an art exhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The White House Chief Data Scientist assures me the White House strongly supports encryption and opposes back doors</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/the-white-house-chief-data-scientist-assures-me-the-white-house-strongly-supports-encryption-and-opposes-back-doors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 13:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/the-white-house-chief-data-scientist-assures-me-the-white-house-strongly-supports-encryption-and-opposes-back-doors/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday March 1 I had a conversation with Dr. DJ Patil, the First White House Chief Data Scientist, at the Venetian Hotel in Las Vegas.
He was interested in discussing ways in which the White House can help healthcare technology companies like mine. The first issue I raised was my concern over the FBI’s request for Apple to decrypt a suspected criminal’s iPhone.
My position in this issue is well known: weak encryption means weak security for ALL of us, so nobody can request weak security for security’s sake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing in London… even with Microsoft!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/playing-in-london-even-with-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 09:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/playing-in-london-even-with-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>These past few days have been quite “playful”.
On the one hand, I have just discovered, right around the corner from our apartment by London Bridge, a free and public playground that has an artificial grass hockey field, half a basketball court, 3 pingpong tables and even a beach volleyball court with sand and all! So obviously, the next day I went with my son to a sports equipment store and bought a soccer ball, a pingpong set, a basketball, a volleyball and a badminton set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My talk at the Circumvention Tech Festival, March 4th</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/my-talk-at-the-circumvention-tech-festival-march-4th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 23:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/my-talk-at-the-circumvention-tech-festival-march-4th/</guid>
      <description>This past winter I met Sandy and James from Open ITP in New York, and Pepe from Valencia. They were organizing the Circumvention Tech Festivalto be held in Las Naves, Valencia (Spain) March 1-6.
They invited me to give a talk, which was eventually scheduled for March 4th at 3pm. I titled the talk “When privacy does not mean the same to you and me”. It was meant to generate debate, to expose other people’s points of view, rather than to be a unidirectional speech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTO: a hyper-reading project</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/hto-a-hyper-reading-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 17:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/hto-a-hyper-reading-project/</guid>
      <description>Iban M. G. and Ben Martin have launched a writing project that breaks the boundaries of typical book in paper/digital format. Over the years I have seen many attempts to push the publishing world further. All commendable and appreciated. But so far I have not seen any project as ambitious as HTO.
Note: Literary review aside. I have not read the novel yet and, as a matter of fact, that`s irrelevant for the purposes of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Circumvention Tech Festival</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/the-circumvention-tech-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 15:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/the-circumvention-tech-festival/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My new OnePlus One phone is amazing</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/my-new-oneplus-one-phone-is-amazing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 22:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/my-new-oneplus-one-phone-is-amazing/</guid>
      <description>I have just bought a OnePlusOne phone, and have been using it for a couple of days. Let me tell you: it`s AMAZING.
If you have never heard of the company, dont worry, youre not alone. But you should definitely check it out, because their phones are incredibly high quality, high specs, and low price (mine was $349). No catch:
 Qualcomm© Snapdragon™ 801 processor with 2.5GHz Quad-core CPUs Adreno 330 GPU, 578MHz 64 GB eMMC 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I was forced to hack into Schiphol Airport wifi</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/i-was-forced-to-hack-into-schiphol-airport-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 12:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/i-was-forced-to-hack-into-schiphol-airport-wifi/</guid>
      <description>A couple weeks ago I was at Schiphol Airport in Amsterdam. Of course, when I arrive in an airport with enough time ahead of my boarding, I look for a plug and wifi. Luckily Schiphol is an excellent airport, offering both. The only problem is that every time I clicked on the &amp;ldquo;Enjoy unlimited free wifi – Connect&amp;rdquo; button, I got an &amp;ldquo;Unknown error 0&amp;rdquo; message back.
 Don`t tell me &amp;ldquo;Enjoy unlimited free wifi&amp;rdquo; and then try to prevent me from accessing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reset the net</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromecast &#43; Hola = Multimedia freedom</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/02/chromecast-hola-multimedia-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 18:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/02/chromecast-hola-multimedia-freedom/</guid>
      <description>How many times have you tried to access online media that was not available in your country? How many times have you gotten frustrated with proxy services?
How many times have you wished there was an easy way to wirelessly display online content on your TV without paying for expensive privative boxes?
Enter Hola.org+ ChromecastHola is a free browser extension used by 14 million people to access geographically restricted online media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate cowardice, political hypocrisy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/corporate-cowardice-political-hypocrisy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 15:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/corporate-cowardice-political-hypocrisy/</guid>
      <description>On July 25 I was asked by someone at IBM to write an article about the use of the cloud in healthcare:
 I’d like to offer you the opportunity to author an article which we would look to promote across all of our social properties, other external communications as well as our paid media sponsorships, i.e. blogs.
 I was given suggestions on article length, topic, and keywords, but freedom to write whatever I wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The key to the use of cloud in healthcare</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/the-key-to-the-use-of-cloud-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 12:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/the-key-to-the-use-of-cloud-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>In a single word: security.
By now there is no doubt about the advantages of the cloud: easy collaboration, scalability, ubiquity, sync, cost savings (21% on average, according to AFCOM 2011, 40% according to our own customers), rapid deployment, etc.
There is also no doubt about the need for a move to the cloud in healthcare: according to Enterprise Strategy Group, by 2015 an average of 665TB of data will be generated per hospital per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police state: TXT with police alert in TX</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/police-state-txt-with-police-alert-in-tx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 14:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/police-state-txt-with-police-alert-in-tx/</guid>
      <description>While in Fort Worth, TX, I received the following TXT:
 They who can give up essential liberty to obtain a little temporary safety, deserve neither liberty nor safety.
 Benjamin Franklin, 1775</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to abide to the law while rejecting threats</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/how-to-abide-to-the-law-while-rejecting-threats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 14:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/how-to-abide-to-the-law-while-rejecting-threats/</guid>
      <description>According to Spanish law
web(emphasis mine):
 Information intermediary suppliers:
    Do not have an obligation to supervise the contents they host, transmit, or classify in a link directory, but must collaborate with public authorities when required to interrupt an IT service or take a content down.
    They are not, in principle, responsible for alien content they host, transmit, or give access to, but could incur in responsibility if they take an active participation in its ellaboration or, if knowing of a particular material being being illegal, do not act swiftly to take it down or prevent access to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am being sued by a troll</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-being-sued-by-a-troll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 10:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-being-sued-by-a-troll/</guid>
      <description>A few hours after the first email, I received this second one with a threat (again, translated by me; here is the original):
 Mr. Cortell:
I can prove my identity and the defamatory content of the indicated page, as I said it has been notarized. I can also prove that this site is currently the subject of proceedings in the Courts of Barcelona, in which the prosecution has already ruled, appreciating criminal evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am requested to take a link down and... Streisand effect!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 01:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</guid>
      <description>Today I received this email (it was in Spanish, I have translated it into English because that is the main language of this blog, and in order to give this issue the international coverage that it deserves – sorry for any translation mistake since I am not a lawyer and he writes like an old-fashioned one trying to sound intimidating; here is the original):
 Mr. Cortell:
Currently I am suing Greg Prévôt in the Courts of Barcelona, author of a defamatory site which infringes upon my honor, whose link appears in which you administer, at the following address:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to celebrate 4th of July: defending our rights</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/how-to-celebrate-4th-of-july-defending-our-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 15:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/how-to-celebrate-4th-of-july-defending-our-rights/</guid>
      <description>I started my 4th of July&amp;ldquo;celebrations&amp;rdquo; one day early, by visiting the Declaration of Independence &amp;amp; Bill of Rights, handwritten by Thomas Jefferson, exhibited for the first time together, at the NYPL.
 Then, today (4th of July) I went to a protest to demand the restoration of the Fourth Amendment:
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5896836194188971633]
  “The right of the people to be secure in their persons, houses, papers, and effects, against unreasonable searches and seizures, shall not be violated&amp;hellip;”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two days in Panama</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/two-days-in-panama/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 15:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/two-days-in-panama/</guid>
      <description>Business took me again to Panama on Monday, for a quick trip (two days).
Tin roofed huts with satellite TV next to high rise office buildings, riding on an official (with sirens) tinted window SUV with driver and no license plates, and staying in a nice hotelthat was not extraordinary but had all and everything that I look for in a hotel (except indoors swimming pool). But it belongs to the friend (former Treasury Secretary) of a friend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed for Zoom News about the Mega case</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/interviewed-for-zoom-news-about-the-mega-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/interviewed-for-zoom-news-about-the-mega-case/</guid>
      <description>Interviewedby Aurora Muñoz for Zoom News about the Mega case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft, derivative works, parodies...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 10:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</guid>
      <description>Hugo sends me thisamazing song/video made in Minecraft. Of course, that leads to 10more, 14more&amp;hellip; there are so many!
When you make the tools available to the people, and allow them to create (in this case under the safe harbor of &amp;ldquo;parody&amp;rdquo;) wonderful things happen. Its NOT all about the money, profit, control... Its about imagination, art, creativity, culture. Thats how it happens: copying, re-using, mixing, adjusting, modifying... thats what creativity is really about (or did you think it was about &amp;ldquo;inventing&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;making unheard of things out of thin air&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYPL support and citizen budget involvement</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/nypl-support-and-citizen-budget-involvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 12:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/nypl-support-and-citizen-budget-involvement/</guid>
      <description>After supporting the NYPL efforts to fight back budget cuts, I have received a lovely message of thanks from Christine C. Quinn (Speaker, NYC Council), along with a very nice suggestion:
 Dear New Yorker, Many thanks for your email expressing your support for our city`s libraries. [&amp;hellip;]
We cant do it alone, though, and I hope youll consider signing up for Council &amp;ldquo;enews&amp;rdquo;. These issue-based e-mail updates are a great way for us to stay connected and engaged with you and other New Yorkers about the budget, healthcare, and other important issues affecting our city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I admire these criminals</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-admire-these-criminals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 15:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-admire-these-criminals/</guid>
      <description>In Spain, the conservative PP government is planning to make &amp;ldquo;passive resistance&amp;rdquo; a crime(as well as organizing demonstrations using internet technologies).
I have these 4 criminals` magnetic puppets on my fridge. 2 were outlawed (and had to flee) by German Nazis. 1 had to flee Spanish dictatorship because he was a Communist. And the other one was thrown in jail by British occupation forces for &amp;ldquo;passive resistance&amp;rdquo;.
 I will not let anyone walk through my mind with their dirty feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with face.com face recognition technology</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/playing-with-face.com-face-recognition-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 17:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/playing-with-face.com-face-recognition-technology/</guid>
      <description>While I am preparing a loooooong post about technology and privacy (with a provocative twist, for a change 😈 ), I have decided to play with face.com‘s face recognition technology.
What do you think? On target (hint: no, not on target, I am not THAT old, and definitely I AM a male)? Scary (hint: only if we are unaware of these technologies and their uses)?&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The price of standing up for your rights: Opt-Out at Atlanta`s airport scanner</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-price-of-standing-up-for-your-rights-opt-out-at-atlantas-airport-scanner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 14:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-price-of-standing-up-for-your-rights-opt-out-at-atlantas-airport-scanner/</guid>
      <description>Atlanta`s Hartsfield airport has been having one of those uselessscanners that show passengers naked for a while now. But the last time I was there, they were being tested, and most passengers did not go through them. Today, though, as I approached the security line, I saw that next to every metal detector, there was one of those scanners. &amp;ldquo;Wow, this is getting worse&amp;rdquo;, I thought, while seeing how almost everybody was going through the scanners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infographic on the Hypocrisy in Hollywood</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/infographic-on-the-hypocrisy-in-hollywood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 01:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/infographic-on-the-hypocrisy-in-hollywood/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better privacy through your browser</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/better-privacy-through-your-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 17:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/better-privacy-through-your-browser/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to improve your online privacy? Go ahead, install HTTPSand Collusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MLK speech &amp;quot;I have a dream&amp;quot; under restrictive copyright</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/mlk-speech-quoti-have-a-dreamquot-under-restrictive-copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 18:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/mlk-speech-quoti-have-a-dreamquot-under-restrictive-copyright/</guid>
      <description>Embarrassing. We should all be ashamed. At least we can access his words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almodovar and SGAE force cancellation of film screenings at NY Library</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/almodovar-and-sgae-force-cancellation-of-film-screenings-at-ny-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 17:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/almodovar-and-sgae-force-cancellation-of-film-screenings-at-ny-library/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went to the New York Public Library to see Pedro Almodovars &amp;quot;Talk to her&amp;quot;, as part of a &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;httpss://www.nypl.org/blog/2011/12/06/films-pedro-almodovar&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;httpss://www.nypl.org/blog/2011/12/06/films-pedro-almodovar&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;series&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; of Almodovars films screenings in the NYPL. But, to my surprise, the screening (and remainder ones) had been cancelled.
I talked to the person in the information desk, and she told me that the collecting society (that would be the despicable SGAE, which does not even deserve a link in my blog) and Almodovar`s Production company (El Deseo Producciones) had raised what they had previously been asking for as royalties or compensation for the (free) screening of the (not in movie theater) films, and the amount they were now asking was so high, the NYPL could not afford it, so they had to cancel the screenings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArtHack Exhibit closing party in Brooklyn</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 22:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday I went to the ArtHack Exhibitclosing party at 319 ScholesSt, Brooklyn (New York).
Located in an industrial complex in Brooklyn, at night, loooong two blocks from the subway, graffiti all over, small door&amp;hellip; that gave way to heaven: young (I was the oldest hacker in that space, but I did not feel that way) energetic happy people tinkering with technology and proudly showing their &amp;ldquo;toys&amp;rdquo; (hacks, mashups, creations, or whatever).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RePress: fight online censorship with a WP Plug-In</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/repress-fight-online-censorship-with-a-wp-plug-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 17:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/repress-fight-online-censorship-with-a-wp-plug-in/</guid>
      <description>I just installed RePress: This plug-in enables you to magically uncensor any website on the internet from your own WordPress installation. Why and How.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protest against SOPA on your site: easy code</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/protest-against-sopa-on-your-site-easy-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 09:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/protest-against-sopa-on-your-site-easy-code/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Sara, there is a very easy way to add code to your site to protest against SOPA:
Drop the following code in between your two tags on your site, your users will be redirected to the blackout page that describes what you are doing and why.
`Then, when the protest is over, simply remove the added code. The protest is starting at 12am on 1/18, and lasts 24 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia blackout protesting SOPA and PIPA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/wikipedia-blackout-protesting-sopa-and-pipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 19:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/wikipedia-blackout-protesting-sopa-and-pipa/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;div&amp;gt; Today, the Wikipedia community &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;w:en:Wikipedia:SOPA initiative/Action&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;httpss://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/en:Wikipedia:SOPA_initiative/Action&amp;quot;&amp;gt;announced its decision&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; to black out the English-language Wikipedia for 24 hours, worldwide, beginning at 05:00 UTC on Wednesday, January 18 (you can read the &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;Press releases/English Wikipedia to go dark&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;httpss://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Press_releases/English_Wikipedia_to_go_dark&amp;quot;&amp;gt;statement from the Wikimedia Foundation here&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;). The blackout is a protest against proposed legislation in the United States—the &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;w:en:Stop Online Piracy Act&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;httpss://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/en:Stop_Online_Piracy_Act&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Stop Online Piracy Act (SOPA)&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The absurd hypocrisy of the recent &amp;quot;Intelectual Property&amp;quot; legal abuse</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-absurd-hypocrisy-of-the-recent-quotintelectual-propertyquot-legal-abuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 17:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-absurd-hypocrisy-of-the-recent-quotintelectual-propertyquot-legal-abuse/</guid>
      <description>The USA has become the largest exporter of censorship.
Based on wrong beliefs, manipulated data, and self-declared ignorant politicians, their legislative body cooks up a law designed to restrict competition, serving the interests (apparently, although as any freshman Economics student will tell you, that is not really the case) of an oligopoly of media-(sic)culture megacorporations that would not recognized the present (not to say &amp;ldquo;future&amp;rdquo;) if it hit them in the face, represented by multi-million dollar copyright infringers, while stomping on basic citizens` rights (not that they seem to care anyway, since they allow such basic rights violations as warrantless GPS monitoring, or unlimited incarceration without trial).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga Guru uses copyright to sue competitor</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 19:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</guid>
      <description>Ego, money, power, abuse, restriction&amp;hellip; shame on those who stain the &amp;ldquo;holy&amp;rdquo; teachings.
Source: NYT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing private copies for moving to NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/preparing-private-copies-for-moving-to-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 16:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/preparing-private-copies-for-moving-to-ny/</guid>
      <description>In Spain we have a legal right called &amp;ldquo;private copy&amp;rdquo; by which anyone can make a copy (for non-commercial use) of their copyrighted content (movies, music, books, etc). To offset the supposed loss (many studies prove this &amp;ldquo;loss&amp;rdquo; to be a fallacy) we Spaniards pay the so-called &amp;ldquo;Digital canon&amp;rdquo;, a tax levied on blank media (CDs, HardDisks, printers, photocopiers, etc, etc) and managed by private monopolistic institutions called &amp;ldquo;collecting societies&amp;rdquo;, some run by supposed alcohol-consuming, whore-user, money-embezzler, tax-evading criminals (or so goes the accusations brought to a number of them by the Attorney General).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a movement!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-a-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 10:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-a-movement/</guid>
      <description>First things first: thanks to whomever thought I would be interested in joining MCAthrough RiseUp, BUT&amp;hellip;
 Don`t subscribe me to a list without my consent Don`t do so without at least letting me know who you are Don`t assume I might be interested in something because it sounds related to my interest Don`t align me with &amp;ldquo;scientific socialism&amp;rdquo; when I am a declared anarchist Don`t make me waste my time on a list where the first 20 or so messages are split between arguing troskist, marxist, rose of lenburguist, bujarinist, bakuninist, leninist, hotsiminist, guevarist, maoist, castrist&amp;hellip; and people who want to be taken off the list  So, thanks (and I show it by talking about your project here), but show a little respect for other people`s rights, please.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>