<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>London on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/london/</link>
    <description>Recent content in London on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 15:13:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/london/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A little over 24 hours in Peru</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/05/a-little-over-24-hours-in-peru/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 15:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/05/a-little-over-24-hours-in-peru/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I left London to go to Peru for a business trip. I was connecting in Madrid but, due to a 4-hour delay in the departure of the flight, I missed my red-eye connection to Lima.
Fortunately, European Union regulations mandate that airlines feed and provide shelter to stranded passengers (subject to some conditions), unlike in the USA, where the same unfortunate circumstance is usually the passengers’ problem. So Iberia gave me a voucher for a dinner, a breakfast, a hotel night in a nearby hotel, two phone calls and the transfer to and from the hotel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very interesting insights from the UBS Forum 2017</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/very-interesting-insights-from-the-ubs-forum-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 16:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/very-interesting-insights-from-the-ubs-forum-2017/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Giles and Magda invited me to attend the annual UBS Forum at the beautiful Rosewood Hotel, one of those hotels in a renovated palace in the heart of London, with a resident dog.
Held in major financial cities across Europe, the UBS Forum is presented under the banner &amp;ldquo;sharper opinions – smarter decisions”, where UBS specialists and external experts provide insights on key topics. This years` speakers and topics were:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Revolution needs a Revolution</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 17:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went with my wife and son to visit the Victoria &amp;amp; Albert`s Museum exhibition You Say You Want a Revolution? Records and Rebels 1966-1970. The aim of the exhibition was quite clear:
 How have the finished and unfinished revolutions of the late 1960s changed the way we live today and think about the future?
 I was very much looking forward to visiting the exhibition. It is SO timely, and SO needed, I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When your son falls into a frozen lake</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/when-your-son-falls-into-a-frozen-lake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 10:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/when-your-son-falls-into-a-frozen-lake/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I took a stroll through Wimbledon Commons with my son, as my wife was traveling.It was a typical London day: 3 seasons in a day. When we decided to leave the apartment it was sunny and felt kind of warm. When we arrived at the forest, it was gloomy and chilly. And by the time we made it back home, it was already night time and really cold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the UK-China Hi! Technology event in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/invited-to-the-uk-china-hi-technology-event-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 16:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/invited-to-the-uk-china-hi-technology-event-in-london/</guid>
      <description>For reasons beyond the scope of this post I was invited to participate in the UK-China Hi! Technology event in London.
The event was well attended by a large number of entrepreneurs, funds and investors from the UK and China.
The highlight of the event, for me, other than a couple of really interesting contacts, was to see all these suited-up people lining up to try the VR sets (HTC, Oculus, Hololens, etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting the London Design Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/visiting-the-london-design-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 08:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/visiting-the-london-design-museum/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I visited the Design Museum(&amp;ldquo;The world`s leading museum devoted to contemporary design in every form from architecture and fashion to graphics, product and industrial design&amp;rdquo;) in its spectacular new location on High Street Kensington (London), with my son.
The #newdesignmuseum opened its doors in its new location only 5 days ago. The building and renovation are great, and in a nice location: on the edge of Holland Park, with the added bonus of being near the Kyoto Garden, Muji, and not far from the Serpentine Gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to speak at GIANT Health event in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/invited-to-speak-at-giant-health-event-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 15:22:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/invited-to-speak-at-giant-health-event-in-london/</guid>
      <description>Right after I returned from Germany, and before departing for Paraguay, I was invited to speak at the GIANT Health event(the “global innovation and new technology health event), health in The Coronet, London.
The event run for 3 days, November 16-18, with 3 parallel tracks, and it included over 200 speakers. I spoke November 18, in the main auditorium.
There was an exhibition area, with several companies and organizations showing their innovations and technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to participate in PA Consulting event</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/invited-to-participate-in-pa-consulting-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 08:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/invited-to-participate-in-pa-consulting-event/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I was invited to participate in a Healthcare Innovation workshop at PA Consulting in London.
Beyond the cute venue, and spectacular list of attendees from the healthcare, industry, and political spaces (“Don’t waste time talking to someone with ‘Lord’ in his title, they are not there to really work”, one of my colleagues advises me), what impressed me was the extremely well organized, choreographed, and disciplined approach to innovation they had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited by the Duque of York to have dinner at Windsor Castle November 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/invited-by-the-duque-of-york-to-have-dinner-at-windsor-castle-november-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 20:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/invited-by-the-duque-of-york-to-have-dinner-at-windsor-castle-november-3/</guid>
      <description>The other day I received a letter from Buckingham Palace, inviting me to have dinner with the Duke of York (Prince Andrew) on Thursday at Windsor Castle.
I was curious to see the castle from the inside: it is a medieval style fortress, filled with military memorabilia (guns, swords, lances, armors…), banners and crests. It was more Game of Thrones than Harry Potter.
The reception was held at the Grand Reception Room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My company has been named “Top Scaleup in the UK”</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-company-has-been-named-top-scaleup-in-the-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 07:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-company-has-been-named-top-scaleup-in-the-uk/</guid>
      <description>For second consecutive year, my company has been named “Top Scaleup in the UK”. This means that we are growing fast, and also that I get invited to cool events. One of those events was a reception and a ‘Ten Years From Now’ series of keynotes at the Royal Institution of Great Britain, another one a mentoring session at London’s City Hall, and another one a series of talks at Google Campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween in Wimbledon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/halloween-in-wimbledon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 07:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/halloween-in-wimbledon/</guid>
      <description>Halloween has arrived in Wimbledon. The multicolored leaves paint their annual natural mosaic, one of the many subjective manifestations where we can observe our mind at work, interpreting events. Do you get taken away by the beauty of the color range? Does it make you wonder why everybody finds beautiful a cyclical natural event that occurs because tree leaves die, fall and rot? Do you associate it with annoyingly unpredictable weather and uncomfortably falling temperatures?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Future Decoded 2016</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/microsoft-future-decoded-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 20:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/microsoft-future-decoded-2016/</guid>
      <description>November 1 I attended Future Decoded, the annual event where Microsoft and Partners present their forward looking products and concepts.
Besides some cool “event attractions” (like the Back To The Future Delorean, seeing how data is not completely deleted even if you deep freeze a hard drive, the Bloodhound record-breaking car, or seeing the inside of a Rolls Royce plane turbine), the key for me was to be able to demonstrate my company’s software running on an amazing 84” Microsoft Surface Hub, and attending the invitation-only Microsoft Executive Party at the Sunborn Yacht Hotel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DHVF, participating in a collective art performance, and meetings in Oxford Science Park</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/dhvf-participating-in-a-collective-art-performance-and-meetings-in-oxford-science-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 19:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/dhvf-participating-in-a-collective-art-performance-and-meetings-in-oxford-science-park/</guid>
      <description>The last couple of weeks in October I went to Valencia to attend the Digital Health Venture Forum, where I received the Best Presentation Award.
After spending a few days with my family and my Spanish team, and participating in an art installation by the SuperFlex collective on the 25th, I returned to London.
October 27 I went to the beautiful Oxford Science Park to have a couple of business meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some meetings in London and Paris: from UK`s Secretary of Health to Microsoft`s CEO</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/some-meetings-in-london-and-paris-from-uks-secretary-of-health-to-microsofts-ceo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 16:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/some-meetings-in-london-and-paris-from-uks-secretary-of-health-to-microsofts-ceo/</guid>
      <description>The last few days have been quite hectic. So much so that I`m going to &amp;ldquo;bundle&amp;rdquo; them into one or two very heterogeneous posts.
By the end of September I had to attend a few events, like being invited to a member of Microsoft`s Partner Advisory Council (we held the first meeting at the InterContinental London Park Lane Hotel), or an E2E networking dinner at Charlotte Street Hotel:
Tuesday October 4 I travelled to Paris to meet a South American Vice-minister of Health in IBM France:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to speak at Microsoft Healthcare event</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/08/invited-to-speak-at-microsoft-healthcare-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 15:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/08/invited-to-speak-at-microsoft-healthcare-event/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday August 9th, I was invited to talk about Personalised Medicine at Microsoft’s event “Empowering Health in a mobile first and cloud first world”, at Microsoft’s UK headquarters in Reading (UK).
There were very interesting sessions on Intelligent Cloud, Microsoft Research (with whom we are collaborating) work on radiology and genomics, Introduction to productivity in health, Revolutionising infection control, National Technology Officer’s Cloud Update, Transdermal Sensors in Paediatric Care, Introduction to personalised computing in health, Virtual care clinics in Sweden, Digital wellbeing, The venture programme for health, NHS…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyperJapan 2016 London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/hyperjapan-2016-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 15:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/hyperjapan-2016-london/</guid>
      <description>Today we went with my sister and brother-in-law, who are visiting for a few days, to HyperJapanin London Olympia.
Silly and fun, full of cosplay and otakus. Kawaii!
^.^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wimbledon tennis madness</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/wimbledon-tennis-madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 14:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/wimbledon-tennis-madness/</guid>
      <description>I live in Wimbledon. We moved here from London Bridge because this area is much more relaxed and has great parks within walking distance. But for two weeks a year, this town becomes the tennis capital of the world.
I can post this collection of photos showing how crazy the town gets for two weeks now that the Wimbledon Tennis Championships 2016 are over, and I can tell because I could hear the players moan, the umpire call the score… let alone the crowd roaring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A week of meetings in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/a-week-of-meetings-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 09:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/a-week-of-meetings-in-london/</guid>
      <description>After the trip to Boston I came down with the flu, of course on a weekend as usual. So Monday I had zero energy, but a week ahead with an usual large number of meetings around London, so I had to do “magic calendar tricks” to be able to make all of them and to also attend several events. The main “trick” is to concentrate meetings geographically, adding into the calendar the time it takes to go from point A to point B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Society and Forbidden Planet London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/japan-society-and-forbidden-planet-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 08:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/japan-society-and-forbidden-planet-london/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday , on my way from an event to a meeting, I made two stops. The first one in Forbidden Planet.
Forbidden Planet is a comic store that I enjoyed tremendously while living in New York. While not exactly Tokyo’s Mandarake, Forbidden Planet had enough variety to make it interesting. What I did not know is that they had such a large store in London! It is a fun place full of comic (and non-comic) books, manga, merchandise, figures, posters…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the Amazon Web Services Summit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/invited-to-the-amazon-web-services-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 07:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/invited-to-the-amazon-web-services-summit/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday and Thursday, I was invited to attend the Amazon Web Services Summit in London’s Excel center.
Besides an exhibition area with many vendors (some of them already suppliers to my company) like NewRelic, DataDog, GitHub, Chef, Alscient, Teradici, DataPipe, Ruxit, CloudCheckr, Amazon Activate, Elastic, Redis, etc, all with their great swag (mostly t-shirts and stickers, but lots of giveaways, from drones to iWatches), the highlight was the conference sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating the non-comissioned art piece “Diangle” for the Tate Modern Gallery</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/creating-the-non-comissioned-art-piece-diangle-for-the-tate-modern-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 11:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/creating-the-non-comissioned-art-piece-diangle-for-the-tate-modern-gallery/</guid>
      <description>Thursday June 23 I was given the opportunity to create a non-comissioned art piece at the Tate Gallery new extension Switch House.
Within Meschac Gaba (1961, Benin) “Architecture Room” installation part of the “Museum of Contemporary African Art” exhibit, the artist invitation was to build my own imaginary museum… and what better place to do that than in the recently inaugurated Switch House extension of the Tate Gallery by Herzog &amp;amp; de Meuron?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting the new Tate Modern Switch House</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/visiting-the-new-tate-modern-switch-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/visiting-the-new-tate-modern-switch-house/</guid>
      <description>While narrowly avoiding the fire alarm evacuation that happened a couple of hours before we got there, what we could not avoid was the crowds. In any case, it is always a pleasure to see an expansion to an already amazing gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to Health Tech Innovators event in London City Hall</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-health-tech-innovators-event-in-london-city-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 09:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-health-tech-innovators-event-in-london-city-hall/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday June 21 I was invited to attend the Health Tech Innovators event that took place in London City Hall, organized by Digital Health London, MedCity, and Tech London Advocates.
It consisted of three panels (NHS, Innovators, and Corporate) and an open-bar networking.
Besides some interesting presentations, the main point as always was to network with old colleagues (like Sara – CEO of MedCity, Kay – Health Chair Tech London Advocates, Nooman – Silicon Valley Bank, or Hak – Advisor) and new ones (Brian – Partner PWC Health Advisory, Dough – Medical Director Aviva, John – Healthcare Konica Minolta, Marco – Health Solutions Janssen, Ifan – Healthcare Welsh Government, Martin – NIHR, Axel – ICL, and many more).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Father’s Day gift: building a Picade with my son</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/ultimate-fathers-day-gift-building-a-picade-with-my-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 13:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/ultimate-fathers-day-gift-building-a-picade-with-my-son/</guid>
      <description>For Father’s Day (we live in London, so we celebrate it today, unlike in Spain which is March 19) my wife gave me the “Ultimate Father`s Day” gift, from TechCamp UK. [Thank you, love!]
It consisted of a workshop with other father-son / father-daughter “teams”, held at the Iron Yard (The Leathermarket – London), where we built a desktop arcade machine in 5 hours (including lunch break), following the directions from Tom and Tom, using the Picadeset, setting up and using the Raspberry Pi, custom OS, emulators, ROMs, loudspeakers, power supply, LCD screen, etc:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the AAF Art Show</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-the-aaf-art-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 14:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-the-aaf-art-show/</guid>
      <description>Today I went with my parents and my son to the AAF art show in Hampstead (London).
A good percentage (around 50%?) of works and an even higher percentage of galleries were the same as last year, but it was nonetheless interesting. As always.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to attend the E2Exchange Annual National Reception</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-attend-the-e2exchange-annual-national-reception/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 14:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-attend-the-e2exchange-annual-national-reception/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday, I was invited to attend the E2Exchange Annual National Reception at Banking Hall (London)
It started as a fun networking evening event, where I met all kinds of people, from VCs, to the owner of a large bank, to PR specialists… even a hypnotherapist!
Some politicians, like The Secretary of State for Business, had confirmed their attendance and were scheduled to debate Brexit, but they cancelled at the last minute due to the terrible murder of Jo Cox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest speaker at KPMG UK Health event</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/guest-speaker-at-kpmg-uk-health-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 16:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/guest-speaker-at-kpmg-uk-health-event/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was invited by KPMG UKto be a guest speaker at their Health Get Together event.
It was a pleasure to be invited to participate in their internal event. It gave me an inside look at how consultants work, and I also had a chance to listen to a very interesting internal presentation about their social media use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to InfoSecurity Europe</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-infosecurity-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 15:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-infosecurity-europe/</guid>
      <description>Today I was invited to attend InfoSecurity Europe, Europe`s largest Information Security industry event.
As always, it was interesting to have a chance to catch up with this rapidly moving field, and a great opportunity to chat with old friends.
Apart from gimmicks (VR everywhere, car racing and helicopter simulators, giant robots, etc), swag (all kinds of Star Wars and other Sci-Fi related giveaways, from toys to t-shirts) and junk food (from candy to icecream to chips, the booths did not have healthy alternatives, although the food vendors did), the most interesting part of these events is always the talks, specifically the hands-on demos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited with my son to Intel Buzz videogame developer workshop</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-with-my-son-to-intel-buzz-videogame-developer-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 17:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-with-my-son-to-intel-buzz-videogame-developer-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Today I was invited, along with my son, who at 14 has been a videogame developer for years, to attend the Intel Buzz videogame developer workshop. It was not only a lot of fun, but WONDERFUL to attend with him!
Although a small event, it ended up being extremely interesting, with an area to try indie games and new technologies, and a long list of talks and panels, including one-on-ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manchester</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/manchester/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 19:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/manchester/</guid>
      <description>On May 10 I traveled to Manchester for a business meeting.
After the meeting, I had a couple free hours left before boarding my train back, so I decided to walk around Manchester University (where I will be attending a Bioinformatics Course soon) and visit the eclectic and adorable Manchester Museum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wimbledon breakfast</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/wimbledon-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 19:26:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/wimbledon-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>In England, Summer apparently lasts about 3 days. And it arrives (and leaves) in May.
Those three days were very nice: we went for walks in the parks and village, we enjoyed the flowers blooming and seeing families have fun and catch their vitamin-D-processing-sun-ray-yearly-dose, and we had a lovely breakfast in our castle’s balcony seeing a group of elders play cricket in the Wimbledon Practice Courts.
It was nice, albeit brief, Summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Itadaki Zen: Japanese Vegan restaurant in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/itadaki-zen-japanese-vegan-restaurant-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 19:25:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/itadaki-zen-japanese-vegan-restaurant-in-london/</guid>
      <description>One of my corporate advisors is Vegetarian, and we wanted to have a meeting over dinner. He tasked me with finding a restaurant in central London, so I chose Itadaki Zen, a vegan Japanese restaurant.
I vividly remember Kajitsu, a Shojin cuisine restaurant in New York, as one of the most surprising, delicious, and different restaurants I have ever dined in. So I thought this could be similar. But unfortunately it is not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horse riding surrounded by parks</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/horse-riding-surrounded-by-parks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 15:23:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/horse-riding-surrounded-by-parks/</guid>
      <description>As we imagined, the highlight of moving to Wimbledon is being surrounded by nature.
On one side, 0.3 miles to the East, we have the family-friendly and very civilized Wimbledon Park, with its swans and ducks, water sports, minigolf, tennis courts… even beach volleyball!
On the other side, 0.3 miles to the West, we have the wild and lush dense forest of Wimbledon Common:
Adjacent to Wimbledon Common we have Richmond Park, with its live and free roaming deer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to a castle</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/moving-to-a-castle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 14:54:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/moving-to-a-castle/</guid>
      <description>After a year living by London Bridge, we have decided to move out. Our apartment was nice, and the location quite convenient, but the constant flood of tourists to the Borough Market and the Bridge made me feel just like I did when I lived in Mid-Town/5th Avenue Manhattan (New York) a few years ago. Back then, just like now, I decided to move to an area that felt more “neighborhood” and less “tourist landmark” (in that case it was Chelsea), and it proved to be the right choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up my first art exhibit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/setting-up-my-first-art-exhibit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 14:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/setting-up-my-first-art-exhibit/</guid>
      <description>The weekend of February 27 and 28 I set up my first art exhibition as Independent International Art Curator.
In collaboration with the Internet Freedom Festival, held in Las Naves (Valencia) from 2 to 6 March, Net Freedom Art Showis an international, itinerant, collective and multidisciplinary contemporary art show. After its debut in Valencia, it will be exhibited in galleries around the world (New York, London, Santiago de Chile, and Kaunas).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft event at Sushi Samba London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/microsoft-event-at-sushi-samba-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 18:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/microsoft-event-at-sushi-samba-london/</guid>
      <description>On February 23 Microsoft invited me to an industry event at Sushi Samba, which is located on the 39th floor of the Heron Tower in London.
I have never given a standing presentation right next to a floor to ceiling window with the clouds closer to me than the ground!
The event was nice, as it was the venue. Thank you for inviting me, Microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s pretend none of this ever happened</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 10:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</guid>
      <description>Walking towards my London Shoreditch office
to meet the Swiss investor and his impeccable suit,
leaving the City bankers’s coffee-holding fast pace behind,
I notice the absence nobody seems to
Where did he go?
His sleeping sack and pillow still on the sidewalk
as annoyingly positioned in the corner as always
But he’s gone
.
I wonder and I worry
his failing body, almost as absent as his lost gaze</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the Mayor’s International Programme launch at London City Hall</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/invited-to-the-mayors-international-programme-launch-at-london-city-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 16:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/invited-to-the-mayors-international-programme-launch-at-london-city-hall/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was invited to attend the official launch of the Mayor’s International Programmeat City Hall, London, where I met some of London`s top entrepreneurs, mentors, and the Mayor (who gave a short speech using 007 as a reference).
One of my companies (Kanteron Systems) has been selected as one of the 35 companies forming the initial cohort.
The programme will support high growth businesses from London’s Technology, Life Sciences and Urban sectors to expand their businesses internationally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Big Bang Data” and “Tintin” exhibitions at Somerset House, London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/01/big-bang-data-and-tintin-exhibitions-at-somerset-house-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 18:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/01/big-bang-data-and-tintin-exhibitions-at-somerset-house-london/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we went to see a couple exhibitions at Somerset House, in London.
The first exhibition we saw was “TINTIN: Hergé`s Masterpiece”. Basic but obviously appealing, it was too crowded to be enjoyable.
The second one was “Big Bang Data”.
While undoubtedly interesting, especially for someone who works in, teaches, and loves bid data and technology like myself, to me the most interesting aspect of this exhibition is that everyone who was there had already experienced the subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ai Weiwei at the Royal Academy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/ai-weiwei-at-the-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 13:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/ai-weiwei-at-the-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>On December 4 I was lucky enough to be invited to visit Ai Weiwei`s exhibition at the Royal Academy.
I knew I would enjoy it since Ai Weiwei is one of my favourite artists. I knew even my son, my wife and my mother-in-law would enjoy it, since Ai Weiweis art is highly figurative and symbolic, even to the point of being obvious with his latest works (which makes its appeal that more far-reaching if slightly less elitist).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tate Modern curating methodology</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/tate-modern-curating-methodology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 13:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/tate-modern-curating-methodology/</guid>
      <description>December 2 I went to the Tate Modernwith the whole family, since my mother-in-law was visiting from overseas.
I really like how it is set up according to concepts, rather than chronologically, by artists, or by styles. It feels more like an art gallery (which it is) than a museum. It puts things into the subjective focus of the curator. I wonder how much the artists themselves would agree with the collection parameters, but it definitely is a welcome departure from the more traditional museum logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetings in London (HSBC, Microsoft, solicitors, events...)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/meetings-in-london-hsbc-microsoft-solicitors-events.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 10:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/meetings-in-london-hsbc-microsoft-solicitors-events.../</guid>
      <description>In the past few days I have had quite a few &amp;ldquo;interesting&amp;rdquo; meetings.
On November 26 I was invited to the Pre-Christmas Reception at HSBC corporate offices, along with other business owners/entrepreneurs: a weird mix of industries and interests (which I find a complete waste of business networking time). But one thing was completely homogeneous: wherever you looked, there were men. Middle aged, white, balding, dark suit-wearing men. Just like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice day in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/nice-day-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 10:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/nice-day-in-london/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday was a very nice day in London, which was convenient because I decided to walk to my two appointments, which were quite far apart.
First I met with a PR firm. You know their founders are into art when in the meeting room we were in (one of many) they had a J. Opie and a W. Hewett. Nice. Bonus points.
Then I walked to the Japanese Embassy, where I had been invited to a symposium on big data research for dementia (actually, I chuckled when I thought that, in a way, it could be argued that “big data seems to cause dementia in some vendors”) 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V&amp;A and Science Museums</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/va-and-science-museums/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 15:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/va-and-science-museums/</guid>
      <description>Sunday November 8th we went to the Victoria and Albert Museum and the Science Museum for some educational fun weekend.
I love the V&amp;amp;A for its interesting variety. We saw sculptures (although lot more Rodin than Bernini), Medieval objects (from reliquaries to clothing and drawings), and some fine examples of Japanese design.
In the Science Museum we went to see the small but extremely interesting exhibition on Ada Lovelace’s history. We learned a lot and I believe it was a great inspiration to my son.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royal Veterinary College</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/royal-veterinary-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 15:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/royal-veterinary-college/</guid>
      <description>On Friday November 6 I was invited to a Scientific Symposium on Translational Research, held at the Biotech Innovation Center. The fun part was to stop at the Royal Veterinary College cafeteria, with their interesting museum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>British Library</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/british-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 20:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/british-library/</guid>
      <description>On Friday November 6, on my way to a meeting, I stopped by the British Library. It had been quite a long time since I had been there.
You need a special permit to use their volumes, but they have a very active schedule of events and presentations, and a wonderful museum.
Amongst the “treasures” they have, there are manuscripts from Mozart (‘Verzeichnüss aller meiner Werke’), Beethoven, Magna Carta, John Lennon, Percy Bysshe Shelley (‘The Mask of Anarchy’), and many other historically relevant documents, like the first printed music in western musical notation using Gutemberg’s movable type (Southern Germany c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited by the London Stock Exchange to participate in the market opening ceremony</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/invited-by-the-london-stock-exchange-to-participate-in-the-market-opening-ceremony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 14:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/invited-by-the-london-stock-exchange-to-participate-in-the-market-opening-ceremony/</guid>
      <description>On Friday, November 6th, I was invited by Marcus Stuttard, head of AIM (the London Stock Exchange’s growth market), to participate in the London Stock Exchange market opening ceremony, which takes place daily at 8:00 am.
The ceremony offers companies joining London Stock Exchange’s markets the opportunity to mark their success on the day of their admission. The event was followed by drinks and breakfast.
The reason why I was invited is because one of my companies (Kanteron Systems) had been selected as a member of the #ScaleUpClub 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Million masks march</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/million-masks-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 14:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/million-masks-march/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday, coming back home from a meeting, I run into the Million Masks March. While I assume I agree with most of their anti-system protests (the truth is I did not bother to read them), I think their choice of Guy Fawkes as an &amp;ldquo;icon&amp;rdquo;, even if a graphical one as proposed by the comic/movie &amp;ldquo;V for Vendetta&amp;rdquo;, is a very stupid one. Just read about what that historical figure had in mind and judge for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Press Photo 2015</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/world-press-photo-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 13:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/world-press-photo-2015/</guid>
      <description>Last Thursday, on my way to a business meeting, I stopped by the Southbank Center, to view the World Press Photo 2015 exhibition. It was a great collection of pieces, but I particularly liked (or was most shocked by) the work of Tomas van Houtryve (2nd prize stories), Cai Sheng Xiang (1st prize singles), Turi Calafato (3rd prize stories), and Arash Khamooshi (3rd prize stories).
Definitely worthwhile visiting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetings in London in cool places</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/meetings-in-london-in-cool-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 13:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/meetings-in-london-in-cool-places/</guid>
      <description>I have business meetings all the time. Sometimes in person, sometimes via videoconference.
It’s always about the people you meet, and the business you discuss. But sometimes, the location is extraordinary, or fun, or interesting for whatever reason. So once in a while I will add a few comments or pictures about those meetings. For example, check out the views from the 32nd floor of the Tower 42 building, or the reception room of the Royal Institute of British Architects!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Illustration Awards Exhibition at Somerset House</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/world-illustration-awards-exhibition-at-somerset-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 17:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/world-illustration-awards-exhibition-at-somerset-house/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday October 31st we went to the World Illustration AwardsExhibition at Somerset House(London). It was a pure delight. Not only it was hosted at one of my favorite venues in London, but the selection of works by contemporary illustrators was quite good. The one I liked the most was Malika Favre’s Futurist-inspired posters for the BAFTAs 2015, but there were many remarkable ones, like Bartosz Kosowskis perfect poster for Kubricks Lolita, the cheerfully cute drawings of Chris Haughton for the Royal London Children`s Hospital, the super busy &amp;ldquo;Larger Than line&amp;rdquo; by Mattias Adolfsson, the powerful and colorful &amp;ldquo;Alice in Wonderland&amp;rdquo; art by Grahame Baker-Smith, or the iconic &amp;ldquo;Autism&amp;rdquo; work by Aad Goudappel (one copy of which I acquired for our private collection).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affordable Art Fair in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/affordable-art-fair-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 16:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/affordable-art-fair-in-london/</guid>
      <description>October 25 we were invited to attend the Affordable Art Fair in Battersea (London), where 110 galleries showcased work by 1,100 artists.
There is always something interesting, and it is always a pleasure to attend art shows, but art in NY tends to be more daring and exciting. Sometime I miss living in Manhattan.
In any case, here you have a few pictures of works that caught my eye for one reason or another:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dinner at Le Meridien Piccadilly</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/dinner-at-le-meridien-piccadilly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 22:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/dinner-at-le-meridien-piccadilly/</guid>
      <description>After the visit to the British Museum &amp;amp; Fortnum &amp;amp; Mason, my in-laws treated us to dinner at The Terrace Grill restaurant at Le Meridien Piccadilly Hotel.
As was to be expected, it was delicious. A great way to end a great day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>British Museum and Fortnum &amp; Mason</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/british-museum-and-fortnum-mason/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 22:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/british-museum-and-fortnum-mason/</guid>
      <description>It is quite a privilege to be able to take your son to the British Museum every week for his homeschooling history class. And that’s what we did Friday October 9, but this time I also took my wife and the in-laws.
Visiting a museum on a regular basis allows for much deeper analysis and engagement, gaining on the depth the exhibits have and most tourist don’t have the time to enjoy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Gallery</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/national-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 22:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/national-gallery/</guid>
      <description>It had been quite a long time since I was last at the National Gallery, but Tuesday October 6 I took my family there. While my in-laws were visiting, for my home-schooled son was Art class time. I enjoyed tremendously discussing with him the differences between early and late Renaissance visual art.
Even if was only for the proximity to some of the world’s best museums, living in London is great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sky Garden in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/sky-garden-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 22:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/sky-garden-in-london/</guid>
      <description>Monday October 5 I took my family to the Sky Garden, at 20 Fenchurch St., London. It’s the UK’s highest public garden, and it’s free to visit although an online reservation is required.
Honestly, I wonder how come it took me so long to check it out. It’s awesome!
Despite the hordes of visitors, it does not feel overly crowded, offering different levels and spaces from where to admire the amazing view of London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another weekend in Oxford</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/another-weekend-in-oxford/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 22:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/another-weekend-in-oxford/</guid>
      <description>I can not have enough of Oxford. Being there is like being in another world: a timeless, self-contained, engrossing, and intellectual stimulating one. And you don’t even need to be a student or to attend a lecture to feel it. On Sunday October 4 I visited with my wife, my son and my parents-in-law.
I took them to the college I attended and others, enjoying their architecture and gardens, marveling at the incredible amount of cultural events (mainly concerts and lectures, not so much art, though) going on for such a small town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London City Hall meetings</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/london-city-hall-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 22:01:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/london-city-hall-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday September 29 I had a couple meetings in London’s City Hall and the London and Partners office, to prepare for the BioJapan mission and to learn more about apprenticeship program in the UK. The views were quite nice, specially at sunset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to a Christie’s Art Auction</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/invited-to-a-christies-art-auction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 13:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/invited-to-a-christies-art-auction/</guid>
      <description>This summer London became the setting for more than 20 giant sculptures inspired by the DNA double helix by some of the biggest names in the world of art and design, including Ai Weiwei, Aston Martin, or Zaha Hadid. Last Wednesday my wife and I were invited to the auction of those pieces at legendary art auction house Christie’s.
I was surprised, or rather “appalled”, to see that Ai Weiwei’s sculptures went for only around £20,000 each (he made two).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imperial War Museum London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/imperial-war-museum-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 13:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/imperial-war-museum-london/</guid>
      <description>Last week I visited the Imperial War Museum of London with my father-in-law and my son.
I am a pacifist, and I believe the military-industrial complex is a very scary and abominable reality. So anything related to military makes me cringe. But I must admit I was pleasantly surprised by this museum. It did not glorify the military, nor it played the over-sensitive card of victim’s suffering. It was detached enough to be “objective”, while human enough to transmit the horrors of war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast in London, lunch in Reykjavík and dinner in Boston</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/breakfast-in-london-lunch-in-reykjav%C3%ADk-and-dinner-in-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 10:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/breakfast-in-london-lunch-in-reykjav%C3%ADk-and-dinner-in-boston/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crazy couple of days: meeting Google Ventures, NHS, Accenture, interview, events…</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/crazy-couple-of-days-meeting-google-ventures-nhs-accenture-interview-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 09:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/crazy-couple-of-days-meeting-google-ventures-nhs-accenture-interview-events/</guid>
      <description>Everybody is too busy. It’s the “toxic work world” we live in, accordingto the New York Times. But some days are more ridiculously packed than others.
Last week I had so many meetings, it was hard for me to keep track of them. Some that I remember off the top of my head: meeting with a General Partner of Google Ventures, meeting two executives from the National Health Service (NHS), an executive from Accenture at their posh London offices, being interviewed by an Editor from The Times, being picked up by a driver in a hybrid car with wifi who took me to a media event (Haymarket Group’s Create 2015) to present and participate in a panel along two other accomplished “entrepreneurs” from TechHub, and minutes later participating at another event (Connected Health) at Simmons &amp;amp; Simmons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing in London… even with Microsoft!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/playing-in-london-even-with-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 09:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/playing-in-london-even-with-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>These past few days have been quite “playful”.
On the one hand, I have just discovered, right around the corner from our apartment by London Bridge, a free and public playground that has an artificial grass hockey field, half a basketball court, 3 pingpong tables and even a beach volleyball court with sand and all! So obviously, the next day I went with my son to a sports equipment store and bought a soccer ball, a pingpong set, a basketball, a volleyball and a badminton set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royal Society of Medicine 11th Medical Innovations Summit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/royal-society-of-medicine-11th-medical-innovations-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 14:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/royal-society-of-medicine-11th-medical-innovations-summit/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I attended the 11th Medical Innovations Summitheld at the Royal Society of Medicine.
Like everyone else, I usually attend these events because there is a chance you may get to actually listen to an interesting presenter, or learn about a true innovation. But I usually leave disappointed due to a number of reasons like too much hype and lack of substance, bad organisation, “innovations” that are not really innovations, or bad presenters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20/21 British Art Fair</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/20/21-british-art-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 13:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/20/21-british-art-fair/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I attended the 20/21 British Art Fairat the Royal College of Art, in London.
Usually I love art fairs, and find many exciting works of art. I particularly love the creative energy you can feel at contemporary art fairs.
This one was not an exciting fair. Perhaps because it is modern and contemporary, perhaps because it is limited to British artists, or perhaps because this year’s selection was not that interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horse riding vacation in the English countryside: Four Seasons Hampshire</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/horse-riding-vacation-in-the-english-countryside-four-seasons-hampshire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 09:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/horse-riding-vacation-in-the-english-countryside-four-seasons-hampshire/</guid>
      <description>Last month we took the kids to an idyllic English countryside retreat: the Four Seasons Hampshire, where we stayed in two adjacent suites.
Not far from London, it has everything a kid can dream of for a wonderful countryside vacation: green hills, a fishing pond, clay pigeon shooting, indoors heated swimming pool, bicycles, a large collection of DVDs, library, a playground, a rope-adventure course, a crocket lawn, tennis courts, a kids playroom with videogames, foosball, pool table… even a resident black labrador dog called Oliver!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A fun summer with the kiddos: Legoland, Parks, Museums, Zoo, Bowling, and Gardens</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/a-fun-summer-with-the-kiddos-legoland-parks-museums-zoo-bowling-and-gardens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 06:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/a-fun-summer-with-the-kiddos-legoland-parks-museums-zoo-bowling-and-gardens/</guid>
      <description>This summer we have enjoyed London and its surrounding areas as tourists with the kids.
Due to the personal nature of this post, I will keep it brief and pictures, as usual in this blog for privacy reasons, will not show my kids.
Places we went to:
Although some years ago we went to Legoland Billund, we wanted to check this one out. As expected, it was a lot of fun (especially if you are a Lego fan… and who isn’t?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool work meetings this summer in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/cool-work-meetings-this-summer-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 15:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/cool-work-meetings-this-summer-in-london/</guid>
      <description>This summer I have had several work meetings around London. Some of the most interesting, cool and fun:
 At London Blackfriars Railway Station NHS Test Beds 2nd round event at the Kia Oval… with a live cricket match going on! (it was somehow distracting, if only because I don not understand this game) Handing out student awards at PwC At London BioScience Innovation Centre At Google  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My latest art acquisitions: a Hokusai and a Cel-ga</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/my-latest-art-acquisitions-a-hokusai-and-a-cel-ga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 08:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/my-latest-art-acquisitions-a-hokusai-and-a-cel-ga/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I acquired two very different works of Japanese fine art.
One was a very rare and wonderful find: an original Ukiyo-e woodblock print by Katsushika Hokusai (1760-1849), whose &amp;ldquo;Great Wave off Kanagawa&amp;rdquo; is one of the best-known works of Japanese art, titled “Wavy shadow of Mount Fuji” from the “One Hundred Views of Mount Fuji, Vol. 2” Series, created in 1835. The “One Hundred Views of Mount Fuji” series was featured by the British Museum in 2001and is part of the MET Museum collectionin New York.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enjoying the HyperJapan festival in London`s O2</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/enjoying-the-hyperjapan-festival-in-londons-o2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 17:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/enjoying-the-hyperjapan-festival-in-londons-o2/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who knows me knows I am crazy about all things Japanese; so since it has been so long that I have been in Japan, I decided to attend the HyperJapanevent taking place in London`s O2 arena.
It was a blast! Many booths with Japanese merchandise, videogames (with a huge Nintendo area), clothing (like Aoior the supercool t-shirts of Askew Gaming), manga artists, publishers (like Kaori, or Kodansha), bookstores (like JP Books), jewelry (like LittleMooseor Jane Nevermore), designers (like Ayako Shirata), art galleries (like CelGaor The Japanese Gallery), tourism info and institutions (like Japan Foundation), Japanese schools (like Alpha), steampunk (like Mikie &amp;amp; Co.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the TechHubIs5 Party in Shoreditch</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/invited-to-the-techhubis5-party-in-shoreditch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 16:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/invited-to-the-techhubis5-party-in-shoreditch/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday we (Carlos and Victoria from Kanteron, my wife and I) were invited, since we are members, to the TechHub 5th birthday party at an abandoned textile warehouse in London.
The party was expertly organized by the TechHub crew, and had everything you need to ensure a great party: two DJs, karaoke, photo-booth, grilled cheese sandwiches, ice-cream, cupcakes, booze, and cool tech (this time it was the HP Sprout).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at MedTech London July 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/speaking-at-medtech-london-july-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 18:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/speaking-at-medtech-london-july-7/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday July 7th I was also invited, this time by Prof Tony Young (National Clinical Director for Innovation NHS England), to speak at the MedTech eventheld at University College London Partners.
The other three speakers also talked about different aspects of MedTech:
 Jim Dawton, Director Great Fridays “Disrupting Healthcare through Design” Henrietta Hughes, Regional Medical Director, NHS England ‘Innovation From the Frontline of Primary Care` Prof. Jo Martin, National Clinical Director for Pathology, ‘eCPD and More’  It was also another great event for networking, with over 100 people there, all related to MedTech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Kings College London July 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/speaking-at-kings-college-london-july-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 17:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/speaking-at-kings-college-london-july-7/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday July 7th, I was invited to participate in a round table at the &amp;ldquo;Annual Networking Conference on Healthcare Efficiency through Technology: BIG DATA and Clinical Genomics&amp;rdquo; event.
It was a pleasure and an honor to share the stage and discuss the state of Clinical Genomics with speakers as distinguished as Prof. Tim Hubbard, Head of Bioinformatics (Genomics England); Dr Johnny Marshall, Director of Policy (NHS Confederation); or my friend Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Next Event: NY vs London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/google-next-event-ny-vs-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 14:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/google-next-event-ny-vs-london/</guid>
      <description>On June 23 I was invited to attend the Google Next Event, as a customer of Google and a potential partner.
It was quite a shock comparing the overall tone and spirit to the same event in New York, last year.
In New York everything was oriented toward networking, and you had the feeling that anyone could be anyone, and it didn`t matter if they represented a large company or a &amp;ldquo;start-up wannabe&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetings and walks around London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/meetings-and-walks-around-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 14:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/meetings-and-walks-around-london/</guid>
      <description>These past days Ive had quite a few meetings and events around London at several lawyers (or _solicitors_, like theyre called here), and tax and investment advisers` offices.
Those meetings are important for the future of my company, and I did learn quite a few things, while they help me select the &amp;ldquo;super-star team&amp;rdquo; that will allow me to take my company to the next level.
But I have also enjoyed running around London, from meeting to meeting, while keeping my eyes (and camera) up in &amp;ldquo;tourist mode&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the London Technology Week launch at The Shard</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/invited-to-the-london-technology-week-launch-at-the-shard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 10:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/invited-to-the-london-technology-week-launch-at-the-shard/</guid>
      <description>This morning I was invited to the launch of London Technology Week, which was held at The Shard.
Besides your typical mix of VIPs, politicians, and media, the most outstanding thing was the view 😉
You can read the details of the press release here.
PS.- Some constructive criticism:
 In an event like this &amp;ldquo;Technology&amp;hellip; whatever&amp;rdquo; you need a hashtag (something like #LTW15) A Technology Week is full of events, how about a MAP, CALENDAR, or an APP to show them all, and to sign up?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London AFF Art Show</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/london-aff-art-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 17:32:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/london-aff-art-show/</guid>
      <description>Today we went to the Affordable Art Fair Hampstead. With over 100 galleries, it was a real pleasure. We saw some artists that we like and have seen in quite a few shows before, and discovered many new ones that were quite interesting.
In no particular order, my non-comprehensive list would include many artists, like:
 Adele Moreau Max Naylor Edvardas Racevicius Andy Wilx, etc  And the whole selection of Galleries like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hampstead Heath</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/hampstead-heath/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 17:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/hampstead-heath/</guid>
      <description>Today, on our way to the AFF show we strolled around Hampstead Heath, one of the many lovely areas with a park, pond (with baby swans!), and flowers around London. It was truly beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London New Tech meeting</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/london-new-tech-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 16:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/london-new-tech-meeting/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday, June 11 I attended the London New Tech Meeting at Google Campus.
It was a typical presentation format (5 companies, 5 minutes). I enjoyed some of the presentations, specially since two of the projects sounded very very promising. Unfortunately they were not even MVP with a landing page. I hope they make it so we can all benefit from their cool ideas.
Since it was a nice day, on my way back home I noticed how the typical beer-drinking crowd had multiplied by hundreds, and they were all drinking and being cheerly loud out on the streets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out and about in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/out-and-about-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 16:36:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/out-and-about-in-london/</guid>
      <description>My parents came to visit from Paris, so we spent a week as “tourist guides”, which is very nice because you discover or re-discover parts of the city that you do not normally go to.
With them we went to
 Old Spitafields Market (lovely London Tea Exchange) Brick Lane Guildhall Covent Garden Market Museum of the Docklands Southwark Cathedral St. Paul`s Cathedral Royal Courts of Justice Tate Modern Parliament Buckingham Palace Walk along the Thames South Bank   And ate at:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art walk</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/art-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 18:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/art-walk/</guid>
      <description>Today I went on an &amp;ldquo;art walk&amp;rdquo;. Since the first Thursday of each month many art galleries in London remain open until late and host special events (an awesome initiative). Unfortunately I left quite late from the office, but I was working on a very special deal, so I could not leave earlier.
First I visited Boxpark Shoreditch.
 &amp;ldquo;Situated in the heart of east London’s fashion and art district, two floors of sixty shipping containers began as the world’s first pop up mall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCL MechEng Party</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/ucl-mecheng-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 15:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/ucl-mecheng-party/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Mykal invited me to the University College London’s Mechanical Engineering Summer Session at Student Central.
It was a blast. A geek blast. Many featured projects, such as giant drone, hydrogen racing car prototype, alternative transportation infrastructure, robotic fish, or improved artificial heart valve design, along with entertainment: giant Scalextric racing, giant jinga, FIFA 15 tournament, impact simulators, pool, and a live concert by Cable Street Collective.
[Note: Congratulations on launching the UK’s first fully Open Access university press!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attending the presentation of a new videogame as investment opportunity</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/attending-the-presentation-of-a-new-videogame-as-investment-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 20:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/attending-the-presentation-of-a-new-videogame-as-investment-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>On Monday I attended the presentation of Project M, a new video-game as investment opportunity, in Google Campus, London.

First of all, let me congratulate the savvy business and marketing team behind it. They put together a well though-out package, their idea is unique and very interesting: a videogame that will reward players by sending them real gold + investors buying &amp;ldquo;mines&amp;rdquo; in the game and participating in the profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to participate in a round table about Healthcare Technology at King`s College</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/invited-to-participate-in-a-round-table-about-healthcare-technology-at-kings-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 18:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/invited-to-participate-in-a-round-table-about-healthcare-technology-at-kings-college/</guid>
      <description>I have been invited to participate in a round table about Healthcare Technology Integration at King`s College(London), July 7 at 2:00pm, Great Hall, Strand Campus.
Mark your calendars, and see you there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maltby Street Market</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/maltby-street-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 17:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/maltby-street-market/</guid>
      <description>I admit I am a chicken when it comes to nasty weather (who would have thought after walking for miles in snow-covered New York’s sidewalks!), so this weekend the rain, wind and low temperatures (plus a nasty technological installation) kept me home, away from amazing events I really wanted to attend like the Web We Want Festival, and the HowTheLightGetsIn2015Philosophy and Music Festival. But a man has to eat, so on Saturday I went to the Maltby Street Market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Chamber of Commerce in Great Britain event at London &amp; Partners</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/spanish-chamber-of-commerce-in-great-britain-event-at-london-partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 21:41:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/spanish-chamber-of-commerce-in-great-britain-event-at-london-partners/</guid>
      <description>The event &amp;ldquo;Expand your Network after Setting Up in London&amp;rdquo; organized by the Spanish Chamber of Commerce in Great Britainat the London &amp;amp; Partnersoffice was quite interesting. The venue was ideal: some of the best views in London. As a matter of fact that meeting room is often used as a recording studio.
Networking events are quite useful if they are industry focused, if someone already knows everyone and introduces to those who may have specific synergy (or if everybody has a chance to quickly introduce themselves).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitching at Google Campus London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/pitching-at-google-campus-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 21:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/pitching-at-google-campus-london/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday I introduced my company officially to the Google Campus London community, with a &amp;ldquo;pitch&amp;rdquo;.
It didn`t surprise me to see the relaxed &amp;ldquo;cool startup&amp;rdquo; vibe, or the fact that it was full of entrepreneurs. What surprised me is how much people liked my pitch. I ran out of business cards!
It was interesting to hear what those entrepreneurs are working on: from a Polish working on &amp;ldquo;on-demand concierge services&amp;rdquo;, to a Russian with &amp;ldquo;personality analysis applied to finances&amp;rdquo;, or an Egyptian/Spanish couple working on &amp;ldquo;social-selling fashion&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art, comics, poetry, food and music at Southbank Centre</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/art-comics-poetry-food-and-music-at-southbank-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 03:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/art-comics-poetry-food-and-music-at-southbank-centre/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I went to the Southbank Centrefor a number of reasons:
The Poetry Comics exhibition at the Saison Poetry Library(Royal Festival Hall) – the largest poetry library in the UK.-
Amazing as the library itself is, this exhibition co-curated by Chris McCabe and Chrissy Williams made it even more so. Featuring works by William Blake, Derik Badman, Bill Berkson / Joe Brainard, Kenneth Patchen, Oliver East, Kenneth Loch, Bianca Stone, Paul K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London Global Art Fair 2015</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/london-global-art-fair-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 15:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/london-global-art-fair-2015/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was invited to the London Global Art Fair 2015, which takes place May 21-23 at Olympia, Kensington, London.
With 150 galleries from 40 countries exhibiting works by over 500 artists, aged 25 (Nicole Wong and Vivien Zhang) to 93 (SH Raza) from 63 countries across the globe, in walling that would wrap over 13 times around the Royal Albert Hall, London Global Art Fair is as much a market as it is a celebration of creativity, art and culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture around the corner: the Tate Modern</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/culture-around-the-corner-the-tate-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 15:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/culture-around-the-corner-the-tate-modern/</guid>
      <description>Living in London means being surrounded by culture. For example, in less than 5 minutes’ walk from our apartment, and without even crossing the London Bridge, we have the Tate Modern(Britain`s national gallery of international modern art), Shakespeare’s Globe Theater, Southbank Centre(Europe’s largest centre for the arts: theatres, concert halls and a cutting edge art gallery presenting over 1200 events each year), and BFI Southbank(the leading repertory cinema in the UK, specialising in classic, independent and non-English language films, operated by the British Film Institute).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working at Google Campus London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/working-at-google-campus-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 11:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/working-at-google-campus-london/</guid>
      <description>I have been working at the Google-TechHub Campus in Shoreditch (the “Silicon Roundabout”) London for a few weeks. It is really cool. In no particular order, here are some things I love about this place:
 A cafeteria (open to anyone) with terrace, foosball table, bitcoin machine, device bar (to test your developments in many different devices) and even a spacesuit! A small but well stocked library of tech books Very nice team, from security to reception, to admin, to social media… all of them Two levels of office space, one of them (supposedly) “quiet zone” Unlimited supplies of toast and tea, great wifi, and good scanners/printers A ton of areas to sit down and have a meeting, not just the “meeting rooms” Most importantly: the events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First days living in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/first-days-living-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 12:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/first-days-living-in-london/</guid>
      <description>We have been in London for a few days already.
Moving to a new country is not such an impossible task as some people imagine, but it is definitely quite a challenge.
The first thing you have to do is to forget comparisons. No place is perfect, and no place is completely awful. But one can’t help but to be stuck by “peculiarities” of the place. Here are some random ones we have been laughing or crying about:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 8</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 12:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-8/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, May 2, was our last day at sea. We got up late, but still on time to have breakfast at the Britannia restaurant. At 10 am we attended a very interesting lecture by Aldon Ferguson on Covert Operations in the Cold War. After yet another time change, we had lunch followed by an unexpected nap.
We graciously avoided the Guest Talent Show, and went to the Library instead, to catch up on some work and return the books we had checked out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 12:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-7/</guid>
      <description>On Friday, May 1, our bodies finally caught up with all the pre-cruise accumulated stress, by sleeping until 1pm, taking into account the time change. So we headed straight to lunch (“would you like some coffee with your steak and kidney pie, dear?”), followed by a very nice walk around the deck.
After the afternoon tea we worked with our laptops in the Library. My wife decided to go back to the room early, so she could get ready for the formal dinner and Masquerade Ball, while sipping rosé champagne.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 6</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 12:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-6/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday, April 30, we made a resolution to get up early (7am is early even if you are not on a Transatlantic crossing!) so we could have breakfast at 8am and join the fencing class at 9am. There is something wonderfully stylish and timeless about fencing in the ballroom of Cunard’s Queen Victoria.
After the fencing class we went back to the stateroom to shower, and then straight to a Galley Tour, where we inspected the cooking areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 5</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 12:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-5/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday, April 29, as the Commodore announced we were right “in the middle of our crossing,” we woke up really late. You realize how late when the steward greets you “good afternoon,” and you go straight to lunch (right after my wife’s immigration procedure). It was surprising, at least to me, that although we were half an hour late for that scheduled process, 80 people were still to show up, most of the from the USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 4</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 11:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-4/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday, April 28, we finally woke up early enough to enjoy a full service breakfast at the Britannia restaurant and attend the morning lecture “Meteors, Meteorites and Comets”, by Howard L.G. Parkin. While the Royal Court Theater was fairly full, by the time his lecture was over, it completely filled out for the next lecture: “Survival in Solitude”, where Terry Waite told us how, while working as negotiator for the Archbishop of Canterbury, he was taken hostage in Beirut and survived for 5 years, 4 of which he spent in solitary confinement, enduring torture and a mock execution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 11:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-3/</guid>
      <description>On Monday, April 27, we woke up quite late again, so we had breakfast at the Lido restaurant, and went straight to the Royal Court Theater to listen to the lecture by Howard L. G. Parkin “The Constellations – Myth, Legend And Mystery”, right after which we attender another lecture, this time by Simon Dinsdale, in which he shared some of his experiences as a Royal Family bodyguard.
After a light lunch, we went to the library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 10:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-2/</guid>
      <description>April 26 we woke up quite late, with the wonderful feeling of not having to rush, and enjoyed a nice breakfast buffet at the Lido restaurant.
After breakfast we took a walk around the ship, exploring the different venues, from the card room to the library. It is definitely not a “flashy” ship, with the decor being elegantly subtle and conservative. Perhaps the weakest point, as with so many cruise ships, being the artwork, and the most interesting one being the Cunardia (the first Cunard museum at sea) celebrating 175 years of history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic crossing on the Queen Victoria, Day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 15:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/transatlantic-crossing-on-the-queen-victoria-day-1/</guid>
      <description>April 25, to celebrate my wifes birthday and to move from New York to London in style, we boarded &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.cunard.com/cruise-ships/queen-victoria/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Cunards Queen Victoriafor a trans-Atlantic crossing (not cruising) onboard the luxury ocean liner (V509).
The night before we had a farewell dinner with some friends in New York at White Street restaurant, which was full of movie industry VIPs already invading Manhattan for the Tribeca Film Festival; our friend Jill, who could not attend the dinner, had a very nice gesture sending a bottle of champagne and a card from Washington DC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manic London days in April</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/manic-london-days-in-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 21:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/manic-london-days-in-april/</guid>
      <description>March 31st we went to London with a very defined mission: to find an apartment, get cell phone lines, open bank accounts, and get the office space running. All in two days and a half, because although we did return to Spain on April 3rd, it was a bank holiday.

We had to run all over the city. The amazing thing? WE DID IT! Well, kinda.
The office was easy, since we had already been selected to join the Google Campus in London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last weekend in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/02/last-weekend-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 16:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/02/last-weekend-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>Yes, the rumor is true: my wife and I are moving to London.
Now that Kanteron USA is solidly stablished, and profitable, I must proceed with the expansion plan, and make sure to grow both Asia and EMEA markets, which I plan to do from London.
So, although we are moving April 25th (more on that in another post, since it will be quite a singular &amp;ldquo;adventure&amp;rdquo;), this was our last weekend in New York because this upcoming weekend we will be in Canada, and next Friday we fly to Europe, where we will be visiting Lisbon, Valencia, Rome and London.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>