<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Society and politics on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/society-and-politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Society and politics on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 15:41:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/society-and-politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A meeting in Chile and 5 days in Paraguay</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/04/a-meeting-in-chile-and-5-days-in-paraguay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 15:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/04/a-meeting-in-chile-and-5-days-in-paraguay/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, March 28 I took a nice flight from London to Santiago de Chile. Nice not because the constant turbulence, which made it feel like I was flying in a food mixer with wings, but because laying down completely stretched, I slept almost throughout the entire flight. The fact that the cabin crew were unusually nice also helped.
After a quick meeting in Santiago de Chile, I took another flight, this time to Asuncion (Paraguay), where I stayed until Sunday, April 2nd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambodia</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/03/cambodia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 10:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/03/cambodia/</guid>
      <description>Sunday, March 12, we arrived in Sihanoukville (Cambodia). We were greeted by our driver, “Mr. Temple” and our guide, “Mr. Lucky”.
Mr. Lucky was a sweet guy who told us a great deal about Cambodia’s history, present, and his life. The kind of guide you always hope to get, but seldom do.
Mr. Lucky was the youngest of 4 brothers. His other 3 brothers died during the Khmer Rouge regime. Fortunately he survived (hence his nickname).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding government intrusion in my latest trip to the USA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/avoiding-government-intrusion-in-my-latest-trip-to-the-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 14:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/avoiding-government-intrusion-in-my-latest-trip-to-the-usa/</guid>
      <description>February 18 to 23 I traveled to Orlando, Florida (USA) for the HIMSS trade show. As much as I have enjoyed the magic of Orlando parks in the past, this was a pure business trip. I am an EU citizen (Spain) living in the UK, and I took a direct flight from London to Orlando. I had recently renewed my passport and ESTA, so I should be able to enter the USA without a problem right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very interesting insights from the UBS Forum 2017</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/very-interesting-insights-from-the-ubs-forum-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 16:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/very-interesting-insights-from-the-ubs-forum-2017/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Giles and Magda invited me to attend the annual UBS Forum at the beautiful Rosewood Hotel, one of those hotels in a renovated palace in the heart of London, with a resident dog.
Held in major financial cities across Europe, the UBS Forum is presented under the banner &amp;ldquo;sharper opinions – smarter decisions”, where UBS specialists and external experts provide insights on key topics. This years` speakers and topics were:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two days in Brussels</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/two-days-in-brussels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:02:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/two-days-in-brussels/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, March 31 and Wednesday, February 1 I went to Brussels by train. It is sad to see the permanent heavy military presence around Brussels main train station.
Microsoft had invited me to participate in the ‘Health Digital Transformation at the Microsoft Executive Briefing Center, because my company is a founding member of the ‘AI in Health Partner Alliance (along with Microsoft and 20 other tech companies) which was launched at the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Revolution needs a Revolution</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 17:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went with my wife and son to visit the Victoria &amp;amp; Albert`s Museum exhibition You Say You Want a Revolution? Records and Rebels 1966-1970. The aim of the exhibition was quite clear:
 How have the finished and unfinished revolutions of the late 1960s changed the way we live today and think about the future?
 I was very much looking forward to visiting the exhibition. It is SO timely, and SO needed, I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My EU policy recommendation published: &#34;Hacking Policy. Exploring Innovative Ways to Advance Policy Reform&#34;</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/my-eu-policy-recommendation-published-hacking-policy.-exploring-innovative-ways-to-advance-policy-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 10:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/my-eu-policy-recommendation-published-hacking-policy.-exploring-innovative-ways-to-advance-policy-reform/</guid>
      <description>Under the title &amp;ldquo;Hacking Policy. Exploring Innovative Ways to Advance Policy Reform&amp;rdquo; StartupEurope has published a report listing the Policy Recommendations that came out of the Policy Hackathon in San Francisco, where my team won the competition.
Download it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valencia (Spain) VC flows</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/valencia-spain-vc-flows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 14:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/valencia-spain-vc-flows/</guid>
      <description>Adam Gilfix, Brian de Luna, and Luke Heine, with the help of Dealroom.co, have created a very interesting data visualization tool for Venture Capital (VC) flows.
I know for a fact and from experience that VC activity in places like Silicon Valley, NY, Boston, or London is big. But even when I go back home (Valencia – Spain) for the holidays, there are all kinds of &amp;ldquo;VC&amp;rdquo; events, news, meetings, spaces&amp;hellip; which, given the conservative and provincial nature of the &amp;ldquo;Valencian Investors&amp;rdquo; I have met, surprises me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My artwork “God bless Amurika”, on display at the Ludwig Museum (Cologne), explained</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-artwork-god-bless-amurika-on-display-at-the-ludwig-museum-cologne-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 09:26:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-artwork-god-bless-amurika-on-display-at-the-ludwig-museum-cologne-explained/</guid>
      <description>I have often criticized artists who hide behind “my work speaks for itself” or “it’s up to the viewer to interpret my work”. Nice try, but that’s bullshit.
Of course, anyone can interpret anything when exposed to an artwork! But the artist should at least make an attempt to explain the meaning behind a piece. No matter how self-explanatory (or obscure) it might be. It’s not “restricting the viewer”, it’s guiding; suggesting is not imposing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview for the art exhibition that I have curated and is currently being shown in Kaunas, Lithuania</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/interview-for-the-art-exhibition-that-i-have-curated-and-is-currently-being-shown-in-kaunas-lithuania/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/interview-for-the-art-exhibition-that-i-have-curated-and-is-currently-being-shown-in-kaunas-lithuania/</guid>
      <description>INTERVIEW with JORGE CORTELL, curator
By Airida Rekštytė – November 4, 2016
According to your profound theoretical education (sic) it will not be difficult to present us in short your intentions for organizing this event.
When did the idea of making this exhibition occur and what inspired it?
I have spent years as activist defending free software and online privacy, and opposing censorship.
During a dinner with the director of an event that focuses on those themes (the Internet Freedom Festival, also known as Circumvention Festival), I told him how it would be a nice challenge to try to convey the main messages of the Festivals themes into an art exhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited by the Duque of York to have dinner at Windsor Castle November 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/invited-by-the-duque-of-york-to-have-dinner-at-windsor-castle-november-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 20:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/invited-by-the-duque-of-york-to-have-dinner-at-windsor-castle-november-3/</guid>
      <description>The other day I received a letter from Buckingham Palace, inviting me to have dinner with the Duke of York (Prince Andrew) on Thursday at Windsor Castle.
I was curious to see the castle from the inside: it is a medieval style fortress, filled with military memorabilia (guns, swords, lances, armors…), banners and crests. It was more Game of Thrones than Harry Potter.
The reception was held at the Grand Reception Room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some meetings in London and Paris: from UK`s Secretary of Health to Microsoft`s CEO</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/some-meetings-in-london-and-paris-from-uks-secretary-of-health-to-microsofts-ceo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 16:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/10/some-meetings-in-london-and-paris-from-uks-secretary-of-health-to-microsofts-ceo/</guid>
      <description>The last few days have been quite hectic. So much so that I`m going to &amp;ldquo;bundle&amp;rdquo; them into one or two very heterogeneous posts.
By the end of September I had to attend a few events, like being invited to a member of Microsoft`s Partner Advisory Council (we held the first meeting at the InterContinental London Park Lane Hotel), or an E2E networking dinner at Charlotte Street Hotel:
Tuesday October 4 I travelled to Paris to meet a South American Vice-minister of Health in IBM France:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last day in San Francisco: ART</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/last-day-in-san-francisco-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 22:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/last-day-in-san-francisco-art/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, September 17, was my last day in San Francisco, and the only one I had with some spare time.
After breakfast, I went to but some gifts from Japan Town and then headed to Union Square, for the Korean Day (Chuseok) culture festival.
Then I went to the Yerba Buena Center for the Arts to check out Tom Sachs _Space Program: Europa_. As I feared, after the failure of _Sony Outsider,_ Tom Sachs obsession with demonstrating his hand-made &amp;ldquo;bricolage style&amp;rdquo; continues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco, day 5</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/san-francisco-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 02:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/san-francisco-day-5/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday, September 14 I spent the whole day at K&amp;amp;L Gates, one of the largest law firms in the world, which has customers like Microsoft (the “Gates” in K&amp;amp;L Gates is for Bill Gates’ father), Amazon, etc.
It was a typical upscale law firm setup: expensive video conference equipment and giant screens (I liked their “rear projector and mirror” trick) in a high-rise building with impressive views, and some art, like the “flying dildos” in reception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I won the Anti-Patents Policy Hackathon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/i-won-the-anti-patents-policy-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 02:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/i-won-the-anti-patents-policy-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>On September 13, Mind the Bridge hosted a policy hackathon sponsored by Dell at the MTB Innovation Center in San Francisco. The Dell PolicyHack™ brought together entrepreneurs and U.S./EU policy experts to solve policy challenges. The goal is to productively brainstorm and to provide top-line thinking that can inspire and serve as basis to develop and implement full policies.
My team was formed by:
 Sara R. Klucking (Section Chief, Innovation &amp;amp; Programs, Office of Science and Technology Cooperation, US Department of State) Bogdan Ceobanu (Policy Officer, Startups &amp;amp; Innovation, European Commission) David Hodgson (CEO, Hummingbird Labs) me  The five teams had 75 minutes to come up with a policy solution to issue areas that impact entrepreneurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A week of meetings in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/a-week-of-meetings-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 09:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/a-week-of-meetings-in-london/</guid>
      <description>After the trip to Boston I came down with the flu, of course on a weekend as usual. So Monday I had zero energy, but a week ahead with an usual large number of meetings around London, so I had to do “magic calendar tricks” to be able to make all of them and to also attend several events. The main “trick” is to concentrate meetings geographically, adding into the calendar the time it takes to go from point A to point B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the Amazon Web Services Summit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/invited-to-the-amazon-web-services-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 07:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/invited-to-the-amazon-web-services-summit/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday and Thursday, I was invited to attend the Amazon Web Services Summit in London’s Excel center.
Besides an exhibition area with many vendors (some of them already suppliers to my company) like NewRelic, DataDog, GitHub, Chef, Alscient, Teradici, DataPipe, Ruxit, CloudCheckr, Amazon Activate, Elastic, Redis, etc, all with their great swag (mostly t-shirts and stickers, but lots of giveaways, from drones to iWatches), the highlight was the conference sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to attend the E2Exchange Annual National Reception</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-attend-the-e2exchange-annual-national-reception/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 14:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-attend-the-e2exchange-annual-national-reception/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday, I was invited to attend the E2Exchange Annual National Reception at Banking Hall (London)
It started as a fun networking evening event, where I met all kinds of people, from VCs, to the owner of a large bank, to PR specialists… even a hypnotherapist!
Some politicians, like The Secretary of State for Business, had confirmed their attendance and were scheduled to debate Brexit, but they cancelled at the last minute due to the terrible murder of Jo Cox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest speaker at KPMG UK Health event</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/guest-speaker-at-kpmg-uk-health-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 16:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/guest-speaker-at-kpmg-uk-health-event/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was invited by KPMG UKto be a guest speaker at their Health Get Together event.
It was a pleasure to be invited to participate in their internal event. It gave me an inside look at how consultants work, and I also had a chance to listen to a very interesting internal presentation about their social media use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The White House Chief Data Scientist assures me the White House strongly supports encryption and opposes back doors</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/the-white-house-chief-data-scientist-assures-me-the-white-house-strongly-supports-encryption-and-opposes-back-doors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 13:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/the-white-house-chief-data-scientist-assures-me-the-white-house-strongly-supports-encryption-and-opposes-back-doors/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday March 1 I had a conversation with Dr. DJ Patil, the First White House Chief Data Scientist, at the Venetian Hotel in Las Vegas.
He was interested in discussing ways in which the White House can help healthcare technology companies like mine. The first issue I raised was my concern over the FBI’s request for Apple to decrypt a suspected criminal’s iPhone.
My position in this issue is well known: weak encryption means weak security for ALL of us, so nobody can request weak security for security’s sake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s pretend none of this ever happened</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 10:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</guid>
      <description>Walking towards my London Shoreditch office
to meet the Swiss investor and his impeccable suit,
leaving the City bankers’s coffee-holding fast pace behind,
I notice the absence nobody seems to
Where did he go?
His sleeping sack and pillow still on the sidewalk
as annoyingly positioned in the corner as always
But he’s gone
.
I wonder and I worry
his failing body, almost as absent as his lost gaze</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ai Weiwei at the Royal Academy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/ai-weiwei-at-the-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 13:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/ai-weiwei-at-the-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>On December 4 I was lucky enough to be invited to visit Ai Weiwei`s exhibition at the Royal Academy.
I knew I would enjoy it since Ai Weiwei is one of my favourite artists. I knew even my son, my wife and my mother-in-law would enjoy it, since Ai Weiweis art is highly figurative and symbolic, even to the point of being obvious with his latest works (which makes its appeal that more far-reaching if slightly less elitist).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetings in London (HSBC, Microsoft, solicitors, events...)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/meetings-in-london-hsbc-microsoft-solicitors-events.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 10:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/meetings-in-london-hsbc-microsoft-solicitors-events.../</guid>
      <description>In the past few days I have had quite a few &amp;ldquo;interesting&amp;rdquo; meetings.
On November 26 I was invited to the Pre-Christmas Reception at HSBC corporate offices, along with other business owners/entrepreneurs: a weird mix of industries and interests (which I find a complete waste of business networking time). But one thing was completely homogeneous: wherever you looked, there were men. Middle aged, white, balding, dark suit-wearing men. Just like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I stood up against a terrorist in a German train</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/i-stood-up-against-a-terrorist-in-a-german-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 12:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/i-stood-up-against-a-terrorist-in-a-german-train/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, after spending the day at a tradeshow in Düsseldorf, on my way by train to the hotel in Mülheim, I stopped in the town of Duisburg, which was on my way, because I heard they were setting up a Christmas market. The market was indeed being set up, but it was still closed, so I decided to go back to the station. To avoid the sprinkling rain I took the 901 tram at König-Heinrich Platz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four days in Düsseldorf</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/four-days-in-d%C3%BCsseldorf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 11:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/four-days-in-d%C3%BCsseldorf/</guid>
      <description>From Monday to Thursday I have been in Düsseldorf attending an industry trade show. It has been four largely uneventful days, except for one incident that was particularly disturbing. I will write about it in a separate post.
Lots of walking, trains, meetings, and random thoughts:
 Why does the baker not let me take a picture of one of their St. Martin`s Day &amp;ldquo;Weckmann”? There was a time, years ago, when I could speak some German.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Million masks march</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/million-masks-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 14:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/million-masks-march/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday, coming back home from a meeting, I run into the Million Masks March. While I assume I agree with most of their anti-system protests (the truth is I did not bother to read them), I think their choice of Guy Fawkes as an &amp;ldquo;icon&amp;rdquo;, even if a graphical one as proposed by the comic/movie &amp;ldquo;V for Vendetta&amp;rdquo;, is a very stupid one. Just read about what that historical figure had in mind and judge for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Press Photo 2015</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/world-press-photo-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 13:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/world-press-photo-2015/</guid>
      <description>Last Thursday, on my way to a business meeting, I stopped by the Southbank Center, to view the World Press Photo 2015 exhibition. It was a great collection of pieces, but I particularly liked (or was most shocked by) the work of Tomas van Houtryve (2nd prize stories), Cai Sheng Xiang (1st prize singles), Turi Calafato (3rd prize stories), and Arash Khamooshi (3rd prize stories).
Definitely worthwhile visiting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Oxford Alumni Weekend lectures</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/four-oxford-alumni-weekend-lectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 10:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/four-oxford-alumni-weekend-lectures/</guid>
      <description>[More pictures here]
Last Saturday I had the pleasure to attend Oxford’s Alumni Weekend with my son.
I knew he would not be the only teenager there, but I was surprised to see kids even younger than him accompanying their parents. The truth is that I wish I had brought him earlier. I’ll try to bring my daughter to the next one.
Besides the obvious networking opportunity, the true pleasure was to attend interesting lectures delivered by top academics, and to see my son actually interested in those lectures!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royal Society of Medicine 11th Medical Innovations Summit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/royal-society-of-medicine-11th-medical-innovations-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 14:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/royal-society-of-medicine-11th-medical-innovations-summit/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I attended the 11th Medical Innovations Summitheld at the Royal Society of Medicine.
Like everyone else, I usually attend these events because there is a chance you may get to actually listen to an interesting presenter, or learn about a true innovation. But I usually leave disappointed due to a number of reasons like too much hype and lack of substance, bad organisation, “innovations” that are not really innovations, or bad presenters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the London Technology Week launch at The Shard</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/invited-to-the-london-technology-week-launch-at-the-shard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 10:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/invited-to-the-london-technology-week-launch-at-the-shard/</guid>
      <description>This morning I was invited to the launch of London Technology Week, which was held at The Shard.
Besides your typical mix of VIPs, politicians, and media, the most outstanding thing was the view 😉
You can read the details of the press release here.
PS.- Some constructive criticism:
 In an event like this &amp;ldquo;Technology&amp;hellip; whatever&amp;rdquo; you need a hashtag (something like #LTW15) A Technology Week is full of events, how about a MAP, CALENDAR, or an APP to show them all, and to sign up?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Chamber of Commerce in Great Britain event at London &amp; Partners</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/spanish-chamber-of-commerce-in-great-britain-event-at-london-partners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 21:41:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/spanish-chamber-of-commerce-in-great-britain-event-at-london-partners/</guid>
      <description>The event &amp;ldquo;Expand your Network after Setting Up in London&amp;rdquo; organized by the Spanish Chamber of Commerce in Great Britainat the London &amp;amp; Partnersoffice was quite interesting. The venue was ideal: some of the best views in London. As a matter of fact that meeting room is often used as a recording studio.
Networking events are quite useful if they are industry focused, if someone already knows everyone and introduces to those who may have specific synergy (or if everybody has a chance to quickly introduce themselves).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My talk at the Circumvention Tech Festival, March 4th</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/my-talk-at-the-circumvention-tech-festival-march-4th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 23:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/my-talk-at-the-circumvention-tech-festival-march-4th/</guid>
      <description>This past winter I met Sandy and James from Open ITP in New York, and Pepe from Valencia. They were organizing the Circumvention Tech Festivalto be held in Las Naves, Valencia (Spain) March 1-6.
They invited me to give a talk, which was eventually scheduled for March 4th at 3pm. I titled the talk “When privacy does not mean the same to you and me”. It was meant to generate debate, to expose other people’s points of view, rather than to be a unidirectional speech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTO: a hyper-reading project</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/hto-a-hyper-reading-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 17:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/hto-a-hyper-reading-project/</guid>
      <description>Iban M. G. and Ben Martin have launched a writing project that breaks the boundaries of typical book in paper/digital format. Over the years I have seen many attempts to push the publishing world further. All commendable and appreciated. But so far I have not seen any project as ambitious as HTO.
Note: Literary review aside. I have not read the novel yet and, as a matter of fact, that`s irrelevant for the purposes of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Circumvention Tech Festival</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/the-circumvention-tech-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 15:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/the-circumvention-tech-festival/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Several days in Mexico</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/several-days-in-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 16:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/several-days-in-mexico/</guid>
      <description>After such a nice weekend, I returned to my usual travel pace. This time the first stop was Mexico.
My friends, in addition to distributors, &amp;ldquo;the Germinales&amp;rdquo; (three generations with the same name), treated me extremely well, inviting me to great restaurants, and taking care of everything from transportation to bills. It is a pleasure doing business with them because they understand the human aspect which we often tend to forget, including myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spain – U.S. Chamber of Commerce Reception</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/spain-u.s.-chamber-of-commerce-reception/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 21:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/spain-u.s.-chamber-of-commerce-reception/</guid>
      <description>Last Wednesday I was invited to attend a reception honoring the new Chairman of the Spain – U.S. Chamber of Commerce, retired Ambassador Alan D. Solomon, at Hunton &amp;amp; Williams.
Located at 200 Park Avenue, NY – Met Life building, floor 52 (if I remember correctly) the views were outstanding.
It was definitely a “business attire” reception, with everyone wearing a suit, and only a couple of us “daring” not to wear a tie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singapore wacky laws</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/singapore-wacky-laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 05:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/singapore-wacky-laws/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acquiring a work of art from the Guggenheim Museum in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/acquiring-a-work-of-art-from-the-guggenheim-museum-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 20:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/acquiring-a-work-of-art-from-the-guggenheim-museum-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>August 30th my wife and I acquired another work of art for our collection.
In this case we chose Colombian contemporary artist Carlos Motta: &amp;ldquo;Brief history of US Interventions in Latin America since 1946, 2005/14&amp;rdquo; (Guggenheim UBS MAP Purchase Fund 2014.39).
It is part of a series produced by Carlos Motta between 2005 and 2009 that present two chronologies of events in Latin America: one of U.S. interventions in the region since 1946, and one of the areas leftist guerrilla movements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canceling a trip to India due to bureaucracy... I`m going to Tokyo</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/canceling-a-trip-to-india-due-to-bureaucracy...-im-going-to-tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 19:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/canceling-a-trip-to-india-due-to-bureaucracy...-im-going-to-tokyo/</guid>
      <description>The absurdly convoluted visa policies of India, and the absurdly privatized process of obtaining it, have made me cancel a trip that was supposed to be a routine work day in Kalkata. Its amazing that in the XXI century bureaucracy affects so many countries so much, and toy with peoples lives via ridiculous laws.
The official information handled by my travel agency, one of the largest in the world, says that if I spend less than 24 hours in India I do not need visa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innomedyx, one of the companies I co-founded, establishes the Clinical Innovation Center at the Polytechnic University of Valencia</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/07/innomedyx-one-of-the-companies-i-co-founded-establishes-the-clinical-innovation-center-at-the-polytechnic-university-of-valencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 09:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/07/innomedyx-one-of-the-companies-i-co-founded-establishes-the-clinical-innovation-center-at-the-polytechnic-university-of-valencia/</guid>
      <description>Innomedyx(Twitter, LinkedIn, FaceBook), a company I`m a co-founder of, has established the Clinical Innovation Center at the Polytechnic University of Valencia(Spain), the best BioTechnology University in Spain according to Spanish newspaper El Mundo.photo © UPVThe Dean of the Polytechnic University of Valencia (UPV), Francisco Mora, and the general director of Innomedyx Knowledge in Action, Rosa Valenzuela, signed a partnership agreement that formalizes the chair of Clinical Innovation company on July 1st.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From VIP breakfast to party to another party... in a day</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/from-vip-breakfast-to-party-to-another-party...-in-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 20:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/from-vip-breakfast-to-party-to-another-party...-in-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday was a long day.
First I was invited to a VIP breakfast executive briefing and presentation by IBM at 7:45am. The event, in which IBM showcased their Watson technology and three partner companies talked about how they are leveraging NLP capabilities, lasted until 12:30pm, but I stayed for an extra hour for a meeting with an IBM executive.
Then I headed back to the office for 3 conference calls. By 7:00pm I was ready to go to the Social Radar startup launch party Stephanie and I had been invited to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the IBM Federal Summit, Washington DC</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/at-the-ibm-federal-summit-washington-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 13:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/at-the-ibm-federal-summit-washington-dc/</guid>
      <description>Last Wednesday I participated in IBM’s Federal Summit at the Ronald Reagan Federal Building in Washington DC.
Business aside, it was one scary meeting. There were control systems all over. From the IRS to airports, to National Security, the demos were much more advanced and comprehensive than anything you may have seen in a movie. Big Brother to the Nth degree. They know it all about you. In a second. You either get paranoid-serious about security, encryption and privacy, or you might as well forget completely about your privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reset the net</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to a gala reception aboard the four-masted tall ship Juan Sebastian de Elcano</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-to-a-gala-reception-aboard-the-four-masted-tall-ship-juan-sebastian-de-elcano/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 21:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-to-a-gala-reception-aboard-the-four-masted-tall-ship-juan-sebastian-de-elcano/</guid>
      <description>The Spanish Consul General in New York, Juan Ramón Martínez Salazar, and the Commander of the Training Ship Juan Sebastián de Elcanoinvited my wife and I to a gala reception aboard the beautiful sail ship (the third largest four-masted tall ship in the world, built in 1927), which is currently docked in New York`s pier 88.
It turned out to be a spectacular evening. The vessel was filled with celebrities: military, politicians with their secret service bodyguards, diplomats, sports, business and entertainment people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to Downtown modern&#43;contemporary art fair</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-to-downtown-modern-contemporary-art-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 20:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-to-downtown-modern-contemporary-art-fair/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I was invited along with my wife by New York art gallery Lyons Wier Galleryto the Downtown modern+contemporary art fairheld at the 69th Regiment Armory in New York.
14,000 international collectors and art enthusiasts, over the course of four-days, gathering to discover paintings, sculptures, photographs and mixed-media works by over 600 artists from around the globe, exhibited by more than 50 international dealers. Seasoned as well as new collectors, curators, museum professionals, cultural foundations, dealers, art advisors and consultants enjoying works by mid-career and emerging artists as well as blue chip works by Picasso, De Kooning, Ruscha, Wesselmann, Rauschenberg, Warhol, Calder and other artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking at the CUNY President`s office</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/networking-at-the-cuny-presidents-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 19:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/networking-at-the-cuny-presidents-office/</guid>
      <description>On May 6th, having just returned from quick trips to Cleveland and Atlanta, I attended with my wife the round table debate &amp;ldquo;Curiosity, Understanding, and Utility: Science and the Creative Economy&amp;rdquo; held at the City University of New York Graduate Center`s Proshansky Auditorium.
William Bialek, director of the Graduate Center`s Initiative for the Theoretical Sciences, moderated a discussion with Jennifer Tour Chayes, distinguished scientist and managing director of Microsoft Research New England and Microsoft Research New York City; Fernando Pereira, research at Google; and Chris Wiggins, chief data scientist at the New York Times and faculty member in the Department of Applied Mathematics and Applied Physics at Columbia University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When &amp;quot;progressive media&amp;quot; is ultra conservative</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/when-quotprogressive-mediaquot-is-ultra-conservative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 17:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/when-quotprogressive-mediaquot-is-ultra-conservative/</guid>
      <description>Last Tuesday, October 1, I attended a panel at the City University of New York Graduate Center, titled &amp;ldquo;Into Left Field: Progressive Media in the Age of Austerity&amp;rdquo;.
The Graduate Center’s Peter Beinart (@PeterBeinart), senior political writer for the Daily Beast, discussed the health of progressive media with Katha Pollitt (@KathaPollitt), longtime columnist for The Nation; Joy-Ann Reid (@TheReidReport), managing editor of NBC’s TheGrio.com; and Nermeen Shaikh (@nermeendn), co-host of Democracy Now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the love of basketball</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/for-the-love-of-basketball/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 17:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/for-the-love-of-basketball/</guid>
      <description>I have decided to join the Chelsea Recreation Center.
It`s right around the corner from our apartment, and for $150/year it has everything I need:
But mainly
Two days ago I went in for the first time.
I checked out a basketball from the office (the best basketball I have played with in my long career), and went straight to the court.
There were around a dozen kids (18 year olds, high school seniors) playing around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate cowardice, political hypocrisy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/corporate-cowardice-political-hypocrisy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 15:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/corporate-cowardice-political-hypocrisy/</guid>
      <description>On July 25 I was asked by someone at IBM to write an article about the use of the cloud in healthcare:
 I’d like to offer you the opportunity to author an article which we would look to promote across all of our social properties, other external communications as well as our paid media sponsorships, i.e. blogs.
 I was given suggestions on article length, topic, and keywords, but freedom to write whatever I wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The key to the use of cloud in healthcare</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/the-key-to-the-use-of-cloud-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 12:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/the-key-to-the-use-of-cloud-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>In a single word: security.
By now there is no doubt about the advantages of the cloud: easy collaboration, scalability, ubiquity, sync, cost savings (21% on average, according to AFCOM 2011, 40% according to our own customers), rapid deployment, etc.
There is also no doubt about the need for a move to the cloud in healthcare: according to Enterprise Strategy Group, by 2015 an average of 665TB of data will be generated per hospital per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police state: TXT with police alert in TX</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/police-state-txt-with-police-alert-in-tx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 14:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/police-state-txt-with-police-alert-in-tx/</guid>
      <description>While in Fort Worth, TX, I received the following TXT:
 They who can give up essential liberty to obtain a little temporary safety, deserve neither liberty nor safety.
 Benjamin Franklin, 1775</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to abide to the law while rejecting threats</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/how-to-abide-to-the-law-while-rejecting-threats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 14:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/how-to-abide-to-the-law-while-rejecting-threats/</guid>
      <description>According to Spanish law
web(emphasis mine):
 Information intermediary suppliers:
    Do not have an obligation to supervise the contents they host, transmit, or classify in a link directory, but must collaborate with public authorities when required to interrupt an IT service or take a content down.
    They are not, in principle, responsible for alien content they host, transmit, or give access to, but could incur in responsibility if they take an active participation in its ellaboration or, if knowing of a particular material being being illegal, do not act swiftly to take it down or prevent access to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am being sued by a troll</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-being-sued-by-a-troll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 10:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-being-sued-by-a-troll/</guid>
      <description>A few hours after the first email, I received this second one with a threat (again, translated by me; here is the original):
 Mr. Cortell:
I can prove my identity and the defamatory content of the indicated page, as I said it has been notarized. I can also prove that this site is currently the subject of proceedings in the Courts of Barcelona, in which the prosecution has already ruled, appreciating criminal evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am requested to take a link down and... Streisand effect!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 01:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</guid>
      <description>Today I received this email (it was in Spanish, I have translated it into English because that is the main language of this blog, and in order to give this issue the international coverage that it deserves – sorry for any translation mistake since I am not a lawyer and he writes like an old-fashioned one trying to sound intimidating; here is the original):
 Mr. Cortell:
Currently I am suing Greg Prévôt in the Courts of Barcelona, author of a defamatory site which infringes upon my honor, whose link appears in which you administer, at the following address:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend in the city, July 11-14</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/weekend-in-the-city-july-11-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 13:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/weekend-in-the-city-july-11-14/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5900883957501185345]
The good weather means more outdoors. In NYC it means more &amp;ldquo;city&amp;rdquo;, but also &amp;ldquo;more things going on in the city&amp;rdquo;.
This weekend we have walked a lot, and seen quite a few interesting things around town (caveat: I am no expert in NY, although Spanish newspaper Expansion interviewed meabout it last week), like:
 A Chinese-Spanish cuisine restaurant (no, I have no desire to try it any time soon; there are many others higher on my list) Yoga in Bryant Park A looooooong line of police cars going by The Orly Genger art installation at Madison Sq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to celebrate 4th of July: defending our rights</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/how-to-celebrate-4th-of-july-defending-our-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 15:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/how-to-celebrate-4th-of-july-defending-our-rights/</guid>
      <description>I started my 4th of July&amp;ldquo;celebrations&amp;rdquo; one day early, by visiting the Declaration of Independence &amp;amp; Bill of Rights, handwritten by Thomas Jefferson, exhibited for the first time together, at the NYPL.
 Then, today (4th of July) I went to a protest to demand the restoration of the Fourth Amendment:
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5896836194188971633]
  “The right of the people to be secure in their persons, houses, papers, and effects, against unreasonable searches and seizures, shall not be violated&amp;hellip;”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoHo surprises</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/soho-surprises/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 15:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/soho-surprises/</guid>
      <description>Lately I have been going to the office more than usual. The FDA inspection, then the PILOT health tech NY day (which was held in the coworking space where my office is), and a few other things have made me walk around SoHo quite a lot these days. Here are a few of the surprises I have encountered in the always colorful neighborhood:  The Pearl River Market store, right next door to my offices entrance, is &amp;quot;SoHos best kept secret&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy of an FDA inspection</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/anatomy-of-an-fda-inspection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 15:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/anatomy-of-an-fda-inspection/</guid>
      <description>On April 25th I attended my first FDA (U.S. Food and Drug Administration) Medical Device Establishment Inspection. Agent (Investigator) Kimberley A. Ricketts called me a couple days before to let me know that as a registered medical device manufacturing company, Kanteron Systems (the company I founded in 2005) had been selected for an Establishment Inspection. It was the &amp;ldquo;Notice of Inspection pursuant to Section 704(a)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetics Act [21 U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And this is how the movie industry chokes itself</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/and-this-is-how-the-movie-industry-chokes-itself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 16:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/and-this-is-how-the-movie-industry-chokes-itself/</guid>
      <description>On May 13th, on my way to a friends apartment, we stumbled upon the set of Ben Stillers new movie right outside the 125th St. subway exit. They were filming in the middle of the street. What struck me the most was that one of the façades of the building had been completely redone (cast, cement, wood, paint&amp;hellip; it looked absolutely real and solid) for the film.
Really? No building façade will do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The System: true injustice</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/the-system-true-injustice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 14:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/the-system-true-injustice/</guid>
      <description>One of the friends having dinner with us yesterdaywas a lawyer that used to be a Public Defender in NY. Of all the many interesting stories she had to tell, one struck me as the perfect example of all that is wrong with The System.
 Once she had to defend a homeless man who was accused of stealing a candy bar from a drugstore. Since he had breached a non-trespass order from a previous similar incident, the prosecutor was asking for a 3 year prison sentence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossing the border for a genetic test</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/04/crossing-the-border-for-a-genetic-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 13:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/04/crossing-the-border-for-a-genetic-test/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, as part of an unusual birthday gift, my fiancé and I signed up to get our genetic test.
So we ordered the test kit online, and when we entered the state (NY), a big warning told us that according to state laws, we could not produce or mail the samples back to their labs from New York. WTF?! OK, whatever. As if a nonsensical law did not have many ways around it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art or war?</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/04/art-or-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 16:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/04/art-or-war/</guid>
      <description>In the TV show Britain`s Got Talent, Hungarian shadow-theatre company Attraction shows with beauty the horror of war.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look at the data, just look at it!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/look-at-the-data-just-look-at-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 14:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/look-at-the-data-just-look-at-it/</guid>
      <description>Carna botnet offers us this amazing 24 hour visualization of relative IPv4 utilization observed using ICMP Ping requests.
Look at the data, just look at it! Dont you see peoples sleeping patterns, internet usage patterns, eating schedule habit, cultural differences, urban influence, regional inequalities&amp;hellip;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two days in Panama</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/two-days-in-panama/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 15:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/two-days-in-panama/</guid>
      <description>Business took me again to Panama on Monday, for a quick trip (two days).
Tin roofed huts with satellite TV next to high rise office buildings, riding on an official (with sirens) tinted window SUV with driver and no license plates, and staying in a nice hotelthat was not extraordinary but had all and everything that I look for in a hotel (except indoors swimming pool). But it belongs to the friend (former Treasury Secretary) of a friend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT day 4</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/mit-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 16:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/mit-day-4/</guid>
      <description>Day 4 started with a corporate presentation (we got to choose, and I attended the one by Pfizer) at 7:30am, in which Pfizer`s Senior Vice President of Research and Development talked about the rapidly shifting way in which big pharma is working, and mentioned an unacceptable fact that should make us all reflect on how much the patent system is broken:
 Pfizer has 98,000 employees&amp;hellip; and 31,000 lawyers!
 The rest of the day I attended classes by Catherine Tucker, Brian Halligan, and a speech by Dean David Schmittlein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/mit-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/mit-day-1/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5838342469980149841]
Today is my first day as a student of &amp;quot;the most important university in the world&amp;rdquo; (according to this article): MIT.
I am here to take the MIT Sloan Executive EducationEDP (Entrepreneurship Development Program).
Getting up at 4 am and braving the fluoutbreakin Boston and the cold weather including a frozen Charles River (not like it is less cold in NY anyway), I arrived from NY this morning in an early flight, and after checking in at the Marriot, I went to a luncheon at the Towne Stove and Spiritsrestaurant sponsored by Ken Morse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed for Zoom News about the Mega case</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/interviewed-for-zoom-news-about-the-mega-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/01/interviewed-for-zoom-news-about-the-mega-case/</guid>
      <description>Interviewedby Aurora Muñoz for Zoom News about the Mega case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Montevideo in December</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/montevideo-in-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 20:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/montevideo-in-december/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5821499441712215169]
December 2nd I flew to Montevideo. I stayed at the Radisson Hotel, Plaza de la Independencia. Very conveniently located with some impressive views from the top floor. Good thing it had a pool, because it is not easy to keep my exercise regime when traveling so much.
Besides very productive meetings with IBM (very nice, professional, and friendly executives, by the way) and presentation to several hospital groups (one of the meetings at the Presidential Building, another one at the country`s largest hospital, and a presentation at the Solis Theater), I enjoyed the promenade by the river which seems like a sea, the old town, and a weird Ice Bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After hurricane Sandy in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 20:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/after-hurricane-sandy-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>From tilted posts to trees completely gone, after hurricane Sandy there were many signs of destruction around New York.
I had to stay at Stepahnie`s apartment (thank you again!) until Monday, because my building remained without power. And even after the power returned, the telephone and internet took two more days.
Some people were not so lucky, with all hotels fully booked, and had to stay at home for days without power or water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20,000 homeless kids in NYC</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/20000-homeless-kids-in-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 02:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/20000-homeless-kids-in-nyc/</guid>
      <description>Number of homeless kids in NYC last year: 16,000
Number of homeless kids in NYC this year: 20,000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>319 Scholes art opening of &amp;quot;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 12:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I went to 319 Scholes to attend the art opening of &amp;ldquo;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;rdquo;.
Beyond the anecdotal post/pre hispter crowd, the exhibition itself is a sad celebration of noise. Which, in itself is as valid, or invalid, as any other starting point in the endless debate about art (more so in regards with contemporary, electronic, net, etc).
But it is its legitimization attempt, with research project, curator, catalogue, and international tour, which brings the debate to a whole different level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Norse vs Inuit approach</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-norse-vs-inuit-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-norse-vs-inuit-approach/</guid>
      <description>The Norse vs Inuit approach
There are many seemingly &amp;ldquo;small events&amp;rdquo; in history to which we do not pay much attention, when actually they provide very important lessons. I always talk about historical examples of perfectly successful cooperatives and anarchist self government. But this time I want to comment on a very different historical event: the Norse attempt to colonize Greenland.
When the Norse tried to colonize Greenland, the Inuit already lived there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The longest war in US history</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-longest-war-in-us-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/the-longest-war-in-us-history/</guid>
      <description>Afghanistan already is the longest (official) war in US history.
In order to begin to understand that mess, as usual in modern history, we may have to go back to the end of World War II, when Pakistan`s colonial nominees, the &amp;ldquo;Taliban&amp;rdquo;, were sent to take over Afghanistan to give them a strategic edge over India in the war over Kashmir.
Today the Taliban and Pakistans ISI (Directorate for Inter-Service Intelligence) alliance are at the heart of why the USA is stuck in an endless war: the USA aligns, or so it would seem, much more with India in terms of values, policy, economy, etc, than with Pakistan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High culture might will numb you, how stay true? On &amp;quot;Graffiti&amp;quot; screening and panel at New Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 15:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I was invited to the New Musuem for the screening of &amp;ldquo;Graffiti – PostGraffiti&amp;rdquo; documentary and panel discussion.Your usual suspects were there. Besides the panelist (Pattie Astor, Fab Five Freddy, Lady Pink, and Lee Quinones), there were many old glories and a couple of aspiring bomber kids in the audience that I am sure were tagging walls late that night.
What started as a celebration, a remembrance, and a comunion, as the liturgy advanced ended up becoming a hurtful vindication and even a flat out purist attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It`s October and all I want is you</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 22:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</guid>
      <description>Lying on the carpet, poetry book and pencil in hand, U2 in the background.
October
 October
And the trees are stripped bare
Of all they wear
What do I care
October
And kingdoms rise
And kingdoms fall
But you go on&amp;hellip;and on&amp;hellip;
 So many literal meanings: the fear of wearing-out (The Edge was considering leaving the band like his brother did before they were even called U2), the false sense of security arising from self-defeat (&amp;ldquo;What do I care&amp;rdquo;), moving on after a loss (both Bono and Larry had just lost their mothers), the high hopes and expectations arising from new democracies in Eastern Europe only to become despair and dissapointment, and eventually resilience, surviving, going on&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for Sugar Man</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/searching-for-sugar-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2012 14:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/searching-for-sugar-man/</guid>
      <description>Last Sunday I went to see Searching for Sugar Manbio/docu/picat Lincoln Plaza Theaters.
 Two South Africans set out to discover what happened to their unlikely musical hero, the mysterious 1970s rock ‘n` roller, Rodriguez.
 While the movieis a very good one, and the story quite powerful (not only a human story about an incredible musiciancalled Rodriguez, better than Bob Dylan if you allow me the heresy), there are two aspects that go well beyond the typical in this kind of documentary:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round table at NYCBA about Campaign Reform</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/round-table-at-nycba-about-campaign-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 13:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/round-table-at-nycba-about-campaign-reform/</guid>
      <description>September 5th (I know, I have really fallen behind my posts; bear with me, there is just too much going on to keep up) I attended a very interesting and enlightening round table at the New York City Bar Associationtitled &amp;ldquo;How Will Recent Developments in the Law Influence the 2012 Elections&amp;rdquo;?
Moderated by Nan Aron (lecturer, author, and President of Alliance for Justice), the panel consisted of:
 Angelo Falcón: President and Founder of the National Institute for Latino Policy Keesha Gaskins: Senior Counsel in the Brennan Center`s Democracy Program Lawrence Lessig: Professor of Law at Harvard University (and much more) John Samples: Director of the Cato Institute Center for Representative Government  The discussion was quite interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft, derivative works, parodies...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 10:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</guid>
      <description>Hugo sends me thisamazing song/video made in Minecraft. Of course, that leads to 10more, 14more&amp;hellip; there are so many!
When you make the tools available to the people, and allow them to create (in this case under the safe harbor of &amp;ldquo;parody&amp;rdquo;) wonderful things happen. Its NOT all about the money, profit, control... Its about imagination, art, creativity, culture. Thats how it happens: copying, re-using, mixing, adjusting, modifying... thats what creativity is really about (or did you think it was about &amp;ldquo;inventing&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;making unheard of things out of thin air&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No unions admitted at the Intrepid Museum, NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/no-unions-admitted-at-the-intrepid-museum-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2012 13:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/no-unions-admitted-at-the-intrepid-museum-ny/</guid>
      <description>New York`s Intrepid Museum, new home of the Space Shuttle Enterprise, does not allow unions. You can see it (point number 13) in their &amp;ldquo;code of conduct&amp;rdquo;. WTF!!??
via Alvaro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/july-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 00:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/july-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>Before I forget more (I am sure I am leaving out a lot), here is a little recap of things I`ve done, tried, or discovered in NY during July:
July 1st I went to Strand, my favorite bookstore, with its cool graffiti outside.
and then went to the &amp;ldquo;Exquisite Corpses: Drawing and Disfiguration&amp;rdquo; Party at the MoMA with Nebula.
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5761705319543704769]
The next day, in SoHo, I took a picture of this robot figure on my way to the gym.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting videos</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/interesting-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 22:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/interesting-videos/</guid>
      <description>Let me share some odd videos I have watched recently, thanks to Leaitrice and Patricia:
The famous &amp;quot;Sunscreen&amp;rdquo; music video(the text comes from an essaywritten in 1997 by Mary Schmich, a columnist at the Chicago Tribune, as a graduation speech for the class of `97) which gives some amazing advice for life. There is even a StarWars Version.
Drunk History: get some history students drunk, have them narrate historical events, while reenacting them&amp;hellip; more fun than it seems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comment on &amp;quot;Debunking Putin`s Newest Myth&amp;quot; by Alexander Yanov</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/comment-on-quotdebunking-putins-newest-mythquot-by-alexander-yanov/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 22:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/comment-on-quotdebunking-putins-newest-mythquot-by-alexander-yanov/</guid>
      <description>After reading &amp;ldquo;Debunking Putin`s Newest Myth&amp;rdquo; by Alexander Yanov, PhD, and with all my respect and admiration for this very well known historian of Russian nationalisms:
Although quite brilliant and eloquent, I believe it is not incisive and daring enough in debunking Putin`s newest myth. It takes a very conservative approach, perhaps letting a Western traditional philosophy baggage and inclination take the part of pure reason and belief, which is usually needed, in equal parts, to fight a political/philosophical quarrel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I beat Watson at Jeopardy (more or less)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 18:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/i-beat-watson-at-jeopardy-more-or-less/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in my previous post, at IBM Innovation Center in Chicago they have a Watson(more info here) interactive kiosk with which to play an interactive game of Jeopardy. In case you have been living in a cave for the past few months, Watson beatJeopardy human champions on live TV, the significanceof which can not be overstated.
Now, remember: this is a &amp;ldquo;small version&amp;rdquo; of Watson, and a &amp;ldquo;self-contained&amp;rdquo; version of Jeopardy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYPL support and citizen budget involvement</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/nypl-support-and-citizen-budget-involvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 12:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/nypl-support-and-citizen-budget-involvement/</guid>
      <description>After supporting the NYPL efforts to fight back budget cuts, I have received a lovely message of thanks from Christine C. Quinn (Speaker, NYC Council), along with a very nice suggestion:
 Dear New Yorker, Many thanks for your email expressing your support for our city`s libraries. [&amp;hellip;]
We cant do it alone, though, and I hope youll consider signing up for Council &amp;ldquo;enews&amp;rdquo;. These issue-based e-mail updates are a great way for us to stay connected and engaged with you and other New Yorkers about the budget, healthcare, and other important issues affecting our city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry Elephants</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/angry-elephants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 21:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/angry-elephants/</guid>
      <description>via APM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real strength</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/real-strength/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 17:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/real-strength/</guid>
      <description>As I head for the shower at the gym, wondering if I should stay longer on the bike, lift more weights, or try a new boxing class, I find the real meaning of strength lying right there in front of me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom of religion, freedom of expression, and public spaces</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/freedom-of-religion-freedom-of-expression-and-public-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 17:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/freedom-of-religion-freedom-of-expression-and-public-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Picture.
Question: why do I have to cross the street on my way home?
Debate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal action against Bankia and Rato</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/legal-action-against-bankia-and-rato/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 17:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/legal-action-against-bankia-and-rato/</guid>
      <description>The citizen platform #15MpaRato is preparing legal action to take Rodrigo Rato to court.
Today they started asking small Bankia stockholders to file an anonymous report, so it can be used in a lawsuit.
Here is their news release [ES]:
https://15mparato.wordpress.com/2012/05/29/accionesparato/
Here is their website:
https://15mparato.wordpress.com/2012/05/29/accionesparato/
Here is their twitter:
@15MpaRato
Hashtag:
#accionpaRato
If you know any Bankia stockholder, ask him/her to contact:
15mparato@gmail.com
Good luck!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journalists covering FB IPO</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/journalists-covering-fb-ipo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 13:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/journalists-covering-fb-ipo/</guid>
      <description>May 18th, on my way to the subway, outside my office.
Look at the pictures. The making of the circus. Draw your own conclusions (and yes, the third one is a journalist on top of a wooden box to make her look taller).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech is a tool, people are stupid</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/tech-is-a-tool-people-are-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 13:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/tech-is-a-tool-people-are-stupid/</guid>
      <description>Technology is getting easier to use everyday. Take GNU/Linux distributions as an example: anyone can make their own. Does that mean everyone should make their own? Why not? But then, again, we end up with things like Ubuntu Satanic(and their Ubuntu SE 666.10 “Necrophiliac Neuromancer”), Hannah Montana Linux(how far would you go to attract kids to free software?), or Red Star OS(free software for North Korea and non-free browsing? WTF?).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts about the 15M</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/thoughts-about-the-15m/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 13:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/thoughts-about-the-15m/</guid>
      <description>May 15th I went to the #15M demosntration in Malaga (Spain). As I was by myself, and to document and support &amp;ldquo;the cause&amp;rdquo;, I took my camerca and zig-zagged thourgh the crowd, in a kind of amateur sociological analysis of the most interesting social movement in these turbulent times. Here are some not-so-random thoughts:
 While no particular spacial organization can be detected in the demonstration, the group dynamics and power hierarchy (even if perceived representation power) applied their invisible forces once more to take the radicals (or most outspoken at least) to march in the front line, families in the middle, and party goers and curious at the back Most &amp;ldquo;organizers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;speakers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;banner-holders and support van drivers&amp;rdquo; were foreign (mainly Argentinians) Although supposedly devoid of political affiliation, the only ones showing political signs were those without direct political representation in the form of &amp;ldquo;their own party&amp;rdquo; (anarchist, republicans, etc) While there was no &amp;ldquo;organized plan of action&amp;rdquo; (I wonder if the &amp;ldquo;assemblies&amp;rdquo; could get to one without some sort of non-hierarchical order and/or structure), the #cazerolada and #lacaixaesmordor seem to channel the discontempt towards the direct real cause (superficial, first and most apparent, but not necessarily the most important) of the dire social tensions of today: banks and the financial system&amp;hellip; although how about the political system that allowed that to happen (from corruption to &amp;ldquo;democratic&amp;rdquo; representation)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business advice for startups: do not collect underpants</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/business-advice-for-startups-do-not-collect-underpants/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 11:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/business-advice-for-startups-do-not-collect-underpants/</guid>
      <description>First read this post.
Then watch this South Park episode.
Now, if you are not going to cook something, get out of the kitchen (and at least start selling 😉 )</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The danger of graphs and cold data</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</guid>
      <description>After posting graphs and cold data (quite ilustrative, I believe), and the discussion it has generated (people, why don`t you use the &amp;ldquo;comment&amp;rdquo; instead all the other unstructured methods you are using?), please let me write a caveat about graphs and cold data.
In my high-tech gym, you have the option to have a lot of data collected, for your own, private and personal use. It seems like a great idea at first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is poisoning the world?</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/who-is-poisoning-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 18:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/who-is-poisoning-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Play with data, discover, learn the hard truth&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letting data talk</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/letting-data-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 18:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/letting-data-talk/</guid>
      <description>Government debt does not explain it all:Unemployment is, indeed, quite inapelable:And minimum wage:So, perhaps, taking all those (and the last &amp;ldquo;devastating evidence&amp;rdquo; one) graphs into account, French and German governments have tricked, via manipulative markets and rating agencies, ignorant technocrat Spain`s PP government into cutting social spending (like education and health, which in turn becomes productivity, and minimum wage and job stability, which promotes spending and growth) so we go deeper into the hole, and they take advantage of our excellent engineers at a low rate, while speculating with debt and making sure Spain does not become a strong competitor&amp;hellip;Don`t they realise that with a monarchy that &amp;ldquo;shoots itself in the foot trying to hunt elephants and hiding corruption and scandalous ties&amp;rdquo;, a media that is so self complacent and ass kissing that feels more like brothels, politicians so entrenched in the corrupt game that with two degrees of separation you could not find an honest Spaniard anymore, a starch church mingling in public affairs, and a population so absorbed by soccer, celebrities and fear, they do not need to do that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC anarchist book fair</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/nyc-anarchist-book-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 13:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/nyc-anarchist-book-fair/</guid>
      <description>Since I could not get a hold of tickts for New Museum`s Seven on Seven, I decided to make the most out of my day yesterday (defying my cold), so I even had time to visit the NYC anarchist book fair, at Judson Church (Washington Square).
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5731668030633382577]
I wish I had had more time to devote to exploring all the literature (great and aweful) on display. But at least I had time to notice:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian film at MoMA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/russian-film-at-moma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 13:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/russian-film-at-moma/</guid>
      <description>After j-CATION and having lunch at Mr. Ks&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (one of the best Chinese restaurants in Manhattan), yesterday I went to &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.moma.org/visit/calendar/film_screenings/14846&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.moma.org/visit/calendar/film_screenings/14846&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;MoMA&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; Film to see Gosfilmofonds copy of the 1935 USSR film Loss of the Sensation (87 min.), directed by Aleksandr Andriyevsky.
Virtually unseen in the U.S., Andriyevskys liberal film version of Karel Capeks popular 1920 play, R.U.R. (in which the notion of robots was introduced), the movie tells the story of Jim Ripple, an engineer, who invents robots controlled by saxophones and radio signals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I admire these criminals</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-admire-these-criminals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 15:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/i-admire-these-criminals/</guid>
      <description>In Spain, the conservative PP government is planning to make &amp;ldquo;passive resistance&amp;rdquo; a crime(as well as organizing demonstrations using internet technologies).
I have these 4 criminals` magnetic puppets on my fridge. 2 were outlawed (and had to flee) by German Nazis. 1 had to flee Spanish dictatorship because he was a Communist. And the other one was thrown in jail by British occupation forces for &amp;ldquo;passive resistance&amp;rdquo;.
 I will not let anyone walk through my mind with their dirty feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newspaper map (with translations)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/newspaper-map-with-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 12:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/newspaper-map-with-translations/</guid>
      <description>Map + Newspapers + Translations = Simple and AWESOME!!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curators` thoughts</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/curators-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 00:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/curators-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>On September 28, 2011, Hou Hanru, Director of Exhibitions and Public Programs at the San Francisco Art Institute said on a lecture (Curator`s Perspective) in New York:
 I think the worst exhibition in the world is the exhibition that is organized like a book. We see this a lot, an exhibition that takes the artwork as an illustration of a concept. I think an exhibition is not necessary for this: frankly, it`s too expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with face.com face recognition technology</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/playing-with-face.com-face-recognition-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 17:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/playing-with-face.com-face-recognition-technology/</guid>
      <description>While I am preparing a loooooong post about technology and privacy (with a provocative twist, for a change 😈 ), I have decided to play with face.com‘s face recognition technology.
What do you think? On target (hint: no, not on target, I am not THAT old, and definitely I AM a male)? Scary (hint: only if we are unaware of these technologies and their uses)?&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The absurd cost of healthcare in the USA, one example</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-absurd-cost-of-healthcare-in-the-usa-one-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 14:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-absurd-cost-of-healthcare-in-the-usa-one-example/</guid>
      <description>There is a lot of debate and analysis on why is the US healthcare system so freakingly expensive (basic answer: greedy inhuman and short sighted powerful economic interest added to puppet politicians and sheepish voters). Here is one real life example: a friend in Atlanta told me that he went to the hospital ER after feeling intense chest pain. He knew it was most likely a strong episode of acid reflux (he had been suffering from that for some time), but it was so severe, he got scared and wanted to check.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The price of standing up for your rights: Opt-Out at Atlanta`s airport scanner</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-price-of-standing-up-for-your-rights-opt-out-at-atlantas-airport-scanner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 14:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-price-of-standing-up-for-your-rights-opt-out-at-atlantas-airport-scanner/</guid>
      <description>Atlanta`s Hartsfield airport has been having one of those uselessscanners that show passengers naked for a while now. But the last time I was there, they were being tested, and most passengers did not go through them. Today, though, as I approached the security line, I saw that next to every metal detector, there was one of those scanners. &amp;ldquo;Wow, this is getting worse&amp;rdquo;, I thought, while seeing how almost everybody was going through the scanners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MoMA members night party and the economy of access as identity</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-moma-members-night-party-and-the-economy-of-access-as-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 11:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-moma-members-night-party-and-the-economy-of-access-as-identity/</guid>
      <description>Last night I attended the members night party at the Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) in New York.
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5723677090335639153]
The &amp;ldquo;party&amp;rdquo; was, as most &amp;ldquo;parties&amp;rdquo; in the USA: drinks, and people. Thats basically it. The music was soft enough that it was barely perceivable (unlike the New Museums party, where DJs try to make it impossible to talk to the person next to you).
So, why all the fuss? Why go to a &amp;ldquo;party&amp;rdquo; that has basically nothing to offer in terms of &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel discussion about art collecting at Asia Society</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/panel-discussion-about-art-collecting-at-asia-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 22:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/panel-discussion-about-art-collecting-at-asia-society/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday morning I went to the Asia Society for a panel discussiontitled: &amp;ldquo;The Future of the Past – Collecting Ancient Art in the 21st Century&amp;rdquo; presented by the American Committee for Cultural Policyin conjunction with Asia Week. The panelists included:
 Naman Ahuja, Professor of Indian Art and Architecture, Jawaharlal Nehru University, Delhi, India Kate Fitz Gibbon, attorney and author, former member of the Cultural Property Advisory Committee to the President Kurt A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards an oversimplification cliff: when green=drunks</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/towards-an-oversimplification-cliff-when-greendrunks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 18:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/towards-an-oversimplification-cliff-when-greendrunks/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday morning, as I was walking towards the gym on Park Avenue, I saw waves of young adults (although acting like teenagers or frat boys) wearing green (some just a t-shirt or sweater, some a full leprechaun costume) on a procession towards their favorite Irish watering hole to &amp;ldquo;celebrate&amp;rdquo; St. Patricks Day in the only way that they seem to believe to be appropriate, besides a 5th Ave. official parade: drink until you pass out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subway hell on the way to a meeting</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/subway-hell-on-the-way-to-a-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 15:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/subway-hell-on-the-way-to-a-meeting/</guid>
      <description>On Friday morning I had a meeting, so I took the 1 Subway line to 168th St. [mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5718647890686730977]
Given, the station was not the coolest in NY, but what shocked me was that at the other end of the platform, there was a man on the floor, and people just passed by as if nobody was there.
So I crossed to the other side, and asked him if he needed help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infographic on the Hypocrisy in Hollywood</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/infographic-on-the-hypocrisy-in-hollywood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 01:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/infographic-on-the-hypocrisy-in-hollywood/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sarah Sze`s Infinite Line en Asia Society</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/sarah-szes-infinite-line-en-asia-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 01:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/sarah-szes-infinite-line-en-asia-society/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I had the enourmous pleasure of going to see Sara Sze‘s Infinite Lineat Asia Society.
Definitely a pleasure, an exhibition not to be missed, and true to Sarah`s aim: works that a photograph can not capture (not that the copyright zealots of the Asia Society would let you take pictures anyway).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context in Art as Political Discussion: Amalia Pica`s Venn Diagrams</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/context-in-art-as-political-discussion-amalia-picas-venn-diagrams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 19:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/context-in-art-as-political-discussion-amalia-picas-venn-diagrams/</guid>
      <description>One of the multiple interesting pieces currently being exhibited at the New Museums &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://cortell.net/blog/2012/03/the-ungovernables-party-at-new-museum/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://cortell.net/blog/2012/03/the-ungovernables-party-at-new-museum/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;The Ungovernables&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; is Amalia Picas Venn Diagrams. The text under this piece says:
 During the period of dictatorship in Argentina in the 1970s, gatherings of citizens were closely monitored as they were considered a threat to the government. At the same time group theory and venn diagrams were banned from primary school programs as they could provide a model for subversive thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better privacy through your browser</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/better-privacy-through-your-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 17:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/better-privacy-through-your-browser/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to improve your online privacy? Go ahead, install HTTPSand Collusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Visa odyssey</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/a-visa-odyssey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 23:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/a-visa-odyssey/</guid>
      <description>This is the story of an L1 Visa. I will try to make it short, although some details have to be explained to be believed&amp;hellip;
In August of 2011 I thought of starting a US subsidiary of my software company in the USA, so I decided to move to New York to start it up and manage it. Since I needed a visa (form I-129) to live and work in the USA, I contacted an immigration lawyer (form G-28 and thousands of dollars) through a friend, and we started the whole process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypocritical and absurd visa questions</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/hypocritical-and-absurd-visa-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 07:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/hypocritical-and-absurd-visa-questions/</guid>
      <description>Some hypocritical and absurd questions found in the DS-160 form, needed to get a US Visa:
 Do you have a mental or physical disorder that poses or is likely to pose a threat to the safety or welfare of yourself or others? Are you or have you ever been a drug abuser or addict? Have you ever violated, or engaged in a conspiracy to violate, any law relating to controlled substances?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debt graph as main decoration in government office</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/debt-graph-as-main-decoration-in-government-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 20:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/debt-graph-as-main-decoration-in-government-office/</guid>
      <description>On Monday, I met the Chief Information Officer of a large US Government Administration in Washington DC.
His office was surprisingly small and functional compared to European &amp;ldquo;big government&amp;rdquo; offices. A nice reminder of how European bureaucracy and public sector spending in administration itself is burying us. But what caught my attention the most was the largest picture in the office: it was not Obama`s, a diploma, a family picture, a flag&amp;hellip; it was this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spain – US business = Pride Vs Arrogance</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/spain-us-business-pride-vs-arrogance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 20:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/spain-us-business-pride-vs-arrogance/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, in a meeting at the Setai Hotel in NY, Michael (with over 3 decades of experience working with US and Spanish corporations) perfectly described what is like to do business between the USA and Spain:
 A struggle between American arrogance and Spanish pride
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MLK speech &amp;quot;I have a dream&amp;quot; under restrictive copyright</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/mlk-speech-quoti-have-a-dreamquot-under-restrictive-copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 18:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/mlk-speech-quoti-have-a-dreamquot-under-restrictive-copyright/</guid>
      <description>Embarrassing. We should all be ashamed. At least we can access his words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spain, second country in the world with the most &amp;quot;disappeared&amp;quot; after Cambodia</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/spain-second-country-in-the-world-with-the-most-quotdisappearedquot-after-cambodia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 18:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/spain-second-country-in-the-world-with-the-most-quotdisappearedquot-after-cambodia/</guid>
      <description>After 36 years of democracy, [Spain] is the second country in the world with the most &amp;ldquo;disappeared&amp;rdquo; after Cambodia
 SourceRegional President Campsfree, the Duke Urdangarínseems like is not going to be punished&amp;hellip; and judge Garzonbeing judged. And you ask me why I say I am &amp;ldquo;European&amp;rdquo; rather than &amp;ldquo;Spaniard&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Valencian&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artist that still don`t get it</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/artist-that-still-dont-get-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 05:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/artist-that-still-dont-get-it/</guid>
      <description>This is not going to be one of those deep, thoughtful, analytical posts (as if I ever wrote one 😉 ). I just need to vent.
Last Saturday, in Prince Street, in the middle of Soho, a man (I will not mention his name, because as you will see, he does not deserve publicity) was handing out CDs. As with anything digital, I felt the urge to find out more, so I took it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almodovar and SGAE force cancellation of film screenings at NY Library</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/almodovar-and-sgae-force-cancellation-of-film-screenings-at-ny-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 17:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/almodovar-and-sgae-force-cancellation-of-film-screenings-at-ny-library/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went to the New York Public Library to see Pedro Almodovars &amp;quot;Talk to her&amp;quot;, as part of a &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.nypl.org/blog/2011/12/06/films-pedro-almodovar&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.nypl.org/blog/2011/12/06/films-pedro-almodovar&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;series&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; of Almodovars films screenings in the NYPL. But, to my surprise, the screening (and remainder ones) had been cancelled.
I talked to the person in the information desk, and she told me that the collecting society (that would be the despicable SGAE, which does not even deserve a link in my blog) and Almodovar`s Production company (El Deseo Producciones) had raised what they had previously been asking for as royalties or compensation for the (free) screening of the (not in movie theater) films, and the amount they were now asking was so high, the NYPL could not afford it, so they had to cancel the screenings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArtHack Exhibit closing party in Brooklyn</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 22:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday I went to the ArtHack Exhibitclosing party at 319 ScholesSt, Brooklyn (New York).
Located in an industrial complex in Brooklyn, at night, loooong two blocks from the subway, graffiti all over, small door&amp;hellip; that gave way to heaven: young (I was the oldest hacker in that space, but I did not feel that way) energetic happy people tinkering with technology and proudly showing their &amp;ldquo;toys&amp;rdquo; (hacks, mashups, creations, or whatever).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RePress: fight online censorship with a WP Plug-In</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/repress-fight-online-censorship-with-a-wp-plug-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 17:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/repress-fight-online-censorship-with-a-wp-plug-in/</guid>
      <description>I just installed RePress: This plug-in enables you to magically uncensor any website on the internet from your own WordPress installation. Why and How.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic reactions: Twitter censorship, Google campaign, and magenta trade-marked</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/automatic-reactions-twitter-censorship-google-campaign-and-magenta-trade-marked/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 15:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/automatic-reactions-twitter-censorship-google-campaign-and-magenta-trade-marked/</guid>
      <description>The net was all up in arms this week. After the marvelous uprising against SOPA and PIPA, the new battle ground was Twitter`s announcement of country specific censorship. Never mind that they are open about it (unlike Facebook), never mind that they are talking about their offices and employees in those countries where censorship is the law&amp;hellip; if you hear &amp;ldquo;censorship&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;net&amp;rdquo; get up and scream! Wired has a nice pieceabout it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of context in the interpretation (and enjoyment) of a work of art</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-importance-of-context-in-the-interpretation-and-enjoyment-of-a-work-of-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 01:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-importance-of-context-in-the-interpretation-and-enjoyment-of-a-work-of-art/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went to 3 exhibitions/events that have allowed me to see the importance of context in the interpretation (and enjoyment) of a work of art. Note that I differentiate &amp;ldquo;interpretation&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;enjoyment&amp;rdquo;, although for many of us, those two concepts go hand in hand. But this is just a short post, so the Phenomenological Aesthetics will have to wait (you can read Dewey, Hartmann, Adorno, Ortega y Gasset, Sartre, etc, etc in the meantime 😉 )</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture in today`s world in a state of polarized anomie</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/culture-in-todays-world-in-a-state-of-polarized-anomie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 17:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/culture-in-todays-world-in-a-state-of-polarized-anomie/</guid>
      <description>When Émile Durkheim wrote on the concept of anomie (expanding on Jean-Marie Guyau`s work) in his 1897 book Suicide, he spoke of one end of anomie: a society with too much rigidity and little individual discretion causing a destructive mismatch (moral deregulation and an absence of legitimate aspirations).
This is happening in the XXI century world, in many countries: those totalitarian (military or religious) societies where the social rule, expectations, and repression conform a cage around individuals, deposessing them of their individuality, their aspirations, subtly (or otherwise) imposing a social corset where the individual can not be itself, concentrating only on breathing, surviving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEDxManhattan: Changing the way we eat</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/tedxmanhattan-changing-the-way-we-eat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 16:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/tedxmanhattan-changing-the-way-we-eat/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow, January 21st, 2012, NY</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Zen ad making me sick</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/anti-zen-ad-making-me-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 10:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/anti-zen-ad-making-me-sick/</guid>
      <description>As I walk towards my office, I see an ad that makes me sick (as a matter of fact, I see many, but this one points to something other that the consumerism-sexism-excess that we are so dangerously getting used to).
The ad says &amp;ldquo;Turn now into memories&amp;rdquo;. How wrong is that?!!
Now is now. Now has to be now. Now should be now. Now has to remain now.
When you strive to &amp;ldquo;turn now into memories&amp;rdquo;, you are missing out on the real now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protest against SOPA on your site: easy code</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/protest-against-sopa-on-your-site-easy-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 09:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/protest-against-sopa-on-your-site-easy-code/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Sara, there is a very easy way to add code to your site to protest against SOPA:
Drop the following code in between your two tags on your site, your users will be redirected to the blackout page that describes what you are doing and why.
`Then, when the protest is over, simply remove the added code. The protest is starting at 12am on 1/18, and lasts 24 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia blackout protesting SOPA and PIPA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/wikipedia-blackout-protesting-sopa-and-pipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 19:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/wikipedia-blackout-protesting-sopa-and-pipa/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;div&amp;gt; Today, the Wikipedia community &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;w:en:Wikipedia:SOPA initiative/Action&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/en:Wikipedia:SOPA_initiative/Action&amp;quot;&amp;gt;announced its decision&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; to black out the English-language Wikipedia for 24 hours, worldwide, beginning at 05:00 UTC on Wednesday, January 18 (you can read the &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;Press releases/English Wikipedia to go dark&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Press_releases/English_Wikipedia_to_go_dark&amp;quot;&amp;gt;statement from the Wikimedia Foundation here&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;). The blackout is a protest against proposed legislation in the United States—the &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;w:en:Stop Online Piracy Act&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/en:Stop_Online_Piracy_Act&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Stop Online Piracy Act (SOPA)&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate MLK day with RX2008 mix</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/celebrate-mlk-day-with-rx2008-mix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 09:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/celebrate-mlk-day-with-rx2008-mix/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The absurd hypocrisy of the recent &amp;quot;Intelectual Property&amp;quot; legal abuse</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-absurd-hypocrisy-of-the-recent-quotintelectual-propertyquot-legal-abuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 17:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-absurd-hypocrisy-of-the-recent-quotintelectual-propertyquot-legal-abuse/</guid>
      <description>The USA has become the largest exporter of censorship.
Based on wrong beliefs, manipulated data, and self-declared ignorant politicians, their legislative body cooks up a law designed to restrict competition, serving the interests (apparently, although as any freshman Economics student will tell you, that is not really the case) of an oligopoly of media-(sic)culture megacorporations that would not recognized the present (not to say &amp;ldquo;future&amp;rdquo;) if it hit them in the face, represented by multi-million dollar copyright infringers, while stomping on basic citizens` rights (not that they seem to care anyway, since they allow such basic rights violations as warrantless GPS monitoring, or unlimited incarceration without trial).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook: couple breaker for drunks</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/facebook-couple-breaker-for-drunks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 05:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/facebook-couple-breaker-for-drunks/</guid>
      <description>Interesting couple of trivia about Facebook in UK:
 Facebook blamed for one-third marriage breakdowns British Facebook users intoxicated in 76% of their photos  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga Guru uses copyright to sue competitor</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 19:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/yoga-guru-uses-copyright-to-sue-competitor/</guid>
      <description>Ego, money, power, abuse, restriction&amp;hellip; shame on those who stain the &amp;ldquo;holy&amp;rdquo; teachings.
Source: NYT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senate celebrates Bill of Rights authorizing indefinite detentions</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/senate-celebrates-bill-of-rights-authorizing-indefinite-detentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 19:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/senate-celebrates-bill-of-rights-authorizing-indefinite-detentions/</guid>
      <description>The US Senate &amp;ldquo;celebrates&amp;rdquo; the 220th anniversary of the ratification of the Bill of Rights by passing a defense billthat authorizes indefinite detentions of American terrorism suspects.
Beautiful irony. Source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying to Rio with a character</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/flying-to-rio-with-a-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 10:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/flying-to-rio-with-a-character/</guid>
      <description>After arriving in JFK in the most predictable way (rain, snow, traffic or whatever) which is the combo E line + AirTrain, and boarding on a &amp;ldquo;last call&amp;rdquo; although I arrived early enough (due to the never-ending security lines, and the abnormal amount of passengers with special needs such as many small children in strollers, large hand-luggage, senior citizens, etc) I finally arrive at my seat on the flight New York – Rio de Janeiro, and I see it is occupied by… Rolls Royce car keys, with a Rolls Royce keyring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We the people... divorce = bankruptcy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/we-the-people...-divorce-bankruptcy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 17:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/we-the-people...-divorce-bankruptcy/</guid>
      <description>Walking on 8th Ave., I find this amazing signs on a lawyer`s office window (NO COMMENT):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing private copies for moving to NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/preparing-private-copies-for-moving-to-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 16:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/preparing-private-copies-for-moving-to-ny/</guid>
      <description>In Spain we have a legal right called &amp;ldquo;private copy&amp;rdquo; by which anyone can make a copy (for non-commercial use) of their copyrighted content (movies, music, books, etc). To offset the supposed loss (many studies prove this &amp;ldquo;loss&amp;rdquo; to be a fallacy) we Spaniards pay the so-called &amp;ldquo;Digital canon&amp;rdquo;, a tax levied on blank media (CDs, HardDisks, printers, photocopiers, etc, etc) and managed by private monopolistic institutions called &amp;ldquo;collecting societies&amp;rdquo;, some run by supposed alcohol-consuming, whore-user, money-embezzler, tax-evading criminals (or so goes the accusations brought to a number of them by the Attorney General).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are charitable dinners and then charitable dinners</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/there-are-charitable-dinners-and-then-charitable-dinners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 10:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/there-are-charitable-dinners-and-then-charitable-dinners/</guid>
      <description>I hate charitable dinners where most (or almost all) of the money goes to caviar, tuxedos, valet parking and other hoopla.
Fortunately there are other charitable dinners, where you wont see any &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.escolar.net/MT/archives/2011/11/la-nueva-politica-de-igualdad.html&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.escolar.net/MT/archives/2011/11/la-nueva-politica-de-igualdad.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;PP mothers&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, like yesterdays organized by Didi, where people sit on the floor, eat off plastic plates, and enjoy Didis deliciously vegan cooking and sincere love, so just about all money collected goes to Calcuttas orphans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a movement!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-a-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 10:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-a-movement/</guid>
      <description>First things first: thanks to whomever thought I would be interested in joining MCAthrough RiseUp, BUT&amp;hellip;
 Don`t subscribe me to a list without my consent Don`t do so without at least letting me know who you are Don`t assume I might be interested in something because it sounds related to my interest Don`t align me with &amp;ldquo;scientific socialism&amp;rdquo; when I am a declared anarchist Don`t make me waste my time on a list where the first 20 or so messages are split between arguing troskist, marxist, rose of lenburguist, bujarinist, bakuninist, leninist, hotsiminist, guevarist, maoist, castrist&amp;hellip; and people who want to be taken off the list  So, thanks (and I show it by talking about your project here), but show a little respect for other people`s rights, please.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plagiarism</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/plagiarism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 13:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/plagiarism/</guid>
      <description>From worksto charactersthe list of plagiarism in mainstream media and culture is staggering. Read also the comments for further info and discussion.
It even happensbetween Harvard scholars!
Know of any comprehensive listof plagiarism? Let us know!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approaching 1984</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/approaching-1984/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 12:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/approaching-1984/</guid>
      <description>Governments that use stats to lie, that shamelessly change political stands, that pocket millionaires paychecks and retirements in even in times of crisis&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, that &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.ij.org/about/4058&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.ij.org/about/4058&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;steal from citizens with any excuse&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, that &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://boingboing.net/2011/09/25/rejected-designs-for-the-federal-housing-finance-agency-seal.html?utm_source=pulsenews&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+boingboing%2FiBag+%28Boing+Boing%29&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://boingboing.net/2011/09/25/rejected-designs-for-the-federal-housing-finance-agency-seal.html?utm_source=pulsenews&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+boingboing%2FiBag+%28Boing+Boing%29&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;do not care to spend 400$ or 600,000€ in a logo&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, that allow an &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://youtu.be/6zZ_JfROhOE&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://youtu.be/6zZ_JfROhOE&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;out of control financial system&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (and force lower interest to finance a war driven by personal economic interests in a time that required higher interests) which places us at the edge of the cliff and dares to &amp;quot;rescue them&amp;quot; with everybodys money, with a cost higher than which would be needed to end poverty in the world, and not making any changes so it does not happen again in the financial or food markets&amp;hellip; all this and more, with complete impunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignorants eat shit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/ignorants-eat-shit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 12:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/ignorants-eat-shit/</guid>
      <description>According to this articlethe food people usually eat (thanks to my wife and my conscience, I have slightly healthier eating habits than most people) is pure shit: wood celulose in many foods, fruit juices over a year old, ammonia in meat, artificial blueberries, &amp;ldquo;free-range chicken&amp;rdquo; that is not free at all, and other lies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>