<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Videogames on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/videogames/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Videogames on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 15:33:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/videogames/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to speak at Microsoft Healthcare event</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/08/invited-to-speak-at-microsoft-healthcare-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 15:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/08/invited-to-speak-at-microsoft-healthcare-event/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday August 9th, I was invited to talk about Personalised Medicine at Microsoft’s event “Empowering Health in a mobile first and cloud first world”, at Microsoft’s UK headquarters in Reading (UK).
There were very interesting sessions on Intelligent Cloud, Microsoft Research (with whom we are collaborating) work on radiology and genomics, Introduction to productivity in health, Revolutionising infection control, National Technology Officer’s Cloud Update, Transdermal Sensors in Paediatric Care, Introduction to personalised computing in health, Virtual care clinics in Sweden, Digital wellbeing, The venture programme for health, NHS…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyperJapan 2016 London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/hyperjapan-2016-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 15:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/hyperjapan-2016-london/</guid>
      <description>Today we went with my sister and brother-in-law, who are visiting for a few days, to HyperJapanin London Olympia.
Silly and fun, full of cosplay and otakus. Kawaii!
^.^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Society and Forbidden Planet London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/japan-society-and-forbidden-planet-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 08:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/japan-society-and-forbidden-planet-london/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday , on my way from an event to a meeting, I made two stops. The first one in Forbidden Planet.
Forbidden Planet is a comic store that I enjoyed tremendously while living in New York. While not exactly Tokyo’s Mandarake, Forbidden Planet had enough variety to make it interesting. What I did not know is that they had such a large store in London! It is a fun place full of comic (and non-comic) books, manga, merchandise, figures, posters…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Father’s Day gift: building a Picade with my son</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/ultimate-fathers-day-gift-building-a-picade-with-my-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 13:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/ultimate-fathers-day-gift-building-a-picade-with-my-son/</guid>
      <description>For Father’s Day (we live in London, so we celebrate it today, unlike in Spain which is March 19) my wife gave me the “Ultimate Father`s Day” gift, from TechCamp UK. [Thank you, love!]
It consisted of a workshop with other father-son / father-daughter “teams”, held at the Iron Yard (The Leathermarket – London), where we built a desktop arcade machine in 5 hours (including lunch break), following the directions from Tom and Tom, using the Picadeset, setting up and using the Raspberry Pi, custom OS, emulators, ROMs, loudspeakers, power supply, LCD screen, etc:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited with my son to Intel Buzz videogame developer workshop</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-with-my-son-to-intel-buzz-videogame-developer-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 17:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-with-my-son-to-intel-buzz-videogame-developer-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Today I was invited, along with my son, who at 14 has been a videogame developer for years, to attend the Intel Buzz videogame developer workshop. It was not only a lot of fun, but WONDERFUL to attend with him!
Although a small event, it ended up being extremely interesting, with an area to try indie games and new technologies, and a long list of talks and panels, including one-on-ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attending the presentation of a new videogame as investment opportunity</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/attending-the-presentation-of-a-new-videogame-as-investment-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 20:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/attending-the-presentation-of-a-new-videogame-as-investment-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>On Monday I attended the presentation of Project M, a new video-game as investment opportunity, in Google Campus, London.

First of all, let me congratulate the savvy business and marketing team behind it. They put together a well though-out package, their idea is unique and very interesting: a videogame that will reward players by sending them real gold + investors buying &amp;ldquo;mines&amp;rdquo; in the game and participating in the profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NY ComicCon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/ny-comiccon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 23:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/ny-comiccon/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5934418147899482241]
After going the other day with Maker Fairewith my parents, yesterday we went backto ComicCon. The usual: cosplay, crowds, swag&amp;hellip; FUN!!
UPDATE: here is a list of interesting links (artists, publishing houses, software, etc) we collected there.
Artists/Comics:
 Bill Plympton (studio, blog, store, tumblr), whom I have admired for many years, was there in person. Cool! Dylan (UpsideDownGrin) Rich Miller (FilthWorks) Selina Briggs (The Jelly Empire) The Gate Crashers  Studios/Stores:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections from NY Comic Con</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 09:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I went to NY Comic Con, like everyone else, I guess, with the idea of having fun, of experiencing first hand one of the &amp;ldquo;major events&amp;rdquo; that a true nerdy geek can attend. I also wanted to meet Cory Doctorow (although we actually ended up not meeting). It has been years since I last met him, and it was the perfect &amp;ldquo;excuse&amp;rdquo; to attend the conference.
When I arrived, I was really surprised to see the size of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft, derivative works, parodies...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 10:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</guid>
      <description>Hugo sends me thisamazing song/video made in Minecraft. Of course, that leads to 10more, 14more&amp;hellip; there are so many!
When you make the tools available to the people, and allow them to create (in this case under the safe harbor of &amp;ldquo;parody&amp;rdquo;) wonderful things happen. Its NOT all about the money, profit, control... Its about imagination, art, creativity, culture. Thats how it happens: copying, re-using, mixing, adjusting, modifying... thats what creativity is really about (or did you think it was about &amp;ldquo;inventing&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;making unheard of things out of thin air&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry Elephants</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/angry-elephants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 21:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/angry-elephants/</guid>
      <description>via APM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geekest prom date</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/geekest-prom-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 10:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/geekest-prom-date/</guid>
      <description>And you thought I was talking about Princess Leia?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>