<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Art on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Art on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 06:21:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Singapore day 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/03/singapore-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 06:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/03/singapore-day-3/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, March 7 in the morning, after breakfast, we checked out of the hotel. But before we boarded the cruise ship, we left the luggage with the hotel’s concierge, and went across the bridge to visit the National Gallery Singapore, which is the only main museum in Singapore I had not yet visited, since it opened in 2015.
It has an interesting Asian art collection, with artist from the late XIX Century like Raden Saleh, to the XX Century like Liu Kang, Nguyen Gia Tri, and contemporaries like Tang Da Wu or Montien Boonma (whose “The Pleasure of Being, Crying, Dying and Eating” was being restored, and it looked better in the glass temporary encaging than when originally created in 1993, and reconstructed in 2015).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Revolution needs a Revolution</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 17:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/01/this-revolution-needs-a-revolution/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went with my wife and son to visit the Victoria &amp;amp; Albert`s Museum exhibition You Say You Want a Revolution? Records and Rebels 1966-1970. The aim of the exhibition was quite clear:
 How have the finished and unfinished revolutions of the late 1960s changed the way we live today and think about the future?
 I was very much looking forward to visiting the exhibition. It is SO timely, and SO needed, I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My non-commissioned art installation at the Contemporary Art Museum in Santiago, Chile</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/my-non-commissioned-art-installation-at-the-contemporary-art-museum-in-santiago-chile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 10:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/my-non-commissioned-art-installation-at-the-contemporary-art-museum-in-santiago-chile/</guid>
      <description>The exhibition titled “Le Corbusier and South America”, in the main hall of the Contemporary Art Museum in Santiago (Chile), shows for the first time in Chile a collection of Le Corbusier’s original plans and drawings for 12 projects he created in South America (although, of all of those, only the Curutchet house in Argentina was actually built).
As part of the exhibition, Chilean curator Maximiano Atria has arranged all around the central part of the hall location-specific installations by a number of artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santiago Museums</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/santiago-museums/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 16:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/12/santiago-museums/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday 13 I had the rare opportunity of spending a few hours doing what I like most during a business trip: visiting art museums. I went to the Fine Arts National Museum, the Contemporary Art Museum, the Visual Arts Museum, and the Telefonica Foundation Art Gallery.
Without a doubt, the two museums I enjoyed the most were the Fine Arts National Museum, and the Contemporary Art Museum.
The installation in the lobby of the Fine Arts National Museum is amazing, and the building itself (with a dome designed by Eiffel) is quite impressive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting the London Design Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/visiting-the-london-design-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 08:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/visiting-the-london-design-museum/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I visited the Design Museum(&amp;ldquo;The world`s leading museum devoted to contemporary design in every form from architecture and fashion to graphics, product and industrial design&amp;rdquo;) in its spectacular new location on High Street Kensington (London), with my son.
The #newdesignmuseum opened its doors in its new location only 5 days ago. The building and renovation are great, and in a nice location: on the edge of Holland Park, with the added bonus of being near the Kyoto Garden, Muji, and not far from the Serpentine Gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Düsseldorf Museums</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/d%C3%BCsseldorf-museums/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 09:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/d%C3%BCsseldorf-museums/</guid>
      <description>Last week I spent 3 days in Düsseldorf, attending the Medica trade show. But I do not want to bore you with that. I`d rather tell you what I did after the trade show closed every day.
Since Düsseldorf is a city that I know well, I decided to concentrate in its museums and art galleries. I could not have picked a more perfect time!
At the Kunsthalle I attended the excellent exhibition titled “Wool and water”, wi­th: Li­li Du­jou­rie, Isa Genz­ken, As­trid Klein, Mi­scha Ku­ball, Aron Meh­zi­on, Rein­hard Mu­cha, Stur­te­vant, Ro­se­ma­rie Tro­ckel, and Ger­hard Rich­ter; cu­ra­ted by Gre­gor Jan­sen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I acquired a David Shrigley piece from the Ludwig Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/i-acquired-a-david-shrigley-piece-from-the-ludwig-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 16:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/i-acquired-a-david-shrigley-piece-from-the-ludwig-museum/</guid>
      <description>November 9 I acquired from the Ludwig Museum “I collect records”, a 27 cm ø 175gr. professional vinyl frisbee piece that the Turner Prize-nominated artist and occasional DJ David Shrigley created in 2012.
“I collect records” is based on a drawing he did for a record cover featured in his exhibition Life and Life Drawing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My artwork “God bless Amurika”, on display at the Ludwig Museum (Cologne), explained</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-artwork-god-bless-amurika-on-display-at-the-ludwig-museum-cologne-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 09:26:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/my-artwork-god-bless-amurika-on-display-at-the-ludwig-museum-cologne-explained/</guid>
      <description>I have often criticized artists who hide behind “my work speaks for itself” or “it’s up to the viewer to interpret my work”. Nice try, but that’s bullshit.
Of course, anyone can interpret anything when exposed to an artwork! But the artist should at least make an attempt to explain the meaning behind a piece. No matter how self-explanatory (or obscure) it might be. It’s not “restricting the viewer”, it’s guiding; suggesting is not imposing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview for the art exhibition that I have curated and is currently being shown in Kaunas, Lithuania</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/interview-for-the-art-exhibition-that-i-have-curated-and-is-currently-being-shown-in-kaunas-lithuania/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/interview-for-the-art-exhibition-that-i-have-curated-and-is-currently-being-shown-in-kaunas-lithuania/</guid>
      <description>INTERVIEW with JORGE CORTELL, curator
By Airida Rekštytė – November 4, 2016
According to your profound theoretical education (sic) it will not be difficult to present us in short your intentions for organizing this event.
When did the idea of making this exhibition occur and what inspired it?
I have spent years as activist defending free software and online privacy, and opposing censorship.
During a dinner with the director of an event that focuses on those themes (the Internet Freedom Festival, also known as Circumvention Festival), I told him how it would be a nice challenge to try to convey the main messages of the Festivals themes into an art exhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DHVF, participating in a collective art performance, and meetings in Oxford Science Park</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/dhvf-participating-in-a-collective-art-performance-and-meetings-in-oxford-science-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 19:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/dhvf-participating-in-a-collective-art-performance-and-meetings-in-oxford-science-park/</guid>
      <description>The last couple of weeks in October I went to Valencia to attend the Digital Health Venture Forum, where I received the Best Presentation Award.
After spending a few days with my family and my Spanish team, and participating in an art installation by the SuperFlex collective on the 25th, I returned to London.
October 27 I went to the beautiful Oxford Science Park to have a couple of business meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last day in San Francisco: ART</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/last-day-in-san-francisco-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 22:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/09/last-day-in-san-francisco-art/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, September 17, was my last day in San Francisco, and the only one I had with some spare time.
After breakfast, I went to but some gifts from Japan Town and then headed to Union Square, for the Korean Day (Chuseok) culture festival.
Then I went to the Yerba Buena Center for the Arts to check out Tom Sachs _Space Program: Europa_. As I feared, after the failure of _Sony Outsider,_ Tom Sachs obsession with demonstrating his hand-made &amp;ldquo;bricolage style&amp;rdquo; continues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A walk through Oxford</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/a-walk-through-oxford/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 08:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/a-walk-through-oxford/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday I went with my sister and brother-in-law on a day trip to my alma mater.
Although graduation ceremonies and hoards of tourists made it hard to move around and access temporarily closed buildings, it was a sunny day, and we enjoyed the walk, including a tour of Somerville and Magdalen Colleges, the Ashmolean Museum, a rehearsal for a concert at the Church of St. Mary the Virgin, and the Bodleian Weston Library, where we saw the “Treasures: 24 pairs” exhibition and had a nice lunch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Society and Forbidden Planet London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/japan-society-and-forbidden-planet-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 08:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/07/japan-society-and-forbidden-planet-london/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday , on my way from an event to a meeting, I made two stops. The first one in Forbidden Planet.
Forbidden Planet is a comic store that I enjoyed tremendously while living in New York. While not exactly Tokyo’s Mandarake, Forbidden Planet had enough variety to make it interesting. What I did not know is that they had such a large store in London! It is a fun place full of comic (and non-comic) books, manga, merchandise, figures, posters…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by Meural</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/interviewed-by-meural/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 15:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/interviewed-by-meural/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was interviewed (as art curator) by the Meural team.
Each installment of their Deep Cuts series features a writer, artist, or curator discussing an underrated artist, artwork, movement, or museum.
In Episode 7: “Seriously playful” we discussed the work of one of my favorite artists: Claudio Zirotti.
Check it out!
https://sketchbook.meural.com/post/146606100974/deep-cuts-episode-7-seriously-playful“ADLS50″ by Claudio Zirotti</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating the non-comissioned art piece “Diangle” for the Tate Modern Gallery</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/creating-the-non-comissioned-art-piece-diangle-for-the-tate-modern-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 11:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/creating-the-non-comissioned-art-piece-diangle-for-the-tate-modern-gallery/</guid>
      <description>Thursday June 23 I was given the opportunity to create a non-comissioned art piece at the Tate Gallery new extension Switch House.
Within Meschac Gaba (1961, Benin) “Architecture Room” installation part of the “Museum of Contemporary African Art” exhibit, the artist invitation was to build my own imaginary museum… and what better place to do that than in the recently inaugurated Switch House extension of the Tate Gallery by Herzog &amp;amp; de Meuron?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting the new Tate Modern Switch House</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/visiting-the-new-tate-modern-switch-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/visiting-the-new-tate-modern-switch-house/</guid>
      <description>While narrowly avoiding the fire alarm evacuation that happened a couple of hours before we got there, what we could not avoid was the crowds. In any case, it is always a pleasure to see an expansion to an already amazing gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the AAF Art Show</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-the-aaf-art-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 14:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-to-the-aaf-art-show/</guid>
      <description>Today I went with my parents and my son to the AAF art show in Hampstead (London).
A good percentage (around 50%?) of works and an even higher percentage of galleries were the same as last year, but it was nonetheless interesting. As always.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited with my son to Intel Buzz videogame developer workshop</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-with-my-son-to-intel-buzz-videogame-developer-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 17:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/06/invited-with-my-son-to-intel-buzz-videogame-developer-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Today I was invited, along with my son, who at 14 has been a videogame developer for years, to attend the Intel Buzz videogame developer workshop. It was not only a lot of fun, but WONDERFUL to attend with him!
Although a small event, it ended up being extremely interesting, with an area to try indie games and new technologies, and a long list of talks and panels, including one-on-ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stockholm day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/stockholm-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 18:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/stockholm-day-1/</guid>
      <description>After the wonderful cruise, we disembarked in Stockholm and took a taxi to our hotel: the Nobis . It is a cool design hotel, with a particular claim to history: in their building is where the Stockholm Syndrome effect first happened. It is located in a square where they are installing heated floors!
After storing our luggage in the hotel (too early to checking-in), we went off to explore the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baltic Cruise Day 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/baltic-cruise-day-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 14:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/baltic-cruise-day-7/</guid>
      <description>Friday, May 20, we arrived in Helsinki quite early and docked by Kauppatori (Market Square) where they sell a ton of berries (blackberries, blueberries, raspberries, strawberries, etc), which we have been eating a ton during the cruise.
So, after breakfast we disembarked, and walked the Senate Square, got a map in the City Hall, where we also took the opportunity to check our email thanks to the free wifi, and went on, passing by the Helsinki Cathedral, the Palace of the Council of the State, the main building of the University of Helsinki, and the National Library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baltic Cruise Day 5</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/baltic-cruise-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 06:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/baltic-cruise-day-5/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday, May 18 we asked Marina to start the day visiting the subway (Metro), which gave us an opportunity to have an interesting political and historical discussion. I still remember the monumental Moscow’s Metro. While Saint Petersburg’s Metro is not as spectacular, there are many examples of Soviet era art and decoration. The Metro itself is old but impeccably clean and maintained.
Marina insisted in inviting us to a cup of tea at the famous Yeliseevskiy Gastronom at 56 Nevskiy Prospekt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baltic Cruise Day 4</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/baltic-cruise-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 17:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/baltic-cruise-day-4/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday May 17 we docked at 4:00am so downtown Saint Petersburg that people walking on the sidewalk could see into our suite. We were a few minutes walk from the Hermitage Museum.
After clearing immigration (you need a visa to enter Russia, unless you have arranged private escorted tours like we had), we were met by Slava, our driver, who for the next three days would take us everywhere in a large white Mercedes Benz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two days in Copenhagen</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/two-days-in-copenhagen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 19:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/05/two-days-in-copenhagen/</guid>
      <description>Thursday, May 12 we travelled to Copenhagen, Denmark. We had many things on our list, and being there for two days only, we had to make many sacrifices. But overall, we covered a lot of ground.
We had many things on our list, and being there for two days only, we had to make many sacrifices. But overall, we covered a lot of ground.Upon arrival in the airport we took the very convenient and modern train that took us to the Central Station, and our hotel was next door.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up my first art exhibit</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/setting-up-my-first-art-exhibit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 14:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/04/setting-up-my-first-art-exhibit/</guid>
      <description>The weekend of February 27 and 28 I set up my first art exhibition as Independent International Art Curator.
In collaboration with the Internet Freedom Festival, held in Las Naves (Valencia) from 2 to 6 March, Net Freedom Art Showis an international, itinerant, collective and multidisciplinary contemporary art show. After its debut in Valencia, it will be exhibited in galleries around the world (New York, London, Santiago de Chile, and Kaunas).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s pretend none of this ever happened</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 10:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/02/lets-pretend-none-of-this-ever-happened/</guid>
      <description>Walking towards my London Shoreditch office
to meet the Swiss investor and his impeccable suit,
leaving the City bankers’s coffee-holding fast pace behind,
I notice the absence nobody seems to
Where did he go?
His sleeping sack and pillow still on the sidewalk
as annoyingly positioned in the corner as always
But he’s gone
.
I wonder and I worry
his failing body, almost as absent as his lost gaze</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Big Bang Data” and “Tintin” exhibitions at Somerset House, London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/01/big-bang-data-and-tintin-exhibitions-at-somerset-house-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 18:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/01/big-bang-data-and-tintin-exhibitions-at-somerset-house-london/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we went to see a couple exhibitions at Somerset House, in London.
The first exhibition we saw was “TINTIN: Hergé`s Masterpiece”. Basic but obviously appealing, it was too crowded to be enjoyable.
The second one was “Big Bang Data”.
While undoubtedly interesting, especially for someone who works in, teaches, and loves bid data and technology like myself, to me the most interesting aspect of this exhibition is that everyone who was there had already experienced the subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ai Weiwei at the Royal Academy</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/ai-weiwei-at-the-royal-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 13:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/ai-weiwei-at-the-royal-academy/</guid>
      <description>On December 4 I was lucky enough to be invited to visit Ai Weiwei`s exhibition at the Royal Academy.
I knew I would enjoy it since Ai Weiwei is one of my favourite artists. I knew even my son, my wife and my mother-in-law would enjoy it, since Ai Weiweis art is highly figurative and symbolic, even to the point of being obvious with his latest works (which makes its appeal that more far-reaching if slightly less elitist).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tate Modern curating methodology</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/tate-modern-curating-methodology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 13:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/12/tate-modern-curating-methodology/</guid>
      <description>December 2 I went to the Tate Modernwith the whole family, since my mother-in-law was visiting from overseas.
I really like how it is set up according to concepts, rather than chronologically, by artists, or by styles. It feels more like an art gallery (which it is) than a museum. It puts things into the subjective focus of the curator. I wonder how much the artists themselves would agree with the collection parameters, but it definitely is a welcome departure from the more traditional museum logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice day in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/nice-day-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 10:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/nice-day-in-london/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday was a very nice day in London, which was convenient because I decided to walk to my two appointments, which were quite far apart.
First I met with a PR firm. You know their founders are into art when in the meeting room we were in (one of many) they had a J. Opie and a W. Hewett. Nice. Bonus points.
Then I walked to the Japanese Embassy, where I had been invited to a symposium on big data research for dementia (actually, I chuckled when I thought that, in a way, it could be argued that “big data seems to cause dementia in some vendors”) 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V&amp;A and Science Museums</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/va-and-science-museums/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 15:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/va-and-science-museums/</guid>
      <description>Sunday November 8th we went to the Victoria and Albert Museum and the Science Museum for some educational fun weekend.
I love the V&amp;amp;A for its interesting variety. We saw sculptures (although lot more Rodin than Bernini), Medieval objects (from reliquaries to clothing and drawings), and some fine examples of Japanese design.
In the Science Museum we went to see the small but extremely interesting exhibition on Ada Lovelace’s history. We learned a lot and I believe it was a great inspiration to my son.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>British Library</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/british-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 20:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/british-library/</guid>
      <description>On Friday November 6, on my way to a meeting, I stopped by the British Library. It had been quite a long time since I had been there.
You need a special permit to use their volumes, but they have a very active schedule of events and presentations, and a wonderful museum.
Amongst the “treasures” they have, there are manuscripts from Mozart (‘Verzeichnüss aller meiner Werke’), Beethoven, Magna Carta, John Lennon, Percy Bysshe Shelley (‘The Mask of Anarchy’), and many other historically relevant documents, like the first printed music in western musical notation using Gutemberg’s movable type (Southern Germany c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Press Photo 2015</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/world-press-photo-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 13:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/world-press-photo-2015/</guid>
      <description>Last Thursday, on my way to a business meeting, I stopped by the Southbank Center, to view the World Press Photo 2015 exhibition. It was a great collection of pieces, but I particularly liked (or was most shocked by) the work of Tomas van Houtryve (2nd prize stories), Cai Sheng Xiang (1st prize singles), Turi Calafato (3rd prize stories), and Arash Khamooshi (3rd prize stories).
Definitely worthwhile visiting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Illustration Awards Exhibition at Somerset House</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/world-illustration-awards-exhibition-at-somerset-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 17:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/world-illustration-awards-exhibition-at-somerset-house/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday October 31st we went to the World Illustration AwardsExhibition at Somerset House(London). It was a pure delight. Not only it was hosted at one of my favorite venues in London, but the selection of works by contemporary illustrators was quite good. The one I liked the most was Malika Favre’s Futurist-inspired posters for the BAFTAs 2015, but there were many remarkable ones, like Bartosz Kosowskis perfect poster for Kubricks Lolita, the cheerfully cute drawings of Chris Haughton for the Royal London Children`s Hospital, the super busy &amp;ldquo;Larger Than line&amp;rdquo; by Mattias Adolfsson, the powerful and colorful &amp;ldquo;Alice in Wonderland&amp;rdquo; art by Grahame Baker-Smith, or the iconic &amp;ldquo;Autism&amp;rdquo; work by Aad Goudappel (one copy of which I acquired for our private collection).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affordable Art Fair in London</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/affordable-art-fair-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 16:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/affordable-art-fair-in-london/</guid>
      <description>October 25 we were invited to attend the Affordable Art Fair in Battersea (London), where 110 galleries showcased work by 1,100 artists.
There is always something interesting, and it is always a pleasure to attend art shows, but art in NY tends to be more daring and exciting. Sometime I miss living in Manhattan.
In any case, here you have a few pictures of works that caught my eye for one reason or another:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cup Noodles Museum Yokohama</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/cup-noodles-museum-yokohama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 11:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/cup-noodles-museum-yokohama/</guid>
      <description>On my way back from the amazing Sankeien Garden, after attending (but honestly not paying much attention to) a Japanese-only BioInformatics lecture (seriously, I enjoy those things), I went for something fun and quirky: the Cup Noodles Museum.
Founded by revered Momofuku Sando-san, Instant Noodles (Cup Noodles) has a very interesting story behind its world wide wild success. I learned that Sando-san spent two years in jail for tax evasion. That he invented the instant noodles in his 60’s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yokohama day 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/yokohama-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 06:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/yokohama-day-2/</guid>
      <description>The next day it was my (almost) free day. Absolutely necessary, specially for those who are not used to long flights and big time zone differences. Not my case, but I’m still glad I had that day off… specially in Japan!
So I got up early, dealt with my emails as quickly as I could, had tradicional Japanese breakfast, I met my friend and client Komaki-san, and after the meeting I left the hotel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>British Museum and Fortnum &amp; Mason</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/british-museum-and-fortnum-mason/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 22:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/british-museum-and-fortnum-mason/</guid>
      <description>It is quite a privilege to be able to take your son to the British Museum every week for his homeschooling history class. And that’s what we did Friday October 9, but this time I also took my wife and the in-laws.
Visiting a museum on a regular basis allows for much deeper analysis and engagement, gaining on the depth the exhibits have and most tourist don’t have the time to enjoy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Gallery</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/national-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 22:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/national-gallery/</guid>
      <description>It had been quite a long time since I was last at the National Gallery, but Tuesday October 6 I took my family there. While my in-laws were visiting, for my home-schooled son was Art class time. I enjoyed tremendously discussing with him the differences between early and late Renaissance visual art.
Even if was only for the proximity to some of the world’s best museums, living in London is great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to a Christie’s Art Auction</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/invited-to-a-christies-art-auction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 13:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/10/invited-to-a-christies-art-auction/</guid>
      <description>This summer London became the setting for more than 20 giant sculptures inspired by the DNA double helix by some of the biggest names in the world of art and design, including Ai Weiwei, Aston Martin, or Zaha Hadid. Last Wednesday my wife and I were invited to the auction of those pieces at legendary art auction house Christie’s.
I was surprised, or rather “appalled”, to see that Ai Weiwei’s sculptures went for only around £20,000 each (he made two).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20/21 British Art Fair</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/20/21-british-art-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 13:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/09/20/21-british-art-fair/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I attended the 20/21 British Art Fairat the Royal College of Art, in London.
Usually I love art fairs, and find many exciting works of art. I particularly love the creative energy you can feel at contemporary art fairs.
This one was not an exciting fair. Perhaps because it is modern and contemporary, perhaps because it is limited to British artists, or perhaps because this year’s selection was not that interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My latest art acquisitions: a Hokusai and a Cel-ga</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/my-latest-art-acquisitions-a-hokusai-and-a-cel-ga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 08:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/07/my-latest-art-acquisitions-a-hokusai-and-a-cel-ga/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I acquired two very different works of Japanese fine art.
One was a very rare and wonderful find: an original Ukiyo-e woodblock print by Katsushika Hokusai (1760-1849), whose &amp;ldquo;Great Wave off Kanagawa&amp;rdquo; is one of the best-known works of Japanese art, titled “Wavy shadow of Mount Fuji” from the “One Hundred Views of Mount Fuji, Vol. 2” Series, created in 1835. The “One Hundred Views of Mount Fuji” series was featured by the British Museum in 2001and is part of the MET Museum collectionin New York.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London AFF Art Show</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/london-aff-art-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 17:32:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/london-aff-art-show/</guid>
      <description>Today we went to the Affordable Art Fair Hampstead. With over 100 galleries, it was a real pleasure. We saw some artists that we like and have seen in quite a few shows before, and discovered many new ones that were quite interesting.
In no particular order, my non-comprehensive list would include many artists, like:
 Adele Moreau Max Naylor Edvardas Racevicius Andy Wilx, etc  And the whole selection of Galleries like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art walk</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/art-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 18:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/art-walk/</guid>
      <description>Today I went on an &amp;ldquo;art walk&amp;rdquo;. Since the first Thursday of each month many art galleries in London remain open until late and host special events (an awesome initiative). Unfortunately I left quite late from the office, but I was working on a very special deal, so I could not leave earlier.
First I visited Boxpark Shoreditch.
 &amp;ldquo;Situated in the heart of east London’s fashion and art district, two floors of sixty shipping containers began as the world’s first pop up mall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCL MechEng Party</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/ucl-mecheng-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 15:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/06/ucl-mecheng-party/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday Mykal invited me to the University College London’s Mechanical Engineering Summer Session at Student Central.
It was a blast. A geek blast. Many featured projects, such as giant drone, hydrogen racing car prototype, alternative transportation infrastructure, robotic fish, or improved artificial heart valve design, along with entertainment: giant Scalextric racing, giant jinga, FIFA 15 tournament, impact simulators, pool, and a live concert by Cable Street Collective.
[Note: Congratulations on launching the UK’s first fully Open Access university press!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art, comics, poetry, food and music at Southbank Centre</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/art-comics-poetry-food-and-music-at-southbank-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 03:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/art-comics-poetry-food-and-music-at-southbank-centre/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I went to the Southbank Centrefor a number of reasons:
The Poetry Comics exhibition at the Saison Poetry Library(Royal Festival Hall) – the largest poetry library in the UK.-
Amazing as the library itself is, this exhibition co-curated by Chris McCabe and Chrissy Williams made it even more so. Featuring works by William Blake, Derik Badman, Bill Berkson / Joe Brainard, Kenneth Patchen, Oliver East, Kenneth Loch, Bianca Stone, Paul K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London Global Art Fair 2015</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/london-global-art-fair-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 15:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/london-global-art-fair-2015/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was invited to the London Global Art Fair 2015, which takes place May 21-23 at Olympia, Kensington, London.
With 150 galleries from 40 countries exhibiting works by over 500 artists, aged 25 (Nicole Wong and Vivien Zhang) to 93 (SH Raza) from 63 countries across the globe, in walling that would wrap over 13 times around the Royal Albert Hall, London Global Art Fair is as much a market as it is a celebration of creativity, art and culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture around the corner: the Tate Modern</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/culture-around-the-corner-the-tate-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 15:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/05/culture-around-the-corner-the-tate-modern/</guid>
      <description>Living in London means being surrounded by culture. For example, in less than 5 minutes’ walk from our apartment, and without even crossing the London Bridge, we have the Tate Modern(Britain`s national gallery of international modern art), Shakespeare’s Globe Theater, Southbank Centre(Europe’s largest centre for the arts: theatres, concert halls and a cutting edge art gallery presenting over 1200 events each year), and BFI Southbank(the leading repertory cinema in the UK, specialising in classic, independent and non-English language films, operated by the British Film Institute).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Named Technology Advisor to the Saint Charles Royal Academy of Fine Arts</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/named-technology-advisor-to-the-saint-charles-royal-academy-of-fine-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 20:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/named-technology-advisor-to-the-saint-charles-royal-academy-of-fine-arts/</guid>
      <description>On March 23rd I was named Technology Advisor to the 250 year old Saint Charles Royal Academy of Fine Arts by its 56th president, Dr. Manuel Muñoz.
The Royal Academy has the second largest and most important classical painting collection in Spain, after Madrid`s Museo del Prado.
Technology and Art are two of my passions, so combining the two sounds like a very exciting proposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Rome, March 7-12</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/in-rome-march-7-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 11:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/in-rome-march-7-12/</guid>
      <description>March 7th my wife and I traveled to Rome for a few days, since last summer’s cruise visit was too short and left us wanting more.
First we stayed at the Splendide Royal hotel. A “grand dame” with baroque decor and a fancy restaurant full of business people, rich Eastern Europe oligarchs and their lovers.
On the 9th we moved to the Kolbe Rome hotel, a monastery (part of it still in operation) located right next to the Circo Massimo and the Colosseo, where my in-laws joined us from Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art show in Las Atarazanas, March 6</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/art-show-in-las-atarazanas-march-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 23:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/art-show-in-las-atarazanas-march-6/</guid>
      <description>On March 6th we were invited, along with my wife, my friend the artist Claudio Zirotti, and his wife, to the opening of the art show “(Female) Art Owners” at the Atarazanas building in Valencia.
After the show we had a nice dinner in downtown Valencia, where we talked about the collective art exhibition I am putting together for next year in New York and London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A couple days in Malaga</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/a-couple-days-in-malaga/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 04:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/a-couple-days-in-malaga/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday 17 I arrived in Malaga (Spain) via Zurich for a couple of important business meetings. The meetings went really well, but I also enjoyed this very special city.
It had been a while since I was last in Malaga, so I went back to my favorite places: La Tetería teashop (right in front of the Picasso Museum), and the Contemporary Art Center CAC, where they have a small but always excellent and ever-changing display of works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to the MoMA member reception “The Tomorrow Now…”</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/invited-to-the-moma-member-reception-the-tomorrow-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 16:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/invited-to-the-moma-member-reception-the-tomorrow-now/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday my wife and I were invited to the MoMA member reception “The Forever Now: Contemporary Painting in an Atemporal World”, which opens officially tomorrow for the general public.
Obviously the rain did not prevent hordes of socialites to flock to MoMA and gather around one of the three open bars. But that was great because it gave us, and quite a few other &amp;ldquo;they must be on a How About We date&amp;rdquo; couples to visit some of the galleries without having to use our elbows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTO: a hyper-reading project</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/hto-a-hyper-reading-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 17:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/12/hto-a-hyper-reading-project/</guid>
      <description>Iban M. G. and Ben Martin have launched a writing project that breaks the boundaries of typical book in paper/digital format. Over the years I have seen many attempts to push the publishing world further. All commendable and appreciated. But so far I have not seen any project as ambitious as HTO.
Note: Literary review aside. I have not read the novel yet and, as a matter of fact, that`s irrelevant for the purposes of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My wife modeling in a photo shooting session for the &#34;I am Warrior&#34; book</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/my-wife-modeling-in-a-photo-shooting-session-for-the-i-am-warrior-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 20:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/my-wife-modeling-in-a-photo-shooting-session-for-the-i-am-warrior-book/</guid>
      <description>While I was in Peru, my wife sent me this picture of her modeling for photographer Shirin Tinati. The photographs will be featured in the upcoming &amp;ldquo;I am Warrior&amp;rdquo; book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pina Bausch dance company at the Howard Gilman Opera House Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/pina-bausch-dance-company-at-the-howard-gilman-opera-house-brooklyn-academy-of-music-bam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 20:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/pina-bausch-dance-company-at-the-howard-gilman-opera-house-brooklyn-academy-of-music-bam/</guid>
      <description>Between my trip to Mexico and the next one to Peru and Colombia, I spent a weekend in New York, and took the opportunity to go with my wife and her ex-husband to see &amp;ldquo;Kontakthof&amp;rdquo; by Pina Bausch dance company at the Howard Gilman Opera House Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM).
Before the show we went to a South African restaurant in Brooklyn called Madiba. Interesting mix of flavors and decor, great seafood imported directly from Mozambique, rustic atmosphere and somewhat &amp;ldquo;hipster&amp;rdquo; but not too much despite being in Brooklyn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Singapore, day 1: Clarke Quay, Asian Civilizations Museum, Singapore Art Museum, Chinatown and Little India</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/in-singapore-day-1-clarke-quay-asian-civilizations-museum-singapore-art-museum-chinatown-and-little-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 13:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/in-singapore-day-1-clarke-quay-asian-civilizations-museum-singapore-art-museum-chinatown-and-little-india/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: For some reason WordPress does not show all the pictures from that day (September 7), but you can access MORE PHOTOS here: https://www.flickr.com/photos/jcortell/sets/72157647043529148/I try not to have preconceived notions about a destination. But one can’t help to associate Singapore with high rises, luxury, order and cleanliness brought about by strict laws. As I was about to find out, there is plenty of all that, and reasons for it, but Singapore is also much more than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Tokyo, day 4: Roppongi art triangle and TV Asahi</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/in-tokyo-day-4-roppongi-art-triangle-and-tv-asahi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 13:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/in-tokyo-day-4-roppongi-art-triangle-and-tv-asahi/</guid>
      <description>My last day in Tokyo started with a n00b mistake: my phones, computer, calendar, and travel apps have different times (I have to keep tabs of New York, Valencia, and local time when I travel), that’s why I wear an awesome Casio solar atomic watch that has world time. But somehow I did not take into account the “international day line”, so I kept checking the time right… but not the date!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Tokyo, day 3: Tsukiji, Ueno, Ameyayokocho, and Shinjukku</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/in-tokyo-day-3-tsukiji-ueno-ameyayokocho-and-shinjukku/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 00:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/in-tokyo-day-3-tsukiji-ueno-ameyayokocho-and-shinjukku/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: For some reason WordPress does not show all the pictures from that day (September 6), but you can access more photos from that day here: https://www.flickr.com/photos/jcortell/sets/72157647279455961/I really meant to make it to Tsukiji fish market early. Not that I am that interested in the fish auction, but I want to see all the fish before it is cut and packaged or sold. That means getting there before 8am. So I set the alarm at 5am.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Tokyo, day 2: meeting, MOT, Imperial Palace, International Forum, Mitsubishi Ichigokan Museum, Tokyo Station, Character Street, and Tokyo SkyTree</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/in-tokyo-day-2-meeting-mot-imperial-palace-international-forum-mitsubishi-ichigokan-museum-tokyo-station-character-street-and-tokyo-skytree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 14:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/in-tokyo-day-2-meeting-mot-imperial-palace-international-forum-mitsubishi-ichigokan-museum-tokyo-station-character-street-and-tokyo-skytree/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Tokyo, day 1: Asakusa</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/in-tokyo-day-1-asakusa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 22:36:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/in-tokyo-day-1-asakusa/</guid>
      <description>The trip started with serious work.
During the flight from Newark to Narita there were many movies available in the personal entertainment system, some quite appealing since I would not easily have access to them; movies like a selection from Tribeca Film Festival, Bolt from the Blue, Genome Hazard, Horseplay, Samurai Hustle, The Monkey King, The Snow White Murder Case, or TV shows like Hanasaki Mai Speaks Out, Happy Camp, Secret Series, Tasty Road, Treasures of the Country… but I had access to electrical current outlet plug, so I slept 4 hours and worked on my laptop for 9 hours straight, with “Creep” by Radiohead playing in single repeat mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acquiring a work of art from the Guggenheim Museum in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/acquiring-a-work-of-art-from-the-guggenheim-museum-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 20:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/acquiring-a-work-of-art-from-the-guggenheim-museum-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>August 30th my wife and I acquired another work of art for our collection.
In this case we chose Colombian contemporary artist Carlos Motta: &amp;ldquo;Brief history of US Interventions in Latin America since 1946, 2005/14&amp;rdquo; (Guggenheim UBS MAP Purchase Fund 2014.39).
It is part of a series produced by Carlos Motta between 2005 and 2009 that present two chronologies of events in Latin America: one of U.S. interventions in the region since 1946, and one of the areas leftist guerrilla movements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graffiti show at 21 Precinct, New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/graffiti-show-at-21-precinct-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 19:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/graffiti-show-at-21-precinct-new-york/</guid>
      <description>On August 24th we were invited to the graffiti show at 21 Precinct.
The show ironically took place in the old 21st police Precinct (327 East 22nd Street) which, from 1863 and for 50 years was notorious for corruption and brutality in a [formerly]seedy part of town.
Curated by Robert Aloia &amp;amp; VNA Mag, it featured Adam Dare, Al Diaz, Amanda Marie, ASVP, Bad Pedestrian, Ben Angotti , Bill Claps, Bishop203, Bunny M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cicerone in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/cicerone-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 19:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/cicerone-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>These past 10 days I have been acting as a Cicerone for my sister and her partner. We really enjoyed having them in our Chelsea apartment. It was also a great opportunity to see NY from the eyes of a tourist again, which I sometimes fail to do since I have been living here for 3 years now.
There are a ton of anecdotes and discoveries behind these pictures, but you have to come to New York to experience them 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surprising Poblet restaurant in Valencia</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/surprising-poblet-restaurant-in-valencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 18:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/surprising-poblet-restaurant-in-valencia/</guid>
      <description>I admit it, there are still great restaurants in Valencia that I have not tried yet. But I am on a mission to change that.
While Samsharemains my all-time favorite despite its location, before we flew back to New York we tried the Michelin Guide starred Poblet restaurant.
I shouldnt be surprised, since I ate at Quique Dacostas El Poblet in Denia a few years ago and knew he was onto something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 days in Barcelona in July</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/3-days-in-barcelona-in-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 18:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/09/3-days-in-barcelona-in-july/</guid>
      <description>After the cruise my wife and I took our American relatives to Barcelona for 3 days. Nothing new for me there except the Sagrada Familia (yes, its true: after countless trips to Barcelona, I had never visited the amazing architectural wonder), although there are some things I can never get tired of, like Gaudis architecture, or Picasso`s museum.
Staying at the convenient and elegant Hotel España, next to the Liceu, was a great idea, made even better by their Martín Berasategui`s restaurant Fonda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Mediterranean Cruise Day 5: Tunisia</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/08/family-mediterranean-cruise-day-5-tunisia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 16:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/08/family-mediterranean-cruise-day-5-tunisia/</guid>
      <description>Knowing that the organized excursion to Tunisia was going to be exhausting, the kids did not come with us, so we had plenty of time to explore La Goulette, Sidi Bou Saïd, and the National Bardo Museum.
There is no doubt Sidi Bou Saïd is picturesque and nice to visit. Clearly Mediterranean in its colors and folklore, it reminds you of the Greek islands or even Ibiza (the old twon).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Lego cable management solution</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/08/my-lego-cable-management-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 21:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/08/my-lego-cable-management-solution/</guid>
      <description>After a month traveling throughout Europe (posts and pictures soon), I returned to New York and I needed to catch up with work. In order to be more productive I had to tackle the &amp;ldquo;cable jungle&amp;rdquo; challenge. Quick and easy (and cool) solution? LEGO!
Just attach some velcro to the back of a Lego, attach it to the edge of your desk, get some of your favorite figures, have them &amp;ldquo;hold their arms up&amp;rdquo;, and let them hold the USB and charger cables for you 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From VIP breakfast to party to another party... in a day</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/from-vip-breakfast-to-party-to-another-party...-in-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 20:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/from-vip-breakfast-to-party-to-another-party...-in-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday was a long day.
First I was invited to a VIP breakfast executive briefing and presentation by IBM at 7:45am. The event, in which IBM showcased their Watson technology and three partner companies talked about how they are leveraging NLP capabilities, lasted until 12:30pm, but I stayed for an extra hour for a meeting with an IBM executive.
Then I headed back to the office for 3 conference calls. By 7:00pm I was ready to go to the Social Radar startup launch party Stephanie and I had been invited to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIP pass for Basel art show and Amos Lee concert in Brooklyn</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/vip-pass-for-basel-art-show-and-amos-lee-concert-in-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 16:59:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/vip-pass-for-basel-art-show-and-amos-lee-concert-in-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>A friend got me a VIP pass for the 2014 Scope Basel Art Show(thank you, Jorge!). I had it all planned out: since I had a meeting in Stuttgart the day before, I could drive to nearby Basel, attend the VIP opening, and then fly back to New York. But the Stuttgart meeting was cancelled, so I changed my plane ticket, and returned to New York in time to go to the Amos Lee concert in Brooklyn`s Prospect Parkwith my wife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to Downtown modern&#43;contemporary art fair</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-to-downtown-modern-contemporary-art-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 20:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/invited-to-downtown-modern-contemporary-art-fair/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I was invited along with my wife by New York art gallery Lyons Wier Galleryto the Downtown modern+contemporary art fairheld at the 69th Regiment Armory in New York.
14,000 international collectors and art enthusiasts, over the course of four-days, gathering to discover paintings, sculptures, photographs and mixed-media works by over 600 artists from around the globe, exhibited by more than 50 international dealers. Seasoned as well as new collectors, curators, museum professionals, cultural foundations, dealers, art advisors and consultants enjoying works by mid-career and emerging artists as well as blue chip works by Picasso, De Kooning, Ruscha, Wesselmann, Rauschenberg, Warhol, Calder and other artists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I acquired a new piece of art from the New Museum New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/i-acquired-a-new-piece-of-art-from-the-new-museum-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 18:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/05/i-acquired-a-new-piece-of-art-from-the-new-museum-new-york/</guid>
      <description>For my wifes birthday I acquired a piece of art from &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.newmuseum.org/exhibitions/view/pawel-althamer&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.newmuseum.org/exhibitions/view/pawel-althamer&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Paweł Althamers &amp;ldquo;The Neighbors&amp;quot;, which run through April 13 at the New Museum in New York city.
 Since the early 1990s, Althamer (b. 1967 Warsaw, Poland) has established a unique artistic practice featuring an expanded approach to sculptural representation and consistently experimental models of social collaboration.
 It was great to discuss with a museum curator which piece to select (we agreed without a doubt), and it`s a pleasure to have this piece in the living room of our Chelsea apartment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold men destroy women</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/cold-men-destroy-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 16:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/cold-men-destroy-women/</guid>
      <description>Cold men destroy women,” my mother wrote me years later. “They woo them with something personable that they bring out for show, something annexed to their souls like a fake greenhouse, lead you in, and you think you see life and vitality and sun and greenness, and then when you love them, they lead you out into their real soul, a drafty, cavernous, empty ballroom, inexorably arched and vaulted and mocking you with its echoes— you hear all you have sacrificed, all you have given, landing with a loud clunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NY ComicCon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/ny-comiccon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 23:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/ny-comiccon/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5934418147899482241]
After going the other day with Maker Fairewith my parents, yesterday we went backto ComicCon. The usual: cosplay, crowds, swag&amp;hellip; FUN!!
UPDATE: here is a list of interesting links (artists, publishing houses, software, etc) we collected there.
Artists/Comics:
 Bill Plympton (studio, blog, store, tumblr), whom I have admired for many years, was there in person. Cool! Dylan (UpsideDownGrin) Rich Miller (FilthWorks) Selina Briggs (The Jelly Empire) The Gate Crashers  Studios/Stores:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banksy in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/banksy-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 16:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/10/banksy-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>Banksy is in New York for a month.
With the title &amp;ldquo;Better Out than In&amp;rdquo;, there is a blog, unofficial twitter account(along with the hashtag #banksyny) since it is not linked in the blog, and Instagram(really? Instagram?&amp;hellip; good grief; Im glad I dont have FaceBook so I can`t check if there is also a FB page)&amp;hellip; even a phone number (1 800 6564271) for each piece for which you can call and listen to a great message about (also accessible through the blog).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoHo surprises</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/soho-surprises/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 15:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/soho-surprises/</guid>
      <description>Lately I have been going to the office more than usual. The FDA inspection, then the PILOT health tech NY day (which was held in the coworking space where my office is), and a few other things have made me walk around SoHo quite a lot these days. Here are a few of the surprises I have encountered in the always colorful neighborhood:  The Pearl River Market store, right next door to my offices entrance, is &amp;quot;SoHos best kept secret&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And this is how the movie industry chokes itself</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/and-this-is-how-the-movie-industry-chokes-itself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 16:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/06/and-this-is-how-the-movie-industry-chokes-itself/</guid>
      <description>On May 13th, on my way to a friends apartment, we stumbled upon the set of Ben Stillers new movie right outside the 125th St. subway exit. They were filming in the middle of the street. What struck me the most was that one of the façades of the building had been completely redone (cast, cement, wood, paint&amp;hellip; it looked absolutely real and solid) for the film.
Really? No building façade will do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seen in the streets of NY until april 2013</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/seen-in-the-streets-of-ny-until-april-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 19:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/seen-in-the-streets-of-ny-until-april-2013/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5867858717493854113]
Now that the good weather seems to have arrived to NY, I will be walking more (more than my two hours daily that I already walk), and will be more willing to stop and take photographs of the crazy stuff one sees on the streets every day. Here are some images before April 2013.
(Note: the fun Einstein and Freud images were taken at Chelsea Market, from an exhibition by FunnyFoodArt).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sculpture drafts</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/sculpture-drafts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 19:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/05/sculpture-drafts/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5873034546116971265]
Here are some of my sculpture drafts that I hope some day will become real sculptures: &amp;ldquo;homeless snail: you and me&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;the lovers&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art or war?</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/04/art-or-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 16:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/04/art-or-war/</guid>
      <description>In the TV show Britain`s Got Talent, Hungarian shadow-theatre company Attraction shows with beauty the horror of war.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look at the data, just look at it!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/look-at-the-data-just-look-at-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 14:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/look-at-the-data-just-look-at-it/</guid>
      <description>Carna botnet offers us this amazing 24 hour visualization of relative IPv4 utilization observed using ICMP Ping requests.
Look at the data, just look at it! Dont you see peoples sleeping patterns, internet usage patterns, eating schedule habit, cultural differences, urban influence, regional inequalities&amp;hellip;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Triple art opening at MAD</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/triple-art-opening-at-mad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/triple-art-opening-at-mad/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we were invited to a triple art opening at the Museum of Art and Design(MAD):  After the Museum: &amp;ldquo;As artists, designers, and corporations have increasingly begun to stage exhibitions, lectures, and workshops modeled from the role of museums in the 20th century, current museum forms are increasingly called into question.&amp;rdquo; (March 12, 2013 to June 9, 2013) Wear it or Not: The exhibition features nearly 130 works from around the world, recently acquired by the MAD (March 12, 2013 to June 2, 2013) Against the Grain: Featuring nearly 90 installations, sculptures, furniture, and objects, the exhibition explores some of the most cutting-edge conceptual and technical trends in woodworking today (March 19, 2013 to September 15, 2013)  We also took the opportunity to re-visit &amp;ldquo;Playing with Fire&amp;rdquo;: 50 Years of Contemporary Glass (November 20, 2012 to August 25, 2013).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New City art fair: Japanese contemporary art</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/new-city-art-fair-japanese-contemporary-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 17:57:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/new-city-art-fair-japanese-contemporary-art/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5853820841512126817]
Today we went to New Cityart fair, Japanese contemporary art at hpgrp Galleryin Chelsea.
Almost everything, from Satoru Tamuras machines from Tezukayama Gallery (who also carried and showed works by Yayoi Kusama, Tomohiro Kato, and Takao Machiba), to the works at Art-U room (by Kazuo Shiraga, Atsuko Tanaka, Jiro Yoshihara, Sadamasa Motonaga, Chiyu Uemae, and Takesada Matsutani), the ones at hprgp (Hisaharu Motoda and Yuichi Hirako), to Satelites ART LAB (Shingo Iguchi, Ben Mori, and Anna Tsubaki), to Fuko Ueadas paintings on Gallery Kogure (along with Takahiro Hirabayashi, Hidenori Yamaguchi, Hiroyuki Matsuura, Takahiro Sanda, Yuwa Kato and Takato Yamamoto), to Gallery TEN (who carries Eishi Takaoka, Michio Kono, Jumpei Yamamuro, Masataka Kitamono, and Kazuko Kaneda), to Shusuke Ao`s installation on eitoeiko (who was also showing Shusuke Ao, Ichiro Irie, Yuki Yoshida and Junta Egawa), almost everything was outstanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At Independent art show</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/at-independent-art-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 23:12:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/at-independent-art-show/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5853532342637394897]
Today we have gone to the Independentart show at Center 548. Two floors (starts in the second floor, and the roof top only has a bar). The second floor has some, very few, interesting works. The third floor? Don`t even bother. From childish to improvised, without even being outsider or brut.
When I go to art shows like this I exit with a strange happy grin. The reason? I realize I still have a personal taste, and I know what I don`t like, no matter how crowded the space is, or if it is in Chelsea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inauguration of Edo Pop at Japan Society</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/inauguration-of-edo-pop-at-japan-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 23:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/inauguration-of-edo-pop-at-japan-society/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5853531658541752273]
Yesterday we were invited by Miwako Tezuka (domo arigato!) to the inauguration of Edo Popat Japan Society. It was wonderful!
Besides the classic and beautiful nishiki-e works by the masters Katsushika Hokusai (yes, Under the Wave off Kanagawa from the series Thirty-six Views of Mount Fuji, was there), Utagawa Hiroshige, Toshusai Sharaku, Toyota Hokkei, Utagawa Kunisada, Utagawa Kuniyoshi, and Suzuki Harunobu, there were contemporary works by graffiti artist Aiko, strikingly &amp;ldquo;Japanese&amp;rdquo; transparencies by Emily Allchurch, reinterpreted iconic portraits by Paul Binnie, political criticism in the work of Ishii Toru and Kazama Sachiko (amazing the large format Alas!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Image contemporary video art fair</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/moving-image-contemporary-video-art-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 22:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/moving-image-contemporary-video-art-fair/</guid>
      <description>[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5853065109523333633]
A couple days ago we were invited to the inauguration of Moving Imagecontemporary video art fair at the Terminal Stores (Waterfront Tunnel).
Interesting initiative, in a spectacular space, but as always some works were more appealing than others. This time, without a doubt, the only ones that I would definitely recommend are the ones shown by Ted Victoria(represented by Schröder Romero &amp;amp; Shredder). Very objectual, but quite imaginative and evocative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online access to the art shows I`ll miss</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/online-access-to-the-art-shows-ill-miss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 22:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/online-access-to-the-art-shows-ill-miss/</guid>
      <description>Since this week there are way too many art shows to visit, I`ll miss some, for sure.
Luckily, these events are getting better and better with their online access and info, and now we have Volta‘s catalogue online:We also have a good portion of Armory‘s show online, by Artsy.
Enjoy 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCOPE contemporary art show</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/scope-contemporary-art-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 21:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/03/scope-contemporary-art-show/</guid>
      <description>This is the Armory art weekin New York: Armory, SCOPE, Volta, Independent, Spring/Break, PooL, New City, Moving Image, ADAA, and Fountain.
My friend Jorge (thank you, Jorge!) gave us a VIP pass so we attended the inaugural party of the SCOPE contemporary art show.
I enjoyed it for the same reasons I enjoyed Volta last year: international, interesting, refreshing, criticism, political charge, varied&amp;hellip; There were too many interesting artists and works to mention, but in the photo gallery you have a few examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carnegie Hall concert Royal Stockholm Philharmonic Orchestra with Ray Chen</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/carnegie-hall-concert-royal-stockholm-philharmonic-orchestra-with-ray-chen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 12:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/carnegie-hall-concert-royal-stockholm-philharmonic-orchestra-with-ray-chen/</guid>
      <description>Tonight my friend Caterina has invited us (thank you Cat!!) to the Carnegie Hall concert: Royal Stockholm Philharmonic Orchestra featuring her friend, awesome violinist Ray Chen.
Performers
 Royal Stockholm Philharmonic Orchestra Sakari Oramo, Conductor Ray Chen, Violin Elin Rombo, Soprano  Program
 ROLF MARTINSSON Open Mind GRIEG &amp;ldquo;Våren,&amp;rdquo; Op. 34, No. 2 STENHAMMAR &amp;ldquo;Fylgia,&amp;rdquo; Op. 16, No. 4 STENHAMMAR &amp;ldquo;Flickan kom ifrån sin älsklings möte,&amp;rdquo; Op. 4, No. 1 BRUCH Violin Concerto No.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet VD</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/sweet-vd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 12:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/sweet-vd/</guid>
      <description>When a coconut milk seared wild salmon with basmati rice dinner at home ends with these three desserts/gifts, you know it is sweet:
– I received an incredible Japanese assorted wagashi box from Minamoto Kitchoan(with a beautiful Hokusai &amp;ldquo;The Great Wave off Kanagawa&amp;rdquo; Ukiyo-e card)
– I gave her Momofuku MilkBarassorted cookies (of course, with the &amp;ldquo;compost&amp;rdquo; in the assortment) and b`day truffles
– Plus Wholefoods Market Dark Chocolate Pear Almond (Lindt had that flavor, and the discontinued it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concert and museum opening night</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/concert-and-museum-opening-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 12:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/02/concert-and-museum-opening-night/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday we went to the &amp;ldquo;Tribute to Elliott Carter&amp;rdquo; concert at City University of New York Graduate Center (34th st &amp;amp; 5th Ave). A varied roster of (mostly) great (mostly) young performers, and Elliott Carters unmistakables compositions. I must admit it is not my favorite kind of music to say the least, but I do keep trying to expand my horizons. Always learning, or trying to. Experience, expose, try&amp;hellip; isnt that the hackers attitude?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My gift, goodbye or new beginning</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/my-gift-goodbye-or-new-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 19:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/my-gift-goodbye-or-new-beginning/</guid>
      <description>If the world ends today, this is my goodbye soundtrack gift to you.
If it doesn`t, tomorrow it will be the soundtrack of a waterfall, my new beginning gift to you.
In any case, the first composition that I ever share with the world (&amp;ldquo;Waterfall in the winter&amp;rdquo;). Straight from my open heart. Enjoy. Peace. Love. Happiness.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&amp;quot;Cat on a Hot Tin Roof&amp;quot; at Richard Rodgers Theatre with Scarlett Johansson</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/quotcat-on-a-hot-tin-roofquot-at-richard-rodgers-theatre-with-scarlett-johansson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 18:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/12/quotcat-on-a-hot-tin-roofquot-at-richard-rodgers-theatre-with-scarlett-johansson/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday Stephanie [thank you!] invited me to see &amp;ldquo;Cat on a Hot Tin Roof&amp;rdquo; at Richard Rodgers Theatre (Broadway, New York) with Scarlett Johansson.
Although I had seen the movie, perhaps because I was too young to understand, or perhaps because in the movie the plot is not as clear, the truth is that I enjoyed and understood Tennessee Williams play much better this time. And it has a much broader appeal than what I initially guessed (being a _Southern Gothic_ work).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>007 Skyfall at MoMA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/007-skyfall-at-moma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 21:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/11/007-skyfall-at-moma/</guid>
      <description>Although it may not be too obvious, I have been going through a few very hard weeks for several reasons. So someone who knows me well told me I should not be stupid, and should have fun. Let`s be it, then!
As part of their James Bond 50 years celebration, MoMA has been showing some of 007 movies in their collection (the largest by any museum in the world). So yesterday I was invited, and I of course invited Stephanie to be my guest, to the screening of the latest James Bond movie: &amp;ldquo;007 Skyfall&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Film screening at the portal of power and party at the Whitney</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/film-screening-at-the-portal-of-power-and-party-at-the-whitney/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 23:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/film-screening-at-the-portal-of-power-and-party-at-the-whitney/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday I was invited to the screening of the documentary &amp;ldquo;Gregory Crewdson Brief Encounters&amp;rdquo; at the Core Club(that has been called the &amp;ldquo;Portal of Power&amp;rdquo; by The New York Times, or &amp;ldquo;Where the 1 Percent Go to Lunch&amp;rdquo; by CNBC), with popcorn, M&amp;amp;Ms, wine bar and all.
Both Ben Shapiro and Gregory Crewdson(and his mother) were there introducing the film. But their shyness made them refuse a formal Q&amp;amp;A session, so to talk to them one had to go to the reception area after the film and mingle and chat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaos and Cosmos</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/chaos-and-cosmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 22:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/chaos-and-cosmos/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday I went to listen to Mitchell J. Feigenbaum and Albert J. Libchaber (mathematical physicists) discuss chaos theory at CUNY Graduate Center.
After that I went to McNally Jackson Books, a great book store in SoHo, and to the opening reception for “Rosemarie Trockel: A Cosmos&amp;rdquo;, at the New Museum, organized by Massimiliano Gioni, Associate Director and Director of Exhibitions, and Jenny Moore, Associate Curator, in collaboration with Rosemarie Trockel and Lynne Cooke, chief curator of the Museo Nacional Centro de Arte Reina Sofía, Madrid (Spain).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>319 Scholes art opening of &amp;quot;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 12:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/319-scholes-art-opening-of-quotcollect-the-wwworld-the-artist-as-archivist-in-the-internet-agequot/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I went to 319 Scholes to attend the art opening of &amp;ldquo;Collect the WWWorld: The Artist as Archivist in the Internet Age&amp;rdquo;.
Beyond the anecdotal post/pre hispter crowd, the exhibition itself is a sad celebration of noise. Which, in itself is as valid, or invalid, as any other starting point in the endless debate about art (more so in regards with contemporary, electronic, net, etc).
But it is its legitimization attempt, with research project, curator, catalogue, and international tour, which brings the debate to a whole different level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silver Wind: The Arts of Sakai Hoitsu</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/silver-wind-the-arts-of-sakai-hoitsu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 11:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/silver-wind-the-arts-of-sakai-hoitsu/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, October 2nd I was invited to the member`s viewing and reception of &amp;ldquo;Silver Wind: The Arts of Sakai Hoitsu&amp;rdquo; exhibition at Japan Society. This exhibition is the first American retrospective of Sakai Hoitsu (1761-1828), a samurai aristocrat turned Buddhist monk who dedicated his life to art and poetry. On exhibit there were also a few works by his chief pupil Suzuki Kiitsu, although I must admit the difference between the two is quite notable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections from NY Comic Con</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 09:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/reflections-from-ny-comic-con/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I went to NY Comic Con, like everyone else, I guess, with the idea of having fun, of experiencing first hand one of the &amp;ldquo;major events&amp;rdquo; that a true nerdy geek can attend. I also wanted to meet Cory Doctorow (although we actually ended up not meeting). It has been years since I last met him, and it was the perfect &amp;ldquo;excuse&amp;rdquo; to attend the conference.
When I arrived, I was really surprised to see the size of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>white skin</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/white-skin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/white-skin/</guid>
      <description>Autumn.
My skin falls and yours is not there.
I turn to the canvas, but its not color I want to smear your whiteness with. I face the white screen, but its not light that I seek.
I confront the blank page, but words will not bring solace.
Then my skin falls on the piano ivory.
Fingers sliding down each key.
Caresses that the air won`t keep.
The music was already playing in my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High culture might will numb you, how stay true? On &amp;quot;Graffiti&amp;quot; screening and panel at New Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 15:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/high-culture-might-will-numb-you-how-stay-true-on-quotgraffitiquot-screening-and-panel-at-new-museum/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I was invited to the New Musuem for the screening of &amp;ldquo;Graffiti – PostGraffiti&amp;rdquo; documentary and panel discussion.Your usual suspects were there. Besides the panelist (Pattie Astor, Fab Five Freddy, Lady Pink, and Lee Quinones), there were many old glories and a couple of aspiring bomber kids in the audience that I am sure were tagging walls late that night.
What started as a celebration, a remembrance, and a comunion, as the liturgy advanced ended up becoming a hurtful vindication and even a flat out purist attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It`s October and all I want is you</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 22:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/10/its-october-and-all-i-want-is-you/</guid>
      <description>Lying on the carpet, poetry book and pencil in hand, U2 in the background.
October
 October
And the trees are stripped bare
Of all they wear
What do I care
October
And kingdoms rise
And kingdoms fall
But you go on&amp;hellip;and on&amp;hellip;
 So many literal meanings: the fear of wearing-out (The Edge was considering leaving the band like his brother did before they were even called U2), the false sense of security arising from self-defeat (&amp;ldquo;What do I care&amp;rdquo;), moving on after a loss (both Bono and Larry had just lost their mothers), the high hopes and expectations arising from new democracies in Eastern Europe only to become despair and dissapointment, and eventually resilience, surviving, going on&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for Sugar Man</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/searching-for-sugar-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2012 14:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/09/searching-for-sugar-man/</guid>
      <description>Last Sunday I went to see Searching for Sugar Manbio/docu/picat Lincoln Plaza Theaters.
 Two South Africans set out to discover what happened to their unlikely musical hero, the mysterious 1970s rock ‘n` roller, Rodriguez.
 While the movieis a very good one, and the story quite powerful (not only a human story about an incredible musiciancalled Rodriguez, better than Bob Dylan if you allow me the heresy), there are two aspects that go well beyond the typical in this kind of documentary:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With Keanu Reeves and Chris Kenneally at &amp;quot;Side by side&amp;quot; premiere, MoMA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/with-keanu-reeves-and-chris-kenneally-at-quotside-by-sidequot-premiere-moma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 18:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/with-keanu-reeves-and-chris-kenneally-at-quotside-by-sidequot-premiere-moma/</guid>
      <description>The first one was the archiving and preservation of film. While an interesting debate by itself, it is not as important as it seemed to them, since, as I see it, technology will catch up and surpass the needs and expectations in a matter of very few years. Although a lot could be said about culture, preservation, archiving, formats, etc. Which leads us to&amp;hellip; The second one: it was a very brief moment, when upon the comment &amp;ldquo;somebody has to be the taste maker&amp;rdquo; by one of the producers being interviewed, Keanu, as interviewer said &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft, derivative works, parodies...</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 10:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/08/minecraft-derivative-works-parodies.../</guid>
      <description>Hugo sends me thisamazing song/video made in Minecraft. Of course, that leads to 10more, 14more&amp;hellip; there are so many!
When you make the tools available to the people, and allow them to create (in this case under the safe harbor of &amp;ldquo;parody&amp;rdquo;) wonderful things happen. Its NOT all about the money, profit, control... Its about imagination, art, creativity, culture. Thats how it happens: copying, re-using, mixing, adjusting, modifying... thats what creativity is really about (or did you think it was about &amp;ldquo;inventing&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;making unheard of things out of thin air&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My art projects and pictures</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/my-art-projects-and-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 10:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/my-art-projects-and-pictures/</guid>
      <description>For a few years I have accumulated art projects and pictures, in that oh-so-common delusion &amp;ldquo;one day I will start working on this and&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
Well, reality, resource constraints, day-to-day life&amp;hellip; are all excuses not to take ones passion and live it. So I am going to live it. How? I dont know. But the first step is to share, and to make accessible, my plans, ideas, and projects.
So HERE ARE MY ART PROJECTS (tumblr), and HERE ARE MY PHOTOGRAPHS (500px).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&amp;quot;All White Party&amp;quot; at the New Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/quotall-white-partyquot-at-the-new-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 10:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/quotall-white-partyquot-at-the-new-museum/</guid>
      <description>Five days ago, the New Museum invited me to the &amp;ldquo;All White Party&amp;rdquo;. It`s one of those events I would not normally go by myself, but Jane told me about the rooftop bar that only opens on weekends and during parties, so I decided to go and check it out. Plus, I was told it was the only chance I would have to see new yorkers dressed in white.
As it was to be expected, lot of people, quite a few &amp;ldquo;celebrities&amp;rdquo;, and 95% wearing white (with your typical &amp;ldquo;I am wearing black, to signal I am bad, or odd, or fun, or whatever&amp;rdquo;, two or three &amp;ldquo;ooops, I thought they were joking about the white – or I don`t have white clothes – and I am wearing my grey/orange shirt&amp;rdquo; and a petite blonde wearing black skirt and white top).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/july-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 00:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/july-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>Before I forget more (I am sure I am leaving out a lot), here is a little recap of things I`ve done, tried, or discovered in NY during July:
July 1st I went to Strand, my favorite bookstore, with its cool graffiti outside.
and then went to the &amp;ldquo;Exquisite Corpses: Drawing and Disfiguration&amp;rdquo; Party at the MoMA with Nebula.
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5761705319543704769]
The next day, in SoHo, I took a picture of this robot figure on my way to the gym.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incredible photo of last night`s &amp;quot;derecho&amp;quot; storm in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/incredible-photo-of-last-nights-quotderechoquot-storm-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 10:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/incredible-photo-of-last-nights-quotderechoquot-storm-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>Last night`s storm was, again, AMAZING. I was not exactly in a position to take a picture, &amp;ldquo;too concentrated on something else&amp;rdquo; (although I would have loved it), but this is a great shot by Ryan Brenizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting videos</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/interesting-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 22:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/interesting-videos/</guid>
      <description>Let me share some odd videos I have watched recently, thanks to Leaitrice and Patricia:
The famous &amp;quot;Sunscreen&amp;rdquo; music video(the text comes from an essaywritten in 1997 by Mary Schmich, a columnist at the Chicago Tribune, as a graduation speech for the class of `97) which gives some amazing advice for life. There is even a StarWars Version.
Drunk History: get some history students drunk, have them narrate historical events, while reenacting them&amp;hellip; more fun than it seems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two biggest Lytro pitfalls</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/two-biggest-lytro-pitfalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 11:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/two-biggest-lytro-pitfalls/</guid>
      <description>After playing with it for a while, beyond it limitations (light, format, movement&amp;hellip;) here are the two biggest pitfalls with the Lytro camera:
  It is still for Mac OSX only. They NEED to come out with Open Source / Free Software (both their software AND platform support for GNU/Linux).
  Picture library size and location. BIG unresolved issue.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poem: &amp;quot;Accompanied by your absence&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/poem-quotaccompanied-by-your-absencequot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 16:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/poem-quotaccompanied-by-your-absencequot/</guid>
      <description> Accompanied by your absence
I hear your skin calling.
Silently, still, I answer.
In the solitude of your presence
I remember sliding down your gaze
fearlessly falling into your void,
your being`s foyer.
Next to you, finally, I rest
dreaming and longing,
with the peace and tranquility that comes from
knowing me you.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay for Nebula`s new photobook</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/essay-for-nebulas-new-photobook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 13:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/essay-for-nebulas-new-photobook/</guid>
      <description>I have contributed an essay to the book (PDF soon available for free online, and for purchase in book format -a few sample images shown here-) of an exhibition I am curating. 3 years in the making, &amp;ldquo;Gaze, Reflexion, Fusion&amp;rdquo; is the highly poetical but politically charged work of one of the most interesting new photographers in the New York art scene: NEBULA.
From Tokyo to San Francisco, Madrid to Seoul, the Spanish photographer Nebula has traveled to 10 cities in 4 countries in order to find inspiration and the right images (somethimes a fleeting reflexion of it) to bring to life what she feels about art, identity, apropriationism, feminism, and psychoanalysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning bugs in Central Park instead of Oliver Stone debate</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/lightning-bugs-in-central-park-instead-of-oliver-stone-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 03:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/07/lightning-bugs-in-central-park-instead-of-oliver-stone-debate/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was invited to a member`s only screening of Born on the Fourth of July (1989) and post-screening discussion with Oliver Stone and Ron Kovic at MoMA Film Theater 1.
What do I do instead? I end up at Central Park, with lightning bugs around me. I think I am still there. For some reason, I have gotten trapped there, and I do not want to leave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critics and artists</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/critics-and-artists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 17:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/critics-and-artists/</guid>
      <description>When art critics get together they talk about Form and Structure and Meaning. When artists get together they talk about where you can buy cheap turpentine.
 Picasso</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun days, June 1st and 2nd</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/fun-days-june-1st-and-2nd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 12:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/06/fun-days-june-1st-and-2nd/</guid>
      <description>Trying to catch up with fun days, here is what June 1st looked like: first some crêpes for lunch at Vive La CrepeUnion Square (delicious crêpes and funny chair backs embedded in concrete).
Then, after browsing around at Beacons Closet&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, and going to &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.tibethouse.us/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.tibethouse.us/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Tibet House&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; to gather info (Tuesdays meditation classes, here I go), it was finally time to visit Rubin Museum of Art. While Modernist Art from India, Illuminated, and Casting the Divine were very interesting and delightful, I must admit the nerdy geek in me enjoyed Hero, Villain, Yeti like a real kid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry Elephants</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/angry-elephants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 21:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/angry-elephants/</guid>
      <description>via APM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Kagemu video</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/awesome-kagemu-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 21:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/awesome-kagemu-video/</guid>
      <description>Although I can not embed it (the author has disabled the option) this videoby Japanese performer and CGI artist Kagemu is really worth looking at. Enjoy. (Via Nebula).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with my new Lytro</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/playing-with-my-new-lytro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 18:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/playing-with-my-new-lytro/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I received my new Lytrocamera. Although it is an incredible technology, and allows things that were unthinkable until now, so far I am mixed.
Pros:
 Compact and discreet Extremely easy to use New ways of taking pictures Novelty Supercool &amp;ldquo;focus later&amp;rdquo;  Cons:
 You have to get used to a different way of thinking and framing a shot (square! and distance) Low performance under low light (although better than my crappy Samsung Galaxy IIS camera)  Check out this online gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoHo (window)shopping</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/soho-windowshopping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 17:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/soho-windowshopping/</guid>
      <description>Some people enjoy shopping. Some enjoy the action, other the object, others the fantasy of being able to &amp;ldquo;acquire&amp;rdquo; that which they feel (or society made them feel) they &amp;ldquo;lack&amp;rdquo; (beauty, strength, appeal&amp;hellip; whatever).
Last week, while at the SoHo, I found myself enjoying window shopping. The design. Pure art. Beauty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Saturday: MET and Madison Sq. Park</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/last-saturday-met-and-madison-sq.-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 17:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/last-saturday-met-and-madison-sq.-park/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday I went to the MET for the symposium &amp;ldquo;Michelangelo and His World in the 1490s&amp;rdquo;. Presented by some of the most distinguished Michelangelo`s scholars, there was a lot of in-depth info on this very exceptional artist. Here are some of the most curious trivia I learned:
 He was an exceptional painter and art forger from a very early age (when he was 12 years old he forged and smoked to make it look old, church paintings) and that`s why his father enrolled in an art studio at 13, even though the minimum age was 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Queens Museum of Art</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/queens-museum-of-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 13:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/queens-museum-of-art/</guid>
      <description>Last Thursday I went to Queens Museum of Art for a talk about NYFA Immigrant Art Project.
Besides interesting art, and an interesting (although basic) talk, here are some things that caught my attention (and yes, that IS a model of the park inside the elevator!): </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Monique Péan`s studio</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/in-monique-p%C3%A9ans-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 10:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/in-monique-p%C3%A9ans-studio/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday I went to the studio of jewelry designer Monique Péan, with Margot Norton (curatorial associate, New Museum, New York).
While it was interesting (in a &amp;ldquo;makes me sick but I need to learn this even if it seems impossible to achieve without the right connexions&amp;rdquo; forensics approach) to hear her perfectly polished &amp;ldquo;politically correct and marketing saavy&amp;rdquo; bio and artist statement, what really interested me was the striking beauty of fossilized ivory and minerals from the Artic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A definition of art</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/a-definition-of-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 10:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/05/a-definition-of-art/</guid>
      <description>Seeking the definition of Art for a while, I can not find one that satisfies me, nor I seem to be able to reach one by myself. Here is as far as I have been able to get so far:
 Art is giving the opportunity of being to something that would never be
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese dance at Japan Society and dinner at Sakagura</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/japanese-dance-at-japan-society-and-dinner-at-sakagura/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 12:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/japanese-dance-at-japan-society-and-dinner-at-sakagura/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went to Japan Society for the Kota Yamazaki/Fluid hug-hug (glowing)dance.
I must admit, regardless of having read the description and program, that I did not understand anything at all. Not even after hearing Kota Yamazaki explain his work after the show. So, I did the only thing a reasonable person can do when approaching art and not understanding: feel.
While the apparent lack of linear narrative or character identification makes it hard to approach, the dancers movements (rather than the much touted but ineffective light design), unobtrusive (and minimal) sound landscape by Kohji Setoh, and the elegant twist with the hanging wooden props becoming physical space at the end, played together surprisingly well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guggenheim curator tour and SVA computer arts</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/guggenheim-curator-tour-and-sva-computer-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 11:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/guggenheim-curator-tour-and-sva-computer-arts/</guid>
      <description>On Friday, at lunch time, I went to the Guggenheim to meet Susan Thompson, Curatorial Assistant, for a tour of Francesca Woodman exhibition.
Although Francesca Woodman`s photographs are undeniably subtle and portray the mind of a troubled young woman (body, space, self, disgust, identity, etc), it is a pity she took her life so early, leaving us with what is obviously a truncated body of work, one that begins, explores, promises&amp;hellip; but never concludes because death found her first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At MoMA: New Vision exhibition, The Modern restaurant, and a russian silent film about celebrities</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-moma-new-vision-exhibition-the-modern-restaurant-and-a-russian-silent-film-about-celebrities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 11:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-moma-new-vision-exhibition-the-modern-restaurant-and-a-russian-silent-film-about-celebrities/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday, given that the Anarchist Art Festival seemed a little weak, I decided to spend the day at the MoMA (Museum of Modern Art, New York).
First, a nice tour of &amp;ldquo;The Shaping of New Visions: Photography, Film, Photobook&amp;rdquo; exhibition (Edward Steichen Photography Galleries, third floor) by Dr. Elizabeth Cronin, assistant curator of photography at MoMA and NYPL. This exhibition, covering the period from 1910 to today, offers a critical reassessment of photographys role in the avant-garde and neo-avant-garde movements—with a special emphasis on the mediums relation to Dada, Bauhaus, Surrealism, Constructivism, New Objectivity, Conceptual, and Post-Conceptual art—and in the development of contemporary artistic practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A tour of selected pieces at MET Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/a-tour-of-selected-pieces-at-met-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 12:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/a-tour-of-selected-pieces-at-met-museum/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I went to the MET, and took a tour of their &amp;ldquo;highlights&amp;rdquo; with a curator, stopping at a few particularly interesting pieces in their collection. Here are some of them, and what makes them particularly interesting:
 In the Greek/Roman hall, the sculpture of fabric: while the greek sculptors portrayed the idealized human figure (even turning it into a mathematical formula) and the romans followed that tradition, fabric was the only part that was sculpted as it was, from thick to almost transparent, with embroidery, motifs, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian film at MoMA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/russian-film-at-moma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 13:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/russian-film-at-moma/</guid>
      <description>After j-CATION and having lunch at Mr. Ks&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (one of the best Chinese restaurants in Manhattan), yesterday I went to &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.moma.org/visit/calendar/film_screenings/14846&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.moma.org/visit/calendar/film_screenings/14846&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;MoMA&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; Film to see Gosfilmofonds copy of the 1935 USSR film Loss of the Sensation (87 min.), directed by Aleksandr Andriyevsky.
Virtually unseen in the U.S., Andriyevskys liberal film version of Karel Capeks popular 1920 play, R.U.R. (in which the notion of robots was introduced), the movie tells the story of Jim Ripple, an engineer, who invents robots controlled by saxophones and radio signals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At Deco Japan exhibit and excellent soba lunch (SEO)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-deco-japan-exhibit-and-excellent-soba-lunch-seo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 16:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-deco-japan-exhibit-and-excellent-soba-lunch-seo/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, since I had to go to the Japan Society to take care of some business, I took the opportunity to visit the Deco Japan: Shaping Art and Culture, 1920–1945 exhibition (I was invited to the opening, but I could not make it that day).
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5730180317126910177]
 Curated by Dr. Kendall Brown, Deco Japan: Shaping Art and Culture, 1920–1945 subtly conveys the complex social and cultural tensions in Japan during the Taisho and early Showa periods through dramatically designed examples of metalwork, ceramics, lacquer, glass, furniture, jewelry, sculpture and evocative ephemera such as sheet music, posters, postcards, prints and photography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In 3D with Firefox`s new TILT inspector</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/in-3d-with-firefoxs-new-tilt-inspector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 12:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/in-3d-with-firefoxs-new-tilt-inspector/</guid>
      <description>Lego web design, anyone? 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curators` thoughts</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/curators-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 00:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/curators-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>On September 28, 2011, Hou Hanru, Director of Exhibitions and Public Programs at the San Francisco Art Institute said on a lecture (Curator`s Perspective) in New York:
 I think the worst exhibition in the world is the exhibition that is organized like a book. We see this a lot, an exhibition that takes the artwork as an illustration of a concept. I think an exhibition is not necessary for this: frankly, it`s too expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marvel Marathon</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/marvel-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 23:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/marvel-marathon/</guid>
      <description>From the #thisIsHowItsDone (not the movie adaptations, but special events to make people go more to the movie theaters) department, here is an awesome initiative from AMC movie theaters:
Get ready to watch the greatest Marvel movie event ever held at your local AMC Theatre on May 3rd! Experience THE ULTIMATE MARVEL MARATHON with six movies on one epic day. Watch the heroes’ stories unfold as they assemble for the midnight premiere of The Avengers 3D!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tatsumi at the MoMA Film</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/tatsumi-at-the-moma-film/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 23:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/tatsumi-at-the-moma-film/</guid>
      <description>Tonight I went and see Tatsumiat the MoMA Film (Theater 2), a 2011 animation film from Singapore, directed by Eric Khoo, with the voice of Yoshihiro Tatsumi (who brought innovation to Japanese comics through works of social commentary aimed at an adult audience in postwar Japan in the late 1950s). A Drifting Life, Tatsumi’s epic graphic novel memoir, forms the foundation for the film.
Interesting the unavoidable paralel one can draw between Italys neorealism postwar cinema and Tatsumis works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversation with a Curator and Dawn of Egyptian Art at the MET</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/conversation-with-a-curator-and-dawn-of-egyptian-art-at-the-met/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 22:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/conversation-with-a-curator-and-dawn-of-egyptian-art-at-the-met/</guid>
      <description>This morning I have been at the MET. First I took advantage of the invitation to preview the Dawn of Egyptian Artexhibition which will be on display April 10–August 5, 2012.
While there were many remarkable pieces (for several reasons) in the exhibition, this coyote figure completely captivated me. The legs position denote movement, which is uncommon in animal depictions of the later eras. The reason being that as art evolved, and became &amp;quot;institutionalized&amp;quot; in Ancient Egypt, it adhered more closely to standards and canons, loosing some if the earlier works creativity and freedom, such as this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the MoMA member gallery talk: Cindy Sherman</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-the-moma-member-gallery-talk-cindy-sherman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 17:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-the-moma-member-gallery-talk-cindy-sherman/</guid>
      <description>Today I went to one of MoMA`s members-only gallery talks. This one was about their currentCindy Shermanexhibition(great website, by the way).
Rather than rambling on about Cindy Sherman`s interesting work (an obvious reference to identity, stereotypes, social criticism, art depiction, etc, with her easily recognizable periods and themes), on which there are many articlesthese days, here are some anecdotes:
 Photography is not allowed (I really hate it when museums do not allow photography), so why do they place QRs (particularly when the phone coverage is quite bad)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the Independent Art Spaces Symposium and Art Spaces Directory Launch</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-the-independent-art-spaces-symposium-and-art-spaces-directory-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 14:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-the-independent-art-spaces-symposium-and-art-spaces-directory-launch/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I went to the Independent Art Spaces Symposium and Art Spaces Directory Launchat the New Museum.
I purchased the Art Spaces Directory last week, and I believe it is an excellent work, useful informative, needed. But the symposium was&amp;hellip; sad, to say the least: a bunch of gallery (art-spaces) curators, unable to play a PowerPoint (sic&amp;hellip; makes me sick), and regurgitating exhibit picture after exhibit picture while vomiting names after names of artists, collectives and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the best tea ceremony place in NY: Cha-An</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-the-best-tea-ceremony-place-in-ny-cha-an/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 14:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/at-the-best-tea-ceremony-place-in-ny-cha-an/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday I went to Cha-an. In short: a cute japanese restaurant, good food, excellent desserts, and what seems to be the best Japanese Tea Ceremony in NY (ate there, but will have to do the ceremony some other day). Definitely to the &amp;ldquo;must&amp;rdquo; list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visit to the Madeline Weinrib studio</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/visit-to-the-madeline-weinrib-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 12:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/visit-to-the-madeline-weinrib-studio/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday I visited the studio of Madeline Weinribon 5th Ave., New York.
Located on an impressive loft, her new studio (it used to be located at her apartment above a small museum in SoHo) is, as one would have imagined, full of decorative and inspirational elements, plus lots and lots of fabric samples, books and pictures.
In an informal conversation, Madeline explained her move from painter to fabric designer in 1997 (although she &amp;ldquo;forgot&amp;rdquo; to mention the connexion to her great-grandfather`s company), her world-wide network of artisans and suppliers, and her obvious historical design pattern &amp;ldquo;inspirations&amp;rdquo; (curious how she considers large manufacturers are &amp;ldquo;ripping her off&amp;rdquo; by copying &amp;ldquo;her patterns&amp;rdquo;, when her work is such an obvious &amp;ldquo;appropriation&amp;rdquo; from well known historical-cultural patterns such as the zig-zag or the muslim interlocks, as she describes it in this interview).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madison Square Garden: the LArc~en~Ciel concert</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/madison-square-garden-the-larc~en~ciel-concert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 23:16:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/madison-square-garden-the-larc~en~ciel-concert/</guid>
      <description>The Japan Society invited me to L`Arc~en~Cielconcert at the Madison Square Gardenlast night, so there I went.
L`Arc~en~Cielis a Japanese rock band formed in 1991 in Osaka. The group has sold over 13 million albums, and 16 million singles. Currently on a world tour (obviously last night in NY), their upcoming London and Jakarta concerts are already sold out, and their NY concert was bigger than expected.
Given their JPop-rock sound, no wonder the Madison Square Garden was almost fully packed with Japanese, although there were more than teenagers, like the &amp;ldquo;respectable moms&amp;rdquo; in their 50s, 3 rows ahead of me, who could not stop swinging and laughing and singing, or the guy next to me, there with his wife, who waited patiently for the concert to start while reading manga in his iPad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soba from a master: Soba Totto`s Shuichi Kotani</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/soba-from-a-master-soba-tottos-shuichi-kotani/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 12:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/soba-from-a-master-soba-tottos-shuichi-kotani/</guid>
      <description>Last night, after the MoMA party, I went to have dinner at Soba Totto.
It`s great that NY has so many excellent Japanese restaurants. This was no exception. Kotani sensei is a true master in the ancient art of soba making:More videos here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MoMA members night party and the economy of access as identity</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-moma-members-night-party-and-the-economy-of-access-as-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 11:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-moma-members-night-party-and-the-economy-of-access-as-identity/</guid>
      <description>Last night I attended the members night party at the Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) in New York.
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5723677090335639153]
The &amp;ldquo;party&amp;rdquo; was, as most &amp;ldquo;parties&amp;rdquo; in the USA: drinks, and people. Thats basically it. The music was soft enough that it was barely perceivable (unlike the New Museums party, where DJs try to make it impossible to talk to the person next to you).
So, why all the fuss? Why go to a &amp;ldquo;party&amp;rdquo; that has basically nothing to offer in terms of &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At a WhiteBox NY exhibition closing party</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/at-a-whitebox-ny-exhibition-closing-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 15:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/at-a-whitebox-ny-exhibition-closing-party/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I attended WhiteBox`s exhibition closing party. The invitation said:
 Author and curator Raul Zamudioin conversation with Mookie Tenembaum.
Please join us at White Boxfor the closing reception of DISILLUSIONISM, and to engage in a stimulating conversation between Raul Zamudio and Mookie Tenembaum at 8pm sharp. Mookie will be presenting his new artist book, Paranoia. Malbec wines and truffles will be served.
 Although I am grateful for the invitation, and it sure was an interesting event, some things just beg to be commented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whitney Biennial 2012</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/whitney-biennial-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 23:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/whitney-biennial-2012/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday evening I attended the Whitney Museum of American Contemporary Art`s Biennial 2012exhibition. I had lunchin a hurry, worried that I would not have time to visit the whole exhibition (since I only had a few hours). How wrong I was. Let`s just say it was sooooo disappointing(at least for someone, like me, who knows almost nothing about art), that I was left with a feeling of wonder. Not about the works, but how, who, and why, did they decide to include it in the exhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel discussion about art collecting at Asia Society</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/panel-discussion-about-art-collecting-at-asia-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 22:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/panel-discussion-about-art-collecting-at-asia-society/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday morning I went to the Asia Society for a panel discussiontitled: &amp;ldquo;The Future of the Past – Collecting Ancient Art in the 21st Century&amp;rdquo; presented by the American Committee for Cultural Policyin conjunction with Asia Week. The panelists included:
 Naman Ahuja, Professor of Indian Art and Architecture, Jawaharlal Nehru University, Delhi, India Kate Fitz Gibbon, attorney and author, former member of the Cultural Property Advisory Committee to the President Kurt A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Museum curators talk</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/new-museum-curators-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 18:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/new-museum-curators-talk/</guid>
      <description>Saturday evening I went to the talk_Independent Curators International and the New Museum present The Curators Perspective: Rosina Cazali_. Although there was an interesting &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.sothebys.com/en/auctions/2012/fine-classical-chinese-paintings-n08835/exhibitions.html&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.sothebys.com/en/auctions/2012/fine-classical-chinese-paintings-n08835/exhibitions.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;talk at Sothebystitled &amp;ldquo;_Masters of the Ming and Qing: Chinese Paintings and Calligraphy at Sothebys_&amp;quot; by Arnold Chang, before their Fine Classical Chinese Paintings exhibition and auction. I dont know how the Sotheby`s lecture went, but here is what I saw and heard at the New Museum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The problem with encyclopedic approach to teaching: lecture at MET</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-problem-with-encyclopedic-approach-to-teaching-lecture-at-met/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-problem-with-encyclopedic-approach-to-teaching-lecture-at-met/</guid>
      <description>Friday I attended the Annual Lecture on the Arts of South and Southeast Asia at the NY Metropolitan Museum of Art (MET), delivered by Crispin Branfoot, School of Oriental and African Studies, University of London. His lecturewas titled: &amp;ldquo;Making Madurai: Temple Arts in Early Modern South India&amp;rdquo;.
Dr. Branfoot is, I am sure, a world renowned expert, and the MET has some wonderful education programs. And this one in particular was filled to capacity, such that I had to watch it from an adjacent &amp;ldquo;study room&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LES Gallery walk and Volta NY 2012</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/les-gallery-walk-and-volta-ny-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 20:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/les-gallery-walk-and-volta-ny-2012/</guid>
      <description>So, Sunday came and my feet were already trembling scared in anticipation of another art overdose. Let`s go!
I spent the morning walking around some of Manhattans Lower East Side (LES) galleries with artist &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://leewells.org/home/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://leewells.org/home/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Lee Wells&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. We visited &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.roostergallery.com/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.roostergallery.com/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Rooster Gallery&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.anastasia-photo.com/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.anastasia-photo.com/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Anastasia Photo&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://bridgegalleryny.com/home.html&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://bridgegalleryny.com/home.html&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Bridge Gallery&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.maysongallery.com/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.maysongallery.com/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Mayson Gallery&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://lesleyheller.com/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://lesleyheller.com/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Lesley Heller Workspace&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, and &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.scaramoucheart.com/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armory Art Show 2012 NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/armory-art-show-2012-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 19:28:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/armory-art-show-2012-ny/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday I went to The Armory Show 2012. So many galleries, so little time. While everybody was talking about Marina Abramovic’s _Bed for Human Use _performance, Theaster Gates commissioned Pier 94 café piece, or Michael Riedel’s installation at New York’s David Zwirner’s booth (forget about the Nordic spaces)... I found other works much much more interesting. But thats what makes art`s subjectivity (apparently not so subjective) so appealing.
Although, for the first time I found myself (and was ment to be that way) inside a piece of exhibited art by Michelangelo Pistolettoat Galleria Continua‘s booth (I am not showing it here because it will soon be published in a book).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art at MAD NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/art-at-mad-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 15:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/art-at-mad-ny/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday I went to the New York Museum of Arts and Design (MAD). Honestly, I wasn`t expecting much, but&amp;hellip; on the contrary, what a nice surprise!
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5718498290671972801]
From Japanese exquisite design and art (subtle, delicate, and sensitive beauty that never ceases to soothe your soul) in &amp;ldquo;Beauty in all things&amp;rdquo;, to the awesomely curated &amp;ldquo;Swept Away: Dust, Ashes, and Dirt in Contemporary Art and Design&amp;rdquo;, to the amazing &amp;ldquo;Glasstress New York&amp;rdquo;, the whole museum was a joy to visit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sarah Sze`s Infinite Line en Asia Society</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/sarah-szes-infinite-line-en-asia-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 01:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/sarah-szes-infinite-line-en-asia-society/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I had the enourmous pleasure of going to see Sara Sze‘s Infinite Lineat Asia Society.
Definitely a pleasure, an exhibition not to be missed, and true to Sarah`s aim: works that a photograph can not capture (not that the copyright zealots of the Asia Society would let you take pictures anyway).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context in Art as Political Discussion: Amalia Pica`s Venn Diagrams</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/context-in-art-as-political-discussion-amalia-picas-venn-diagrams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 19:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/context-in-art-as-political-discussion-amalia-picas-venn-diagrams/</guid>
      <description>One of the multiple interesting pieces currently being exhibited at the New Museums &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://cortell.net/blog/2012/03/the-ungovernables-party-at-new-museum/&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://cortell.net/blog/2012/03/the-ungovernables-party-at-new-museum/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;The Ungovernables&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; is Amalia Picas Venn Diagrams. The text under this piece says:
 During the period of dictatorship in Argentina in the 1970s, gatherings of citizens were closely monitored as they were considered a threat to the government. At the same time group theory and venn diagrams were banned from primary school programs as they could provide a model for subversive thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ungovernables party at New Museum</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-ungovernables-party-at-new-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 19:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/the-ungovernables-party-at-new-museum/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was invited to The UngovernablesTriennial leap year cocktail by-invitation-only party at the New Museum.
After a long line on the street, under the rain and cold wind (no wonder I have a cold now), the party started at 7:30pm in the main lobby: DJ, cocktails, and fluorescent rubber bands for a crowd eager to see and be seen.
Not one to particularly enjoy mingling and parties, I went upstairs to see the exhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At MoMA PS1 for K-HOLE2 Release</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/at-moma-ps1-for-k-hole2-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 01:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/at-moma-ps1-for-k-hole2-release/</guid>
      <description>Today I was invited tothe MoMA PS1 for K-HOLE#2 Release. Young people, &amp;ldquo;Brooklyn artsy&amp;rdquo;, holding beers and beards, with the careless attitude that the PS1 requires: either I dont get it or I do, but in any case, it wont show.
There were many works on display, too many (and too complex or infuriatingly simple) to comment here. What was definitely not worth mentioning, from my ignorant point of view, was the Alterazioni Video &amp;ldquo;The New Cinema Event&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Art in NY: from hairdressing to butoh</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/japanese-art-in-ny-from-hairdressing-to-butoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 01:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/japanese-art-in-ny-from-hairdressing-to-butoh/</guid>
      <description>New York is full of Japanese art, and I am not only referring to the Asia Week NYor the architecture (New Museums SANAA, MoMAs Yoshio Taniguchi, Japan Societys Junzo Yoshimura…), interior design (Megus Yasumichi Morita, Morimotos Tadao Ando, Louis Vuittons Jyun Aoki…), sculpture (Red Cube`s Isamu Noguchi…), art collections (MET, MoMA, Japan Society, Morgan, Rubin…), food (Yasuda, Kajitsu, Minamoto Kichoan…), or shops (Makari, Toy Tokyo, JCC…).
Yesterday I had a chance to see two rare forms of Japanese art in NY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&amp;quot;Stuck&amp;quot; in Ottawa (Canada) for a week</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/quotstuckquot-in-ottawa-canada-for-a-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 19:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/quotstuckquot-in-ottawa-canada-for-a-week/</guid>
      <description>Due to my US Visa process (which was soooo long and curious that it requires a separate post), I have been &amp;ldquo;stuck&amp;rdquo; in Ottawa (Canada) for a week.
Sure, Canada would not be one of my priority travel destinations in the winter, particularly if (like me) you cant ski or ice skate. But since I am here, lets make the best of it: The National Gallery, Museum of Civilizations, Museum of War, Winterlude, and a few lovely food places (such as The Tea Store, Memories, or Oh So Good) and a bunch of mediocre ones, while staying in a very nice hotel/castle(with heated indoors pool and gym), will do the trick 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The smallest art gallery in NY</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/the-smallest-art-gallery-in-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 05:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/the-smallest-art-gallery-in-ny/</guid>
      <description>This morning I walked by the smallest art gallery in NY, 125windowgallery, on 47th between 3rd and Lexington Avenue:
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,111219615350942087056,1,64c,center]
The best thing about that gallery is that you do not need to &amp;ldquo;go in&amp;rdquo; 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artist that still don`t get it</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/artist-that-still-dont-get-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 05:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/artist-that-still-dont-get-it/</guid>
      <description>This is not going to be one of those deep, thoughtful, analytical posts (as if I ever wrote one 😉 ). I just need to vent.
Last Saturday, in Prince Street, in the middle of Soho, a man (I will not mention his name, because as you will see, he does not deserve publicity) was handing out CDs. As with anything digital, I felt the urge to find out more, so I took it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almodovar and SGAE force cancellation of film screenings at NY Library</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/almodovar-and-sgae-force-cancellation-of-film-screenings-at-ny-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 17:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/almodovar-and-sgae-force-cancellation-of-film-screenings-at-ny-library/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I went to the New York Public Library to see Pedro Almodovars &amp;quot;Talk to her&amp;quot;, as part of a &amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;https://www.nypl.org/blog/2011/12/06/films-pedro-almodovar&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;https://www.nypl.org/blog/2011/12/06/films-pedro-almodovar&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;series&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; of Almodovars films screenings in the NYPL. But, to my surprise, the screening (and remainder ones) had been cancelled.
I talked to the person in the information desk, and she told me that the collecting society (that would be the despicable SGAE, which does not even deserve a link in my blog) and Almodovar`s Production company (El Deseo Producciones) had raised what they had previously been asking for as royalties or compensation for the (free) screening of the (not in movie theater) films, and the amount they were now asking was so high, the NYPL could not afford it, so they had to cancel the screenings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disappearing Chrysler and &amp;quot;Spanish&amp;quot; Empire State</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/disappearing-chrysler-and-quotspanishquot-empire-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/02/disappearing-chrysler-and-quotspanishquot-empire-state/</guid>
      <description>Excuse to try a new photo plug-in for WP:
First photo: the Chrysler building as seen from my living room window.
Second photo: same thing on a foggy day&amp;hellip; Building gone! (no Image Editing here).
Third photo: the Empire State Building, from the living room, decorated with &amp;ldquo;Spanish flags colors&amp;rdquo;
[mudslide:picasa,0,111219615350942087056,5703177154854937889]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArtHack Exhibit closing party in Brooklyn</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 22:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/arthack-exhibit-closing-party-in-brooklyn/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday I went to the ArtHack Exhibitclosing party at 319 ScholesSt, Brooklyn (New York).
Located in an industrial complex in Brooklyn, at night, loooong two blocks from the subway, graffiti all over, small door&amp;hellip; that gave way to heaven: young (I was the oldest hacker in that space, but I did not feel that way) energetic happy people tinkering with technology and proudly showing their &amp;ldquo;toys&amp;rdquo; (hacks, mashups, creations, or whatever).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antony and the Johnsons at Radio City Music Hall... indescribable</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/antony-and-the-johnsons-at-radio-city-music-hall...-indescribable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 16:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/antony-and-the-johnsons-at-radio-city-music-hall...-indescribable/</guid>
      <description>Antony and the Johnsonsperformed last Thursday 26th, at the Radio City Music HallSWANLIGHTS, a one-night-only performance commissioned by the Museum of Modern Art (MoMA), NY, the most amazing concert I have ever been to.
One would think that the fact that the performance took place in the world`s largest (and one of the most reputed) theater/music venue, or that the place was chock-full of celebrities (I had Björk right next to me in the line to pick up the reserved tickets), would add to the glamour and grandiose of the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of context in the interpretation (and enjoyment) of a work of art</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-importance-of-context-in-the-interpretation-and-enjoyment-of-a-work-of-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 01:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/the-importance-of-context-in-the-interpretation-and-enjoyment-of-a-work-of-art/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went to 3 exhibitions/events that have allowed me to see the importance of context in the interpretation (and enjoyment) of a work of art. Note that I differentiate &amp;ldquo;interpretation&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;enjoyment&amp;rdquo;, although for many of us, those two concepts go hand in hand. But this is just a short post, so the Phenomenological Aesthetics will have to wait (you can read Dewey, Hartmann, Adorno, Ortega y Gasset, Sartre, etc, etc in the meantime 😉 )</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When what the artist intended is distorted by the gallery`s limitations</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/when-what-the-artist-intended-is-distorted-by-the-gallerys-limitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 19:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/when-what-the-artist-intended-is-distorted-by-the-gallerys-limitations/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, along a MeetUp group, we visited several art galleries in Chelsea (NY): Mike Weiss Gallery, Gladstone Gallery, Luhring Augustine Gallery, Metro Pictures Gallery, The Pace Gallery, and Mary Boone Gallery.
Leaving my personal comments on the displayed works aside (as usual, the pleasure of this kind of pilgrimage is to leave your mind and senses open, and let the works and stimuli slowly sink in), one thing surprised me quite a lot: Ai Wei Wei‘s work Sunflower Seeds was supposed to be walked on (at least it did at the Tate Modern in London, for the first 10 days of the exhibit), but at Mary Boone Gallerythere is a security guard that prevents visitors from doing exactly what the artist intended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Renaissance artist Victoria Contreras</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/real-renaissance-artist-victoria-contreras/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2012 16:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/real-renaissance-artist-victoria-contreras/</guid>
      <description>My friend Victoria Contreras is a real Renaissance artist, what we would call today a hacker artist: one that explores different media, different methods, different interest, in a bold, almost childishly uninhibited playful way. While the influences are obvious, and not everything is on the same level (as is always the case in those who try it all), this is what I would call &amp;ldquo;a case of interesting people&amp;rdquo;.
See for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bella Gaia concert</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/bella-gaia-concert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 22:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/bella-gaia-concert/</guid>
      <description>Mickey Hart, Dar Williams, Bella Gaia(AWESOME), &amp;amp; The Abrams Brothers(country/folk/rock energetic brothers&amp;hellip; that violin was smoking! loved it) concert at Highline Ballroom.
Cool mix of music, dance and infographic visuals with eco message. Highly recommended (even the veggie burger was good!).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun interpreting signs</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/fun-interpreting-signs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 17:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/fun-interpreting-signs/</guid>
      <description>The world around us is full of signs. I wont go on dabble about _signifiers_, _meanings_, and the psychoanalitycal importance of the _word_. But sometimes I just cant help myself, when I see a sign begging for a creative interpretation:
Cmon, dont tell me you don`t see something like:
 If you press this button, your mouth will become a hotspot
 or
 A giant asteroid is heading towards your SpaceInvaders spacecraft, push the button to destroy the asteroid with a Dune-sque voice-blast</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art gallery inaugurations</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/art-gallery-inaugurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 23:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/12/art-gallery-inaugurations/</guid>
      <description>Tonight we went to the MaysonGallery inaugural inauguration &amp;ldquo;Launch&amp;rdquo; featuring works by Doug Henders, Scott Hewett, Michael Oatman, Jeff Quinn, Bastienne Schmidt, and Rodger Stevens. It was way too crowded to see the works, but it was fun. Particularly because we enjoyed dinner at almost next door JinJapanese restaurant.
But we wish we were at another art inauguration: IVAM`s Claudio Zirotti.
My dear friend and mentor presents &amp;ldquo;Without Time&amp;rdquo; (PDF), an excellent exhibit of his wonderful art at Valencia`s IVAM Modern Art Institute, until February 19th 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to &amp;quot;What more than sorry&amp;quot; by Ben Harper</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/listening-to-quotwhat-more-than-sorryquot-by-ben-harper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 17:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/listening-to-quotwhat-more-than-sorryquot-by-ben-harper/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCW: Art in Spanish</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/ocw-art-in-spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 20:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/ocw-art-in-spanish/</guid>
      <description>I have been interested in OCW (Open CourseWare) since the year 2000, when I tried to convince Polytechnic University of Valencia to upload all materials and lectures from the Master`s Degree (where I was lecturing) to the web for anyone to access.
Although quite slowly, OCW has come a long way. Years ago MIT and some others made a strong commitment for the OCW. But it has taken Spanish universities years to wake up and start to follow that lead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not so difficult (is it?)</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/not-so-difficult-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 09:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/10/not-so-difficult-is-it/</guid>
      <description>In this cute decorative vinyl from chispum.com, the message says: &amp;ldquo;I want a boyfriend who only wants to sleep with me (and nobody else)&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>