<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy on Jorge Cortell blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cortell.net/categories/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacy on Jorge Cortell blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 14:41:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.cortell.net/categories/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding government intrusion in my latest trip to the USA</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/avoiding-government-intrusion-in-my-latest-trip-to-the-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 14:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2017/02/avoiding-government-intrusion-in-my-latest-trip-to-the-usa/</guid>
      <description>February 18 to 23 I traveled to Orlando, Florida (USA) for the HIMSS trade show. As much as I have enjoyed the magic of Orlando parks in the past, this was a pure business trip. I am an EU citizen (Spain) living in the UK, and I took a direct flight from London to Orlando. I had recently renewed my passport and ESTA, so I should be able to enter the USA without a problem right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview for the art exhibition that I have curated and is currently being shown in Kaunas, Lithuania</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/interview-for-the-art-exhibition-that-i-have-curated-and-is-currently-being-shown-in-kaunas-lithuania/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 09:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/11/interview-for-the-art-exhibition-that-i-have-curated-and-is-currently-being-shown-in-kaunas-lithuania/</guid>
      <description>INTERVIEW with JORGE CORTELL, curator
By Airida Rekštytė – November 4, 2016
According to your profound theoretical education (sic) it will not be difficult to present us in short your intentions for organizing this event.
When did the idea of making this exhibition occur and what inspired it?
I have spent years as activist defending free software and online privacy, and opposing censorship.
During a dinner with the director of an event that focuses on those themes (the Internet Freedom Festival, also known as Circumvention Festival), I told him how it would be a nice challenge to try to convey the main messages of the Festivals themes into an art exhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The White House Chief Data Scientist assures me the White House strongly supports encryption and opposes back doors</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/the-white-house-chief-data-scientist-assures-me-the-white-house-strongly-supports-encryption-and-opposes-back-doors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 13:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2016/03/the-white-house-chief-data-scientist-assures-me-the-white-house-strongly-supports-encryption-and-opposes-back-doors/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday March 1 I had a conversation with Dr. DJ Patil, the First White House Chief Data Scientist, at the Venetian Hotel in Las Vegas.
He was interested in discussing ways in which the White House can help healthcare technology companies like mine. The first issue I raised was my concern over the FBI’s request for Apple to decrypt a suspected criminal’s iPhone.
My position in this issue is well known: weak encryption means weak security for ALL of us, so nobody can request weak security for security’s sake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Million masks march</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/million-masks-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 14:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/11/million-masks-march/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday, coming back home from a meeting, I run into the Million Masks March. While I assume I agree with most of their anti-system protests (the truth is I did not bother to read them), I think their choice of Guy Fawkes as an &amp;ldquo;icon&amp;rdquo;, even if a graphical one as proposed by the comic/movie &amp;ldquo;V for Vendetta&amp;rdquo;, is a very stupid one. Just read about what that historical figure had in mind and judge for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My talk at the Circumvention Tech Festival, March 4th</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/my-talk-at-the-circumvention-tech-festival-march-4th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 23:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/04/my-talk-at-the-circumvention-tech-festival-march-4th/</guid>
      <description>This past winter I met Sandy and James from Open ITP in New York, and Pepe from Valencia. They were organizing the Circumvention Tech Festivalto be held in Las Naves, Valencia (Spain) March 1-6.
They invited me to give a talk, which was eventually scheduled for March 4th at 3pm. I titled the talk “When privacy does not mean the same to you and me”. It was meant to generate debate, to expose other people’s points of view, rather than to be a unidirectional speech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin and block chain event in New York</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/02/bitcoin-and-block-chain-event-in-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2015/02/bitcoin-and-block-chain-event-in-new-york/</guid>
      <description>On Monday, February 9, I attended a Bitcoin – Blockchain eventwith my wife at law firm Latham &amp;amp; Watkins in New York, organized by Hedgeable.

Over 100 bitcoin enthusiasts, investors, journalists, lawyers, and entrepreneurs networking over food and beverages, with demos from:
and a round table of Bitcoin innovation experts:
Since I have already started researching the application of the block chain technology for healthcare, it was quite a useful event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Circumvention Tech Festival</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/the-circumvention-tech-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 15:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/11/the-circumvention-tech-festival/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My new OnePlus One phone is amazing</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/my-new-oneplus-one-phone-is-amazing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 22:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/10/my-new-oneplus-one-phone-is-amazing/</guid>
      <description>I have just bought a OnePlusOne phone, and have been using it for a couple of days. Let me tell you: it`s AMAZING.
If you have never heard of the company, dont worry, youre not alone. But you should definitely check it out, because their phones are incredibly high quality, high specs, and low price (mine was $349). No catch:
 Qualcomm© Snapdragon™ 801 processor with 2.5GHz Quad-core CPUs Adreno 330 GPU, 578MHz 64 GB eMMC 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reset the net</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2014/06/reset-the-net/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The key to the use of cloud in healthcare</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/the-key-to-the-use-of-cloud-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 12:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/09/the-key-to-the-use-of-cloud-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>In a single word: security.
By now there is no doubt about the advantages of the cloud: easy collaboration, scalability, ubiquity, sync, cost savings (21% on average, according to AFCOM 2011, 40% according to our own customers), rapid deployment, etc.
There is also no doubt about the need for a move to the cloud in healthcare: according to Enterprise Strategy Group, by 2015 an average of 665TB of data will be generated per hospital per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police state: TXT with police alert in TX</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/police-state-txt-with-police-alert-in-tx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 14:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/police-state-txt-with-police-alert-in-tx/</guid>
      <description>While in Fort Worth, TX, I received the following TXT:
 They who can give up essential liberty to obtain a little temporary safety, deserve neither liberty nor safety.
 Benjamin Franklin, 1775</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am requested to take a link down and... Streisand effect!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 01:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2013/07/i-am-requested-to-take-a-link-down-and...-streisand-effect/</guid>
      <description>Today I received this email (it was in Spanish, I have translated it into English because that is the main language of this blog, and in order to give this issue the international coverage that it deserves – sorry for any translation mistake since I am not a lawyer and he writes like an old-fashioned one trying to sound intimidating; here is the original):
 Mr. Cortell:
Currently I am suing Greg Prévôt in the Courts of Barcelona, author of a defamatory site which infringes upon my honor, whose link appears in which you administer, at the following address:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The danger of graphs and cold data</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-danger-of-graphs-and-cold-data/</guid>
      <description>After posting graphs and cold data (quite ilustrative, I believe), and the discussion it has generated (people, why don`t you use the &amp;ldquo;comment&amp;rdquo; instead all the other unstructured methods you are using?), please let me write a caveat about graphs and cold data.
In my high-tech gym, you have the option to have a lot of data collected, for your own, private and personal use. It seems like a great idea at first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with face.com face recognition technology</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/playing-with-face.com-face-recognition-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 17:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/playing-with-face.com-face-recognition-technology/</guid>
      <description>While I am preparing a loooooong post about technology and privacy (with a provocative twist, for a change 😈 ), I have decided to play with face.com‘s face recognition technology.
What do you think? On target (hint: no, not on target, I am not THAT old, and definitely I AM a male)? Scary (hint: only if we are unaware of these technologies and their uses)?&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The price of standing up for your rights: Opt-Out at Atlanta`s airport scanner</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-price-of-standing-up-for-your-rights-opt-out-at-atlantas-airport-scanner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 14:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/04/the-price-of-standing-up-for-your-rights-opt-out-at-atlantas-airport-scanner/</guid>
      <description>Atlanta`s Hartsfield airport has been having one of those uselessscanners that show passengers naked for a while now. But the last time I was there, they were being tested, and most passengers did not go through them. Today, though, as I approached the security line, I saw that next to every metal detector, there was one of those scanners. &amp;ldquo;Wow, this is getting worse&amp;rdquo;, I thought, while seeing how almost everybody was going through the scanners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better privacy through your browser</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/better-privacy-through-your-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 17:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/03/better-privacy-through-your-browser/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to improve your online privacy? Go ahead, install HTTPSand Collusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protest against SOPA on your site: easy code</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/protest-against-sopa-on-your-site-easy-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 09:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2012/01/protest-against-sopa-on-your-site-easy-code/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Sara, there is a very easy way to add code to your site to protest against SOPA:
Drop the following code in between your two tags on your site, your users will be redirected to the blackout page that describes what you are doing and why.
`Then, when the protest is over, simply remove the added code. The protest is starting at 12am on 1/18, and lasts 24 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a movement!</title>
      <link>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-a-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2011 10:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cortell.net/2011/11/what-a-movement/</guid>
      <description>First things first: thanks to whomever thought I would be interested in joining MCAthrough RiseUp, BUT&amp;hellip;
 Don`t subscribe me to a list without my consent Don`t do so without at least letting me know who you are Don`t assume I might be interested in something because it sounds related to my interest Don`t align me with &amp;ldquo;scientific socialism&amp;rdquo; when I am a declared anarchist Don`t make me waste my time on a list where the first 20 or so messages are split between arguing troskist, marxist, rose of lenburguist, bujarinist, bakuninist, leninist, hotsiminist, guevarist, maoist, castrist&amp;hellip; and people who want to be taken off the list  So, thanks (and I show it by talking about your project here), but show a little respect for other people`s rights, please.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>